<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>710988203's articles on Inoreader</title>
<link>https://www.inoreader.com/stream/user/1005148177/tag/all-articles/view/html</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<atom:link href="https://www.inoreader.com/stream/user/1005148177/tag/all-articles" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
<generator>Inoreader (https://www.inoreader.com)</generator>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:49:14 +0000</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:49:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<language>en-US</language>
<item>
<title>Creating King's anointing screen was an honour, says designer</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-shropshire-65518256?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=KARANGA</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/E4D6/production/_129628585_2cb41f9ddc86469b7a564e25476baa11933e456a.jpg" alt="_129628585_2cb41f9ddc86469b7a564e25476ba"></p>Iconographer Aidan Hart designed the screen that shielded King Charles III during the Coronation.]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:48:38 +0000</pubDate>
<category>World News</category>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<source url="https://www.bbc.com">BBC News</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75163320f2</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Yellen: ‘No good options’ if Congress fails to act on debt</title>
<link>https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/politics-news/yellen-no-good-options-congress-fails-act-debt-rcna83259</link>
<description><![CDATA[Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen said Sunday that there are “no good options” for the U.S. to avoid an economic “calamity” if Congress fails to raise the nation’s borrowing limit.]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:48:38 +0000</pubDate>
<enclosure length="1337" type="image/jpeg" url="https://media-cldnry.s-nbcnews.com/image/upload/rockcms/2023-05/230507-janet-yellen-jm-1235-c5b064.jpg"></enclosure>
<category>World News</category>
<dc:creator>The Associated Press</dc:creator>
<source url="http://www.nbcnews.com/">NBC News Top Stories</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e7516331c25</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>7 dead after car runs into pedestrians, alleged driver arrested</title>
<link>https://abcnews.go.com/US/7-dead-after-car-runs-pedestrians-brownsville-texas/story?id=99152817</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s.abcnews.com/images/US/caution-tape-rf-gty-mz-43-230416_1681678065410_hpMain_4x3t_384.jpg" alt="caution-tape-rf-gty-mz-43-230416_1681678"></p>Seven people are dead in Brownsville, Texas, after a car ran into pedestrians Sunday morning.]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
<category>World News</category>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<source url="http://abcnews.go.com/">ABC News: Top Stories</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e751633374a</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Lack of Alien Signals Actually Tells Us a Lot</title>
<link>https://www.universetoday.com/161238/a-lack-of-alien-signals-actually-tells-us-a-lot/</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>In a  <a href="https://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.3847/1538-3881/acc327">recent study</a> published in <em>The Astronomical Journal</em>, a researcher from the École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne (EPFL) discusses the potential reasons why we haven’t received technoemission, also called technosignatures, from an extraterrestrial intelligence during the 60 years that SETI has been searching, along with recommending additional methods as to how we can continue to search for such emissions.</p> 
 
 
 
<span></span> 
 
 
 
<p>Dr. Claudio Grimaldi, who is a guest scientist at the Laboratory of Statistical Biophysics at EPFL and sole author of the study, suggests that Earth has not received a technoemission simply because Earth could be in what he refers to as a “void space”, meaning the area of space that Earth resides in has been devoid of technoemissions.</p> 
 
 
<div> 
<img width="1024" height="683" src="https://www.universetoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/VLA_Moonset_NIK_0991_1024.jpg" alt="">Image of radio telescopes at the <a href="https://public.nrao.edu/telescopes/vla/">Karl G. Jansky Very Large Array</a> near Socorro, New Mexico, scanning the heavens for extraterrestrial technoemissions. (Credit: Jeff Hellermann/National Radio Astronomy Observatory/Associated Universities, Inc./National Science Foundation)</div> 
 
 
<p>“If it is true that we’ve been in a void region for sixty years, our model suggests that there are less than one to five electromagnetic emissions per century anywhere in our galaxy. This would make them about as rare as supernovas in the Milky Way,” <a href="https://actu.epfl.ch/news/silence-reveals-insights-in-search-for-extraterres/">said Dr. Grimaldi</a>.</p> 
 
 
 
<p>For the study, Dr. Grimaldi developed a model that assumed the existence of technological “emitters” of extraterrestrial origin that are constantly broadcasting emissions and are equally dispersed throughout our Milky Way Galaxy. In the end, Dr. Grimaldi came up with three viewpoints of optimism regarding how long until Earth will detect a technoemission, which he refers to as a “crossing event”: an optimistic timeframe of 60 years from now, a moderately optimistic timeframe of 170 years from now, and a marginally optimistic timeframe of 1800 years from now.</p> 
 
 
<div> 
<img width="1024" height="768" src="https://www.universetoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/ata1_h.jpg" alt="">Image of the <a href="https://www.seti.org/ata">Allen Telescope Array</a> in Hat Creek, CA, scanning the skies for signals from extraterrestrial civilizations. (Credit: Seth Shostak/SETI Institute)</div> 
 
 
<p>The study concludes by emphasizing the ideas presented could be either true or false but suggested that hunting for technoemissions should go beyond SETI searches while focusing on more “commensal investigations, i.e., searching for technosignals from data collected by telescopes performing other observational activities, rather than investing telescope time in active SETI searches.”</p> 
 
 
 
<p>One such option is the privately funded <a href="https://breakthroughinitiatives.org/initiative/1">Breakthrough Listen project</a> that is conducting the most extensive search for technoemissions to date, which was started in 2015 and is slated to run until 2025. Using radio telescopes that whose sensitivity is 50 times greater than current telescopes committed to searching for extraterrestrial intelligence, Breakthrough Listen is surveying 1,000,000 of the Earth’s closest stars, along with scanning the center of the Milky Way and what’s known as the galactic plane. The search even scans for emissions from 100 of the Milky Way’s closest galaxies. This study also comes as exoplanets are being discovered almost daily and <a href="https://exoplanets.nasa.gov/">over 5,300 have been confirmed</a> as of this writing.</p> 
 
 
 
<div> 
<iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="525" height="296" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9Nllt9nRU1w?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;fs=1&amp;hl=en-US&amp;autohide=2&amp;wmode=transparent" style="border:0;"></iframe> 
</div>Learn more about how Breakthrough Listen tried to <a href="https://www.universetoday.com/159219/astronomers-scanned-12-planets-for-alien-signals-while-they-were-in-front-of-their-stars/">detect technosignatures from 12 exoplanets</a> in 2022.  
 
 
 
<p>Dr. Grimaldi emphasizes that “the truth is, we don’t know where to search, at which frequencies and wavelengths. We are currently looking at other phenomena using our telescopes, so the best strategy might be to adopt the SETI community’s past approach of using data from other astrophysical studies – detecting radio emissions from other stars or galaxies – to see if they contain any techno-signals and make that the standard practice.”</p> 
 
 
 
<p>Two of the most profound ideas pertaining to why we haven’t detected a technoemission from an extraterrestrial intelligence are the <a href="https://www.seti.org/fermi-paradox-0">Fermi Paradox</a> and <a href="https://www.universetoday.com/39966/drake-equation-1/">Drake Equation</a>, and much like this recent study, both ideas present varying degrees of optimism about whether we’ll ever detect such a technoemission.</p> 
 
 
 
<p>While the Drake Equation presents a plethora of variables to attempt to calculate the number of extraterrestrial technological civilizations in the Milky Way Galaxy, the Fermi Paradox presents a less optimistic argument as it is built on the question posed by Dr. Enrico Fermi, “where is everybody?”, while presenting hypothetical explanations for the reasons why we haven’t heard from such a civilization. One such explanation argues that civilizations inevitably destroy themselves in a short time after achieving technological milestones, including spaceflight or radio technology, which was also <a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-many-aliens-are-in-the-milky-way-astronomers-turn-to-statistics-for-answers/">echoed by Dr. Carl Sagan</a>.</p> 
 
 
 
<div> 
<iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="525" height="296" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QgMGvgivCy8?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;fs=1&amp;hl=en-US&amp;autohide=2&amp;wmode=transparent" style="border:0;"></iframe> 
</div> 
 
 
 
<p>Regarding the positive or negative interpretations of his conclusions, Dr. Grimaldi laughed saying, “This is something we need to think about. We may have been unlucky in that we discovered how to use radio telescopes just as we were crossing a portion of space in which electromagnetic signals from other civilizations were absent. To me, this hypothesis seems less extreme than assuming that we are constantly bombarded by signals from all sides but are, for some reason, unable to detect them.”</p> 
 
 
 
<p>Why haven’t we detected a signal from an extraterrestrial technological civilization and when will we? Are we truly alone in the universe, or is it teeming with civilizations like our own? Only time will tell, and this is why we science!</p> 
 
 
 
<p><em>As always, keep doing science &amp; keep looking up!</em></p> 
<p>The post <a href="https://www.universetoday.com/161238/a-lack-of-alien-signals-actually-tells-us-a-lot/">A Lack of Alien Signals Actually Tells Us a Lot</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.universetoday.com">Universe Today</a>.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
<enclosure length="1337" type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.universetoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/1108x622-1024x576.jpg"></enclosure>
<category>Science &amp; Space</category>
<dc:creator>Laurence Tognetti</dc:creator>
<source url="http://www.universetoday.com/">Universe Today</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e751633872c</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Polish jet loses control after 'aggressive' Russian fighter plane crosses five metres in front</title>
<link>https://news.yahoo.com/polish-jet-loses-control-aggressive-160739695.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/nY7POKYnnfFjA59eFusfBg--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD03NTA7Y2Y9d2VicA--/https://media.zenfs.com/en/the_telegraph_258/50fa37cf92a21eab85837ca98ef206c4" alt="50fa37cf92a21eab85837ca98ef206c4"></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:41:13 +0000</pubDate>
<category>World News</category>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<source url="http://news.yahoo.com/topstories/">Yahoo News - Top Stories</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e751633d9bb</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>‘He used people’: Jeffrey Epstein scandal rolls on as new names emerge</title>
<link>https://news.yahoo.com/used-people-jeffrey-epstein-scandal-070014465.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/f4z83L17X86XdvLFXmyTTA--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD03MjA7Y2Y9d2VicA--/https://media.zenfs.com/en/the_guardian_765/27e78757e46a3ec5798965411e09ba7e" alt="27e78757e46a3ec5798965411e09ba7e"></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:41:13 +0000</pubDate>
<category>World News</category>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<source url="http://news.yahoo.com/topstories/">Yahoo News - Top Stories</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e751633d9ab</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>ChatGPT is Powered by $15-an-Hour Contractors</title>
<link>https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/05/07/0346253/chatgpt-is-powered-by-15-an-hour-contractors?utm_source=rss1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/topics/ai_64.png" alt="ai_64.png"></p>An anonymous reader shared this report from NBC News:  
  
Alexej Savreux, a 34-year-old in Kansas City, says he's done all kinds of work over the years. He's made fast-food sandwiches. He's been a custodian and a junk-hauler. And he's done technical sound work for live theater.   
  
These days, though, his work is less hands-on: He's an artificial intelligence trainer.   
  
Savreux is part of a hidden army of contract workers who have been doing the behind-the-scenes labor of teaching AI systems how to analyze data so they can generate the kinds of text and images that have wowed the people using newly popular products like ChatGPT. To improve the accuracy of AI, he has labeled photos and made predictions about what text the apps should generate next.   
  
The pay: $15 an hour and up, with no benefits... He credits the AI gig work — along with a previous job at the sandwich chain Jimmy John's — with helping to pull him out of homelessness.   
  
"Their feedback fills an urgent and endless need for the company and its AI competitors: providing streams of sentences, labels and other information that serve as training data," the article explains:  
"A lot of the discourse around AI is very congratulatory," said Sonam Jindal, the program lead for AI, labor and the economy at the Partnership on AI, a nonprofit based in San Francisco that promotes research and education around artificial intelligence. "But we're missing a big part of the story: that this is still hugely reliant on a large human workforce," she said...   
  
A spike in demand has arrived, and some AI contract workers are asking for more. In Nairobi, Kenya, more than 150 people who've worked on AI for Facebook, TikTok and ChatGPT voted Monday to form a union, citing low pay and the mental toll of the work, Time magazine reported... Time magazine reported in January that OpenAI relied on low-wage Kenyan laborers to label text that included hate speech or sexually abusive language so that its apps could do better at recognizing toxic content on their own. OpenAI has hired about 1,000 remote contractors in places such as Eastern Europe and Latin America to label data or train company software on computer engineering tasks, the online news outlet Semafor reported in January...   
  
A spokesperson for OpenAI said no one was available to answer questions about its use of AI contractors.<p></p><div>  
<a href="http://twitter.com/home?status=ChatGPT+is+Powered+by+%2415-an-Hour+Contractors%3A+https%3A%2F%2Fit.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F05%2F07%2F0346253%2F%3Futm_source%3Dtwitter%26utm_medium%3Dtwitter"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/twitter_icon_large.png" alt="twitter_icon_large.png"></a>  
<a href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fit.slashdot.org%2Fstory%2F23%2F05%2F07%2F0346253%2Fchatgpt-is-powered-by-15-an-hour-contractors%3Futm_source%3Dslashdot%26utm_medium%3Dfacebook"><img src="https://a.fsdn.com/sd/facebook_icon_large.png" alt="facebook_icon_large.png"></a>  
  
  
  
</div><p><a href="https://it.slashdot.org/story/23/05/07/0346253/chatgpt-is-powered-by-15-an-hour-contractors?utm_source=rss1.0moreanon&amp;utm_medium=feed">Read more of this story</a> at Slashdot.</p><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" src="https://slashdot.org/slashdot-it.pl?op=discuss&amp;id=22875177&amp;smallembed=1" style="height:300px;width:100%;border:none;"></iframe>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Tech News</category>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<source url="http://slashdot.org/">Slashdot</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75163c1072</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Celtic win title: Scottish Premiership success celebrated by players and fans in style</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/av/football/65520968?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=KARANGA</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/cpsprodpb/11245/production/_129631207_p0flzvdp.jpg" alt="_129631207_p0flzvdp.jpg"></p>Celtic's players and supporters savour clinching another Scottish Premiership title]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
<category>World News</category>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<source url="https://www.bbc.com">BBC News</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75163c164d</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Man forced to drive car with suspicious object to police station in Northern Ireland</title>
<link>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2023/may/07/man-forced-to-drive-car-with-suspicious-object-to-police-station-in-northern-ireland</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/14accfc814433c9dc015bd6543071e9bdf8f0645/0_3_3166_1900/master/3166.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=630&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;overlay-align=bottom%2Cleft&amp;overlay-width=100p&amp;overlay-base64=L2ltZy9zdGF0aWMvb3ZlcmxheXMvdGctZGVmYXVsdC5wbmc&amp;enable=upscale&amp;s=59c3a2a9895cc816d4e1abc3b2c5c4c1" alt="3166.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=630&amp;quality=8"></p><p>Masked gang hijacked driver at gunpoint and made him drive with the device to Omagh police station</p><p>A man was hijacked at gunpoint by a masked gang and then forced to drive his car with a suspicious object on board to a police station in Northern Ireland.</p><p>The incident caused a major security alert in Omagh, County Tyrone, which led to a number of people being evacuated from their homes and cordons erected.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2023/may/07/man-forced-to-drive-car-with-suspicious-object-to-police-station-in-northern-ireland">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
<category>World News</category>
<dc:creator>PA Media</dc:creator>
<source url="http://www.theguardian.com/world">World news | The Guardian</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75163c1769</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>DR Congo floods death toll surpasses 200</title>
<link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2023/5/7/dr-congo-floods-death-toll-surpasses-200</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.aljazeera.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/11455590-1683474409.jpg?resize=1200%2C675" alt="11455590-1683474409.jpg?resize=1200%2C67"></p>Authorities say 287 killed and 167 others missing after heavy rains caused floods in South Kivu province.]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
<category>World News</category>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<source url="http://www.aljazeera.com/default.html">AL JAZEERA ENGLISH (AJE)</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75163d03c4</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Kate comforts crying girl as royal couple meet Windsor crowds</title>
<link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-65518730?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=KARANGA</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/345B/production/_129630431_p0flzt6j.jpg" alt="_129630431_p0flzt6j.jpg"></p>The Princess of Wales comforted a crying girl as she met crowds celebrating the Coronation at Windsor.]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:27:40 +0000</pubDate>
<category>World News</category>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<source url="https://www.bbc.com">BBC News</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75163d2157</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>'I'm going to be a first responder': Nurse shocked as tourists try to touch bison</title>
<link>https://news.yahoo.com/im-going-first-responder-nurse-153025362.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/qxI9qXcrcL2buWbtqFPcVA--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD02NzU7Y2Y9d2VicA--/https://s.yimg.com/hd/cp-video-transcode/production/7bb55f32-f2f6-3c78-ad6e-b0a9434665aa/2023-05-07/15-32-43/4cf5a9c4-8b00-5c54-b771-f79aeb905945/stream_1920x1080x0_v2_3_0.jpg" alt="stream_1920x1080x0_v2_3_0.jpg"></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
<category>World News</category>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<source url="http://news.yahoo.com/topstories/">Yahoo News - Top Stories</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75163dd9f9</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What happens when we run out of data for AI models</title>
<link>https://venturebeat.com/ai/what-happens-when-we-run-out-of-data-for-ai-models/</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img width="578" height="289" src="https://venturebeat.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/annevb_person_sitting_in_the_dark_at_an_empty_desk_by_a_blank_c_7f68bb15-3240-40cf-b85e-846223a3a780.png?fit=578%2C289&amp;strip=all" alt="Person sitting at a nearly empty desk in front of a blank computer screen in a nearly dark room"><hr>Traditional scaling approaches to building machine learning models will fail as we run out of data for them. Several techniques may help.<a href="https://venturebeat.com/ai/what-happens-when-we-run-out-of-data-for-ai-models/">Read More</a>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Tech News</category>
<dc:creator>Ivan Smetannikov, Serokell</dc:creator>
<source url="http://venturebeat.com/">VentureBeat</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75163dfe91</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Warren Buffett on Finding Success at Work, and What Matters in Hiring</title>
<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/warren-buffett-on-finding-success-at-work-and-what-matters-in-hiring-43da47c3</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://images.wsj.net/im-777428/social" alt="social"></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:17:45 +0000</pubDate>
<category>World News</category>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<source url="http://online.wsj.com/page/2_0006.html">WSJ: World News</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75163e1738</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Anti-Monarchy Group Slams Coronation Arrests And Vows To Continue Protesting</title>
<link>https://www.huffpost.com/entry/anti-monarchy-group-slams-coronation-arrests_n_6457c820e4b046160312dbd1</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/645791992600006a006d76f6.jpg?cache=uJlj2YwquJ&amp;ops=1200_630" alt="645791992600006a006d76f6.jpg?cache=uJlj2"></p>"We will continue to protest with one simple message: Charles is not our king, it is time to abolish the monarchy."]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
<enclosure length="1337" type="image/jpeg" url="https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/645791992600006a006d76f6.jpg?cache=ujlj2ywquj&amp;amp;ops=224_126"></enclosure>
<category>World News</category>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<source url="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/">Huffington Post</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75163e6d21</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Artemis 2 will use lasers to beam high-definition video from the moon (video)</title>
<link>https://www.space.com/nasa-artemis-2-laser-communications-video</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qNbJR3AoagcsrrcjCcDmin-1200-80.jpg" alt="qNbJR3AoagcsrrcjCcDmin-1200-80.jpg"></p>Watch NASA explain how the Orion Artemis 2 Optical Communications System (O2O) will enable the first high-speed transmission of images and video from the moon.]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
<enclosure length="1337" type="image/jpeg" url="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/qNbJR3AoagcsrrcjCcDmin.jpg"></enclosure>
<category>Science &amp; Space</category>
<dc:creator>email@joshdinner.com (Josh Dinner)</dc:creator>
<source url="http://www.space.com/">SPACE.com</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75163e99ae</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Nick Gilbert, son of Cavaliers owner, dies at 26</title>
<link>https://news.yahoo.com/nick-gilbert-son-cavaliers-owner-154701249.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/MJTjszSoaWYW4zIKfb1JYA--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04Mzk7Y2Y9d2VicA--/https://media.zenfs.com/en/ap.org/aa7177299f7b64eef5e648af50783a7e" alt="aa7177299f7b64eef5e648af50783a7e"></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:10:37 +0000</pubDate>
<category>World News</category>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<source url="http://news.yahoo.com/topstories/">Yahoo News - Top Stories</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75163ecc1a</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>I Never Became an Entrepreneur. Now I Wonder Why.</title>
<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/entrepreneur-life-lessons-58e6f8cc</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://images.wsj.net/im-776299/social" alt="social"></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:08:13 +0000</pubDate>
<category>World News</category>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<source url="http://online.wsj.com/page/2_0006.html">WSJ: World News</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75163f0668</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ford, Tesla CEOs Exchange Jabs and Praise Amid Heated EV Rivalry</title>
<link>https://www.wsj.com/articles/ford-tesla-ceos-exchange-jabs-and-praise-amid-heated-ev-rivalry-6526555d</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://images.wsj.net/im-775266/social" alt="social"></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:08:13 +0000</pubDate>
<category>World News</category>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<source url="http://online.wsj.com/page/2_0006.html">WSJ: World News</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75163f063c</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Labour ‘confident but not complacent’ about a general election win as Brexit backers return to the party</title>
<link>https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/labour-general-election-starmer-sunak-brexit-b2334322.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Shadow health secretary Wes Streeting says Labour is ‘not even entertaining’ the prospect of a coalition with the Liberal Democrats </p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:06:47 +0000</pubDate>
<enclosure length="1337" type="image/png" url="https://static.independent.co.uk/2023/05/05/10/starmer medway.png?width=1200&amp;amp;auto=webp"></enclosure>
<category>World News</category>
<dc:creator>Archie Mitchell</dc:creator>
<source url="http://www.independent.co.uk/news/?service=Rss">Independent</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75163f29c3</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>