<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>Fitness via 710988203 on Inoreader</title>
<link>https://www.inoreader.com/stream/user/1005148177/tag/Fitness/view/html</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<atom:link href="https://www.inoreader.com/stream/user/1005148177/tag/Fitness" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
<generator>Inoreader (https://www.inoreader.com)</generator>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 17:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 17:08:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<language>en-US</language>
<item>
<title>One Bottle of This ‘Drugstore Diamond’ Serum Sells Every 30 Seconds—It Features a Dermatologist-Beloved Plumping Ingredient</title>
<link>https://www.wellandgood.com/loreal-paris-revitalift-hyaluronic-acid/</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Most of the time, you’re in it for the long haul when it comes to skin care. Incorporating different ingredients like <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/skin-benefits-vitamin-c/">vitamin C</a> or <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/is-salicylic-acid-bad-for-skin/">salicylic acid</a> into your routine allows you to see results over time. But hydrating ingredients give you instant results, with hero ingredients like <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/how-to-use-hyaluronic-acid/">hyaluronic acid</a> (HA) offering plump skin and softened fine lines right before your eyes. That’s because the natural decrease in skin moisture that happens over time can exacerbate signs of aging like fine lines and crepeiness. One of the best hyaluronic acids out there is the Reviatilft Derm Intensives 2.5% Pure Hyaluronic Acid from L’Oréal Paris. The drugstore diamond is so good that one bottle sells every 30 seconds.</p> 
<div> 
  <div> 
     
     
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Hyaluronic-LOreal-Paris-Revitalift-Intensives/dp/B07GVCVYB9"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/LOre%CC%81al-Paris-Revitalift-Derm-Intensives-2.5-Pure-Hyaluronic-Acid.jpg" alt="L’Oréal Paris Revitalift Hyaluronic Acid"> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Hyaluronic-LOreal-Paris-Revitalift-Intensives/dp/B07GVCVYB9"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Hyaluronic-LOreal-Paris-Revitalift-Intensives/dp/B07GVCVYB9">L’Oréal Paris, Revitalift Derm Intensives 2.5% Pure Hyaluronic Acid  — $12.00</a></div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Hyaluronic-LOreal-Paris-Revitalift-Intensives/dp/B07GVCVYB9"> 
                          </a> 
                       
           
                               
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Hyaluronic-LOreal-Paris-Revitalift-Intensives/dp/B07GVCVYB9"> 
            Shop Now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
            </div> 
</div> 
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Hyaluronic-LOreal-Paris-Revitalift-Intensives/dp/B07GVCVYB9">L’Oréal Paris, Revitalift Derm Intensives 2.5% Pure Hyaluronic Acid</a> ($24) is made with <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/hyaluronic-acid-molecular-weights/">two different weights of HA</a>, attacking hydration and plumping from two angles. The 0.5-percent, high-molecular-weight HA works on the skin’s surface to instantly hydrate it and lock in moisture for a dewy look. The one-percent, low-molecular-weight HA seeps deeper into the skin to smooth skin texture and plump from the inside.</p> 
<p>“Hyaluronic acid is found naturally at a high molecular weight in our tissue, but it can be broken down and found as a low molecular weight as well,” says <a href="https://www.schweigerderm.com/providers/rachel-nazarian-m-d/">Rachel Nazarian, MD,</a> a board-certified dermatologist in New York City. “The different weights may signal different cellular responses in the skin, triggering different pathways of healing and repair mechanisms, but they also have varying levels of penetration into the skin. The thought is that perhaps using a combination of molecular weights will trigger different complementary pathways and lead to even better results than just high-molecular-weight hyaluronic acid alone.”</p> 
<p>L’Oréal Revitalift Hyaluronic Acid also has HEPES (aka  4-(2-hydroxyethyl)-1-piperazineethanesulfonic acid). It was initially used in cell biology to help stabilize pH, but was adopted into skin care by L’Oréal for its ability to promote enzyme activity that breaks down proteins. This results in smoother, softer, and more radiant skin.</p> 
<p>If you have a multi-step routine, apply this serum on damp skin before your others, as the HA will act like a vacuum, <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/how-to-use-hyaluronic-acid-serum/">pulling the ingredients you layer on top deeper into the skin</a>. Plus, “it’s important to apply HA before your other serums because it helps to seal in the moisturizer you’ll be putting on top,” adds board-certified dermatologist <a href="https://www.sperlingdermatology.com/">Shari Sperling, DO</a>.</p> 
<p>It also features <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/moisturizers-with-glycerin/">glycerin</a>, an underrated hydrating ingredient that gives skin care products that slippery, buttery feeling. “When I put a product on, I can tell instantly when glycerin is high up on the ingredient list,” says <a href="https://www.drwoolerylloyd.com/">Heather Woolery-Lloyd, MD</a>. “It just feels like butter.”</p> 
<p>So if you happen to want plump, hydrated, and buttery soft skin, you’ll love the L’Oréal Revitalift Hyaluronic Acid. It’s normally $24, but at the time of publishing, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Hyaluronic-LOreal-Paris-Revitalift-Intensives/dp/B07GVCVYB9/ref=sr_1_4_mod_primary_new?th=1">if you buy from Amazon</a>, you’ll get it for half off.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 15:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Fitness</category>
<dc:creator>Kara Jillian Brown</dc:creator>
<source url="http://wellandgood.com/">Well+Good</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75163fdba3</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dealing With Spring Allergies? An Allergist Say These Are the Foods You Should Add—and Avoid—in Your Diet</title>
<link>https://www.wellandgood.com/foods-seasonal-allergies/</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/GettyImages-foods-for-seasonal-allergies.jpg" alt="GettyImages-foods-for-seasonal-allergies"></p><p>If you have seasonal allergies, you might have noticed your symptoms are starting sooner in the year, lasting longer, or worsening. Or maybe you’re an adult who’s never had allergies, but are experiencing the watery eyes, sneezing, fatigue, and other miseries that go with pollen season for the first time.</p>  
<p>Allergies are worsening thanks in large part to human-caused climate change <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/ways-to-prepare-for-allergy-season/">lengthening pollen season</a> and increasing the amount of pollen in the air. Recent <a href="https://www.nifa.usda.gov/about-nifa/impacts/yes-allergy-seasons-are-getting-worse-blame-climate-change">research</a> shows that compared to 1990, pollen has increased 21 percent, and that pollen season starts 20 days earlier and lasts 10 days longer.</p>  
<p>If you’re on a quest to quell your allergy symptoms or cut back on medications that can have side effects like drowsiness, you might want to consider turning to nature’s medicine cabinet. Certain foods and nutrients have been shown to help allergy symptoms, while others have been shown to make them worse, according to <a href="http://www.doctoratoosa.com">Atoosa Kourosh, MD,</a> a board-certified pediatrician and allergy and immunology specialist in Southlake, Texas.</p>  
<h2><strong>Six natural remedies that may help quell your allergies </strong></h2>  
<p>Dr. Kourosh says while no one thing is right for everyone. Metabolic and genetic testing are the best ways to find out what works best for you. Yet these six nutrients have been found to generally be helpful.</p>  
<p>Important note: Before starting any supplement or making dietary changes, Kourosh says it’s essential to consult with your doctor. Just like prescription meds, supplements can cause side effects and interact with other medications. “I tell everyone to be mindful of supplement introduction,” says Dr. Kourosh. “Start with one at a time, then every few days add a new one, and gauge your response, both positive and negative.”</p>  
<h3><strong>Quercetin </strong></h3>  
<p>This polyphenol found in onions, broccoli, apples, berries, grapes, and tea has been shown in <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6273625/">research</a> to decrease inflammation and inhibit the production and release of histamine, the chemical the body releases in response to allergens. Quercetin is often taken in supplement form when used for allergy symptoms. Kourosh says that certain people may not be able to process quercetin well, so to start slowly when taking it, and be aware of side effects such as agitation.</p>  
<h3><strong>Bromelain </strong></h3>  
<p><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3870104/">Research</a> has found that this group of enzymes from the fruit and stem of pineapple has antiallergic and anti-inflammatory properties. It’s also available in supplement form, sometimes in combination with quercetin. Bromelain should be avoided if you’re allergic to pineapple or latex (due to cross-sensitivity). It also has a blood-thinning effect and should not be taken without consulting with a doctor, especially if you’re on blood thinners, says Dr. Kourosh.</p>  
<h3><strong>Vitamin C </strong></h3>  
<p>Some studies have shown this vitamin found in many fruits and vegetables has an antiviral and anti-inflammatory effect, says Dr. Kourosh. A daily dose of 500 milligrams per day is safe for most adults. “However, too much of a good thing is possible, and it can cause diarrhea and GI upset” at higher doses, she adds.</p>  
<h3><strong>Ginger and garlic</strong></h3>  
<p>These two roots are highly anti-inflammatory and are likely more beneficial if you eat them fresh (as long as you don’t have a sensitivity) as opposed to taking them as supplements, says Dr. Kourosh.</p>  
<h3><strong>Vitamin D3 </strong></h3>  
<p>Allergies and the immune system are all affected by vitamin D levels, and most of us in the Northern Hemisphere have inadequate levels due to the lack of sunlight, says Dr. Kourosh. “There is good data that vitamin D plays a critical role in immune system development, and that it can be helpful for allergies and asthma,” she adds. It’s best to get vitamin D levels tested to determine how much to supplement, and to take vitamin D3, the most effective form, with vitamin K2 for optimal absorption.</p>  
<h2><strong>Foods you might want to pass on</strong></h2>  
<p>If you have seasonal allergies, certain foods can cause what’s known as <a href="https://www.rush.edu/news/pollen-food-allergy-syndrome">“pollen food allergy syndrome,”</a> or PFAS. Also referred to as oral allergy syndrome, PFAS occurs because pollen and certain fruits, vegetables, and tree nuts are so similar they are cross-reactive, meaning they can confuse the body into thinking the food is an allergen.</p>  
<p>“It’s a case of mistaken identity,” says Dr. Kourosh. “The proteins in the cell walls of pollen are so similar biochemically to those in the cell walls of certain foods that the body mistakes the food for an allergen. For those with the allergy, eating the food is like eating a mouthful of pollen.”</p>  
<p>Cross-reactive foods can set off a histamine response that makes the mouth and throat itchy and irritated, and possibly even causes stomach upset or vomiting, says Dr. Kourosh. According to the <a href="https://acaai.org/">American College of Allergy, Asthma, and Immunology</a>, common cross reactions include:</p>  
<p><strong>Birch pollen:</strong> apple, almond, carrot, celery, cherry, hazelnut, kiwi, peach, pear, and plum</p>  
<p><strong>Grass pollen:</strong> celery, melons, oranges, peaches, and tomato</p>  
<p><strong>Ragweed pollen:</strong> banana, cucumber, melons, sunflower seeds, and zucchini</p>  
<p>The good news is not everyone with pollen allergies experiences PFAS, and those who do may find they can eat the food cooked, which breaks down proteins that cause the allergic response.</p>  
<p>Finally, if seasonal allergies are just plain making you miserable no matter what you’ve tried at home, it’s probably time to see an allergist. Longer and more severe allergy seasons aren’t going anywhere, and having every tool to combat them at your disposal can help ensure the buds and blooms of spring are something you can look forward to instead of dread.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 14:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Fitness</category>
<dc:creator>Cathy Nelson</dc:creator>
<source url="http://wellandgood.com/">Well+Good</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e751620b457</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5 Most Quiet Blenders That Won’t Wake Everyone Else Up When You Make Early Morning Smoothies</title>
<link>https://www.wellandgood.com/quiet-blenders/</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/gut-friendly-smoothie-recipes/">Smoothies</a> are a breakfast favorite for many reasons. For one, they’re a quick and dirty way to provide the body with nutrients without much effort, hence why they’re so popular amongst those with ultra-busy schedules. They’re also a great way to mask the taste of nutritious yet gross-tasting ingredients like <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/sea-moss-smoothie-recipes/">sea moss</a> and <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/benefits-of-spirulina-buying-tips/">spirulina,</a> and can help you sneak more nutrients into your diet with the help of things like supplements and protein powder.</p> 
<p>Here’s the thing about smoothies, though: They require blenders, which are <em>loud. </em>If you’ve ever woken up to the ear-piercing shriek of a blender you know the sound they make isn’t exactly pleasant. That being said, not all blenders double as alarm clocks and there are some quieter options on the market that allow you to blend your fruit without creating a symphony of screeches. In an effort to make your mornings (and our’s, to be honest) more peaceful, we researched dozens of blenders to the quietest ones that won’t wake your significant others or roommates up in the morning.</p> 
 
 
<div></div> 
<p><span style="font-family:'acumin-pro-condensed', sans-serif;font-size:20px;font-weight:600;letter-spacing:.04em;">What to look for in a quiet blender</span></p> 
<p>The tricky thing about shopping for quiet blenders is that most blender companies don’t actually share their product’s decibel ratings online, making it difficult to see which *say*  they’re quiet and which are *actually* quiet. That said, there are some other qualities you can consider to ensure a blender isn’t a noisy nuisance.</p> 
<p><span style="font-family:'acumin-pro-condensed', sans-serif;font-size:17px;font-weight:600;">Quiet covers</span></p> 
<p>Many blenders with a quiet design come with quiet covers, which are exactly what they sound like — covers that get placed over the blender to help contain the sound. These are often removable, so you can choose to use the covers at times when running a blender is not entirely possible, such as in the early mornings or during nap time. Bonus: They double as a spray shield, keeping fruit, juice, and whatever else you’re mixing up splattering all over the place. Quiet <em>and </em>clean? Yes, please.</p> 
<h3>‘Quiet Technology’</h3> 
<p>Other blenders are manufactured with what many brands call “quiet technology” to help lower the decibel rating and, therefore, result in a more quiet blending experience. This varies from brand to brand, but is oftentimes a more powerful motor or blade arrangement, which can help pull the food into a vortex to liquify it opposed to traditional crushing.</p> 
<h3>Reviews</h3> 
<p>Real-world testing is always beneficial, whether you want a regular blender or one that is a bit quieter. While not every website has product reviews available, the perks of shopping for quiet blenders on Amazon and other e-commerce websites is that customers can share in-depth reviews where they note how quiet the appliances actually are, plus other important factors like quality, how easy it is to use, and more.</p> 
<div></div> 
<h2>5 quiet blenders that won’t wake everyone up</h2> 
<div> 
  <div> 
     
     
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.amazon.com/VOVGUU-Commercial-Soundproof-Smoothie-Self-Cleaning/dp/B0B9FW2C7W/"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/VOVGUU-Quiet-Blender.jpg" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/VOVGUU-Commercial-Soundproof-Smoothie-Self-Cleaning/dp/B0B9FW2C7W/"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/VOVGUU-Commercial-Soundproof-Smoothie-Self-Cleaning/dp/B0B9FW2C7W/">Vovguu, Quiet Blender — $144.00</a></div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/VOVGUU-Commercial-Soundproof-Smoothie-Self-Cleaning/dp/B0B9FW2C7W/"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p><strong>Originally $200, now $144</strong></p> 
<p>The Vovguu Quiet Blender is one of the most quiet blenders that exists. Albeit a little bulky, this blender is designed specifically to reduce noise by 37 percent compared to a standard blender, and Amazon shoppers agree that it’s not nearly as loud as others. Its quietness comes from the removal soundproof shield cover that actually covers the whole blender, not just the lid. It’s detachable, making it easy to take out the blending cup when you’re done making you’re smoothie and need to clean both pieces. “I love the blender. It’s absolutely incredible and as close to complete silence as you will ever get. I don’t even use the additional sound cover,” says one reviewer.</p> 
<p>As for the blending cup, the 48-ounce glass is durable, long-lasting, and can make several smoothie servings in one go. Each blender also has 10 different functions so, in addition to smoothies, you can also make your own baby food, soup, nut milk, and more, all in the click of a button.</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Includes a removable soundproof shield cover 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Affordable 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Powerful 4D blending system 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>10 pre-set functions 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Anti-paste protection in the blending cup for easy cleaning 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Bulkier than most blenders 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Heavy 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/VOVGUU-Commercial-Soundproof-Smoothie-Self-Cleaning/dp/B0B9FW2C7W/"> 
            SHOP NOW      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.amazon.com/BLACK-DECKER-PowerCrush-Technology-BL1300DG-P/dp/B073D8W6J6/"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/BLACKDECKER-PowerCrush-Digital-Blender-with-Quiet-Technology.jpg" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/BLACK-DECKER-PowerCrush-Technology-BL1300DG-P/dp/B073D8W6J6/"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/BLACK-DECKER-PowerCrush-Technology-BL1300DG-P/dp/B073D8W6J6/">Black+Decker, PowerCrush Digital Blender with Quiet Technology — $70.00</a></div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/BLACK-DECKER-PowerCrush-Technology-BL1300DG-P/dp/B073D8W6J6/"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p><strong>Originally $85, now $70</strong></p> 
<p>The Black+Decker PowerCrush Digital Blender With Quiet Technology is another ultra-quiet blender you can snag on Amazon Prime—and this one costs under $100.</p> 
<p>This quiet blender is beloved for its muted sound and function, as it can crush frozen fruit and ice into a smoothie consistency without causing a scene.“I hate the ear-blasting sound of most blenders and, when I tried to find a quiet one, they were way too expensive—this one ticks both the quiet and the affordable box,” says one Amazon customer. That’s thanks to the brand’s “Quiet Technology”, aka, the blade configuration which pulls food down into a vortex to minimize disruptions. The blender comes with three different speeds plus a pulsing feature, has a functional lid with a pour spot, and also comes with an 18-ounce smoothie cup so you can take your blended fruit on the go. For a basic, no-frills quiet blender, it’s a solid bet.</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros: </strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Utilizes “quiet technology” for noise control 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Affordable 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Three speeds + pulsing feature 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Includes a pour lid and to-go cup 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Lightweight and sleek 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>No pre-set functions 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Small 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/BLACK-DECKER-PowerCrush-Technology-BL1300DG-P/dp/B073D8W6J6/"> 
            SHOP NOW      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://blendjet.com/products/blendjet-2"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/BlendJet-2-Portable-Blender.jpg" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://blendjet.com/products/blendjet-2"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://blendjet.com/products/blendjet-2">BlendJet, 2 Portable Blender — $50.00</a></div><a href="https://blendjet.com/products/blendjet-2"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p><strong>Originally $100, now $50</strong></p> 
<p>If you’re someone who loves smoothies but also travels a lot (or someone who would prefer to drink their smoothie at the office), a travel blender is a must-have. The best travel blender is the BlendJet 2 Portable Blender, which also happens to be incredibly quiet, too.</p> 
<p>I was first introduced to this blender while on vacation with a friend and was impressed not only by how quiet it sounded, but also by how easy it is to take on the go, whether you are on a trip or going to the office. This portable blender is USB-powered and features a small but mighty motor that blends ingredients to smooth perfection with a battery that lasts up to 15 blends. Additionally, this blender is also super easy to clean (just add water and soap, and whirl) and comes in lots of fun colors and patterns so you can make your smoothies in style.</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Portable and lightweight 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Easy to use 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Quiet 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Easy to clean 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Small 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Basic, no-frills design 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://blendjet.com/products/blendjet-2"> 
            SHOP NOW      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Hamilton-Beach-Professional-BPA-free-58870/dp/B01H4WN7EW/"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Hamilton-Beach-Professional-Quiet-Shield-Blender.jpg" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Hamilton-Beach-Professional-BPA-free-58870/dp/B01H4WN7EW/"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Hamilton-Beach-Professional-BPA-free-58870/dp/B01H4WN7EW/">Hamilton Beach, Professional Quiet Shield Blender — $180.00</a></div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Hamilton-Beach-Professional-BPA-free-58870/dp/B01H4WN7EW/"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>For a quiet blender that can live on your countertop and be used for everything from soups to sauces to smoothies, we recommend the Hamilton Beach Professional Quiet Shield Blender. This blender has rave reviews from Amazon customers for both its included “quiet shield” and also its versatility since it allows you to not only blend but also puree, crush, chop, and emulsify ingredients.</p> 
<p>The blender on its own isn’t all that quiet, however, the quiet shield helps to completely mask the sound when in use. “The shield that goes over the mixer container and blade makes one heck of a difference,” writes one Amazon customer. “I can barely hear it in the second-story bedroom and our kitchen is almost directly below it with a large air vent that transfers sound like an amplifier,” they add. Ideal for the smoothie lover and the home cook, that shield essentially puts the blender into stealth mode, so you can make smoothies in the wee hours of the morning without worrying about waking others up.</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Includes Quiet Shield 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Powerful and versatile 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Variable speed dial for custom blending 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Four pre-set programs and a self-cleaning function 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Includes tamper for thick ingredients 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>5-year warranty 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons: </strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Expensive 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Hamilton-Beach-Professional-BPA-free-58870/dp/B01H4WN7EW/"> 
            SHOP NOW      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Blender-Smoothies-Shakes-Kitchen-Countertop/dp/B093JC4VD2/"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Beast-Blender-.jpg" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Blender-Smoothies-Shakes-Kitchen-Countertop/dp/B093JC4VD2/"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Blender-Smoothies-Shakes-Kitchen-Countertop/dp/B093JC4VD2/"> Beast Blender — $165.00</a></div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Blender-Smoothies-Shakes-Kitchen-Countertop/dp/B093JC4VD2/"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>Thanks to the Best Blender, you can have a quiet blender <em>and</em> a pretty blender. While it might look like a sculpture for your kitchen countertop, this stylish blender is so much more than its looks. According to Amazon customers, the blender is also incredibly quiet, makes the smoothest of smoothies, and is super easy to clean (which is a must for blenders).</p> 
<p>“I thought my previous Breville blender was quiet, but this one is a whisper by comparison,” writes one Amazon customer. Another customer notes that the blender’s motor has more of a humming sound, which is easier on the ears. The blender also features a slender space-saving design and is made for convenience, thanks to its carrying cap, which attaches to the blending vessel and transforms it into an on-the-go smoothie jar.</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros: </strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Stylish 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Quiet 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Doubles as a to-go cup 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Expensive 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Not as versatile as other blenders 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Blender-Smoothies-Shakes-Kitchen-Countertop/dp/B093JC4VD2/"> 
            SHOP NOW      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
            </div> 
</div>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 13:27:42 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Fitness</category>
<dc:creator>Jessie Quinn</dc:creator>
<source url="http://wellandgood.com/">Well+Good</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75162e8687</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 3 Most-Effective Abs Exercises You Can Do at Home Using Just a Wall</title>
<link>https://www.wellandgood.com/wall-abs-exercises/</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>By now you’ve likely done your fair share of abs exercises like bicycles, burpees, planks, and mountain climbers. But what about wall abs? For those unfamiliar with the concept, wall abs exercises are a simple, space-efficient way to get a killer core workout from the comfort of your own home.</p> 
<p>Wall abs exercises involve using a wall to support and stabilize the body while performing various core-strengthening exercises. From beginner to advanced, wall abs exercises provide a great way to target the core and increase overall strength and stability while breaking up the monotony of doing abs exercises on the floor all the time.</p> 
<p>“The abs muscles respond well to <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/muscular-endurance/">muscular endurance exercises</a> that require full-body tension and isometric contractions,” says <a href="https://www.instagram.com/rkat51/">Becky Codi</a>, a certified personal trainer, strength coach, and kettlebell specialist. “A wall is an immovable object, so by placing your hands or feet on a wall and pushing, you are performing an isometric exercise where there is no shortening or lengthening of the muscle fibers.” This means your abs are constantly working under tension without a break while you’re performing an exercise, and that’s what helps them build muscular endurance, meaning they’ll be able to work for you longer when you need them. For example, when you’re carrying heavy groceries, you’re gonna want a strong core that can sustain your for the entire trip back from Trader Joe’s.</p> 
<h2>3 wall abs exercises to start doing now</h2> 
<p>Codi says that while there is not a definitive list of the best wall abs exercises, you want to include ones that require you to hold different body positions.  “You want to include a supine movement, lying on your back, a prone movement—facedown, like a plank—and a standing movement,” says Codi, who recommends you perform all of these exercises for 20 seconds to a minute, depending on your fitness level.</p> 
<h3>1. Wall Deadbug</h3> 
<p><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" title="How To Do A Dead Bug, A Common Pilates Core Move | The Right Way | Well+Good" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xGEmmJZdf5g?feature=oembed" frameborder="0"></iframe></p> 
<p>Deadbugs primarily work your deep core stabilizers and abdominal wall, according to Codi. She says that, while performing this variation of the exercise, it’s important to keep tension by pressing your palms into the wall because “this will force your rib cage down and keep your spine flush with the floor.”</p> 
<p><strong>How to:</strong> Start lying on your back with you head facing a wall and scoot your body forward until you can press your palms firmly into the wall (fingers pointing toward the floor) with straight arms. While keeping constant tension between your palms and the wall—really press into it—lift your bent legs into the air so that your knees are above your hips and shins are parallel to the floor. Without straightening your legs, lower your right heel down to tap the floor, then draw that knee back over your hip and switch sides. Continue alternating heel taps for 10–15 reps per side.</p> 
<h3>2. Plank Against a Wall</h3> 
<p><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" title="How to do a Forearm Plank | The Right Way | Well+Good" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mH5Sfb_KTGg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0"></iframe></p> 
<p>Planks work the entire core: the transverse, rectus, and obliques, and Codi says that the benefit of doing wall planks is that using the wall helps you hold proper form and prevents your hips from sagging.</p> 
<p><strong>How to:</strong> Come into a forearm plank position with your heels against the wall and your body extending out away from it, elbows stacked under your shoulders.<br> 
Push your feet into the wall, and maintain a long, tight position through your spine, hugging your abs up to the ceiling. Hold for 20 to 60 seconds or about five to 10 breaths. If you want to make it more difficult, come to a high plank position on your hands and place your feet flat against the wall so that your heels are in line with your hips and shoulders (about 12 inches off the floor), Codi suggests. “Warning, this is tough!” she says.</p> 
<h3>3. Hollow Body on a Wall</h3> 
<p>With this ab exercise using a wall, you want to feel as though you are dragging your hands down the wall, but you’re not actually moving them at all.</p> 
<p>How to: Stand facing a wall with your feet six inches away from the base and your arms extended straight overhead, biceps by ears, and palms pressing into the wall. Tuck your tailbone and hug your ribs down toward your hips, then press your hands hard into the wall and feel like you could slide them down at the same time—without actually moving them. Try to hold this position for 20 seconds to a minute. Keep your abs tight the whole time.</p> 
<h2>Who should try wall abs exercises</h2> 
<p>Codi says that anyone can benefit from doing ab exercises on a wall, and that these particular wall ab exercises are beginner-friendly.</p> 
<p>“If you are just getting started and don’t quite understand the concept of what tension feels like, you should definitely try these exercises,” says Codi, who adds that while wall abs exercises are not necessarily better than floor abs exercises, the wall is a helpful prop to increase core tension, which is a big part of making abs exercises effective that most people miss. “Once your body knows what tension feels like,” she says, “you can replicate it in multiple situations.”</p> 
<p>Plus, if you have <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/fitness-wellness-trends/fitness/mobility-workouts/">mobility issues</a> or struggle to get up and down off of the ground, some of these ab exercises on the wall may be easier to incorporate into your fitness routine.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 00:22:48 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Fitness</category>
<dc:creator>Amber Sayer</dc:creator>
<source url="http://wellandgood.com/">Well+Good</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e7517ed82cd</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Postpartum Hair Loss Was Worse Than I Expected—These Are the Products That Actually Helped</title>
<link>https://www.wellandgood.com/postpartum-hair-loss-products/</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>When you go through pregnancy, you may be expecting plenty of uncomfortable side effects over the course of 40 weeks; however, the fun doesn’t stop there. Despite reading all the baby books, I was still taken aback by how long I experienced <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/postpartum-doula-duties-role/">postpartum side effects</a>, which can range from mood changes to <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/pelvic-floor-exercises-for-incontinence/">incontinence if you have a vaginal birth</a>. And around three months postpartum, one of the longest-lasting effects kicked in: postpartum hair loss.</p> 
<p>Despite expecting it, I still found I was shocked at <em>how </em>much hair I lost, and even more so by how long it has taken to grow back in. I spoke with <a href="https://falsecreekdermatology.com/about.html">Christina Han</a>, MD FRCPC, a board-certified dermatologist at <a href="https://falsecreekdermatology.com/index.html">False Creek Dermatology</a>, to learn more about what causes postpartum hair loss and what can be done to help.</p> 
<h2>What is postpartum hair loss?</h2> 
<p>“Postpartum hair loss is related to a drop in hormone levels after pregnancy,” explains Dr. Han. “Pregnancy hormones such as estrogen and progesterone are present at high levels to sustain a pregnancy, but after delivery, these levels drop and can trigger hairs to fall out.”</p> 
<p>For most people, postpartum hair loss begins around three to four months after a baby is born and can last up to six months. Regrowth can start any time around that point, but, as Dr. Han points out, it progresses <em>slowly</em>. In fact, she shared that it’s about one centimeter per month, so it can take several months for there to really be noticeable regrowth.</p> 
<p>The severity of hair loss can also differ from person to person. “Depending on how much hair someone has at baseline, some people can experience worse and/or more noticeable postpartum hair loss than others,” says Dr. Han. “Rarely, some people can progress to <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/difference-between-hair-thinning-hair-shedding/">genetic hair loss</a> after postpartum hair loss, in which case it can be progressively chronic without further treatment. If there is no improvement in the hair loss, then it is time to see a doctor to rule out other <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/common-hair-loss-causes/">causes of hair loss</a>.” Common hair loss causes include stress, aggressive brushing, <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/vitamin-d-deficiency/">vitamin D deficiency</a>, and hormones.</p> 
<h2>Solutions for postpartum hair loss</h2> 
<p>It can be <em>very </em>frustrating to hear this in the midst of postpartum hair loss, but one of the biggest solutions? Time. At 11 months postpartum, I am currently rocking some two-inch baby hairs around my hairline.  This, Dr. Han explains, isn’t out of the ordinary. “I reassure my patients this type of hair loss is temporary and very common,” she says. “Therefore, specific treatments are not necessary other than to stay healthy with good nutrition, sleep, and stress reduction.”</p> 
<p>Considering how difficult tweaking these lifestyle factors can be when you’re caring for a new baby, there are a few at-home treatments and products that can help speed the process along. Here are a few that Dr. Han recommends:</p> 
<ol> 
<li><a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/shampoos-thin-hair/"><strong> Volumizing shampoos</strong></a> to add volume to the hair.</li> 
<li><a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/dry-shampoo-hair-type/"><strong> Dry shampoos </strong></a>can be great for minimizing excessive washing between shampoos, and can also add some volume to the scalp.</li> 
<li><a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/best-conditioners-thinning-hair/"><strong> Light conditioners</strong></a> to use on the ends of your hair, to prevent the added weight of heavy conditioners.</li> 
<li><strong> Minimize tight buns/ponytails</strong> and hairstyles that can put undue stress on the follicles.</li> 
<li><strong> Try out a new hairstyle.</strong></li> 
</ol> 
<h2>Products that worked for me with postpartum hair loss</h2> 
<p>I have always been the person that has had a 12-step <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/postpartum-beauty/">ritual for my skincare</a>, but when it comes to hair care, my product list is sparse. However, this changed when I started experiencing postpartum hair loss. While nothing has completely changed the effects of postpartum hair loss, these three products have been fantastic in helping to manage it.</p> 
<div> 
  <div> 
     
     
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Captain-Blankenship-Mermaid-Hair-Bottle/dp/B01L29ZMBO"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/61BWEG5g4aL._SL1500_.jpg" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Captain-Blankenship-Mermaid-Hair-Bottle/dp/B01L29ZMBO"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Captain-Blankenship-Mermaid-Hair-Bottle/dp/B01L29ZMBO">Captain Blankenship Hair and Scalp Serum — $48.00</a></div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Captain-Blankenship-Mermaid-Hair-Bottle/dp/B01L29ZMBO"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>I have never been someone who has done treatments to my hair, but this scalp serum changed my mind forever. While you can use a bit on dry hair, when I had baby hairs growing in postpartum, I would use this as an overnight treatment and found that it made my hair look healthier and more shiny than ever.</p> 
<p> </p> 
</div> 
           
                               
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Captain-Blankenship-Mermaid-Hair-Bottle/dp/B01L29ZMBO"> 
            Shop now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.randco.com/products/spiritualized-dry-shampoo-mist"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/71Oe4SORML._SL1500_-1.jpg" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.randco.com/products/spiritualized-dry-shampoo-mist"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.randco.com/products/spiritualized-dry-shampoo-mist">R + Co, Spiritualized Dry Shampoo Mist — $16.00</a></div><a href="https://www.randco.com/products/spiritualized-dry-shampoo-mist"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>I’ve never been a huge fan of the feeling of dry shampoo in my hair, despite loving the effect it has. But this mist has made a world of difference. A few spritzes of it in my hair, and then a quick blow dry through, and I’m left with a ton of volume.</p> 
</div> 
           
                               
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.randco.com/products/spiritualized-dry-shampoo-mist"> 
            Shop now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Massager-Shampoo-Silicon-Tourmaline-Contained/dp/B076Q6442Z"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/61aQt6lRLvL._SL1500_.jpg" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Massager-Shampoo-Silicon-Tourmaline-Contained/dp/B076Q6442Z"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Massager-Shampoo-Silicon-Tourmaline-Contained/dp/B076Q6442Z">HEETA, Hair Shampoo Brush — $7.00</a></div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Massager-Shampoo-Silicon-Tourmaline-Contained/dp/B076Q6442Z"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>I started using a shampoo brush when I was in the thick (or not-so-thick) of postpartum hair loss, but now I will never be without it. Using this brush to massage in shampoo helps to soothe my scalp, and leaving my hair feeling lighter and cleaner than ever before.</p> 
</div> 
           
                               
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Massager-Shampoo-Silicon-Tourmaline-Contained/dp/B076Q6442Z"> 
            Shop now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
            </div> 
</div> 
<p>Postpartum hair loss can be alarming and can cause self-confidence issues during a particularly challenging period of a new parent’s life. However, it’s important to remember that this change is temporary (a mantra you’ll find me repeating to myself constantly). As Dr. Han explained, “It’s a lot of reassurance that it is temporary and that the hair will grow back. It can be really alarming due to the often abrupt nature and even ‘clumps’ of hair falling out or shedding even with simple things like brushing and washing. Rest assured, the hair follicles are still intact and the hairs are going to grow back.”</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 22:50:34 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Fitness</category>
<dc:creator>Morgan Flaherty</dc:creator>
<source url="http://wellandgood.com/">Well+Good</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e7517eb88af</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>7 Things You Should Always Do Before You Drink Coffee in the Morning—Not After</title>
<link>https://www.wellandgood.com/before-you-drink-coffee/</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/WG_Logo-1130x300.png" alt="WG_Logo-1130x300.png"></p><p>If you’re the type to go to bed already dreaming about your morning cappuccino (we’re with you!) the thought of doing <em>anything </em>before an a.m. caffeine fix may seem unreasonable—but hear us out. There are <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/brush-teeth-before-or-after-drinking-coffee/">a number of things</a> you really should be doing <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/coffee-first-thing-morning/">before you drink coffee in the morning</a>—from eating breakfast to brushing your teeth. Getting the order right is about more than keeping your teeth healthy and white, too.</p>  
<p>“Supporting your morning coffee routine with some strategic practices can be a game changer for digestion, stress, hormone balance, energy and so much more,” says <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/abigail-hueber-rd-ldn-6095451b">Abigail Hueber</a>, RD, LDN, a functional dietitian and digestive health expert.</p>  
<p>What’s more, jumping out of bed and reaching for a cup of Joe may activate the release of stress hormones including adrenaline and cortisol. “<a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/high-cortisol-levels/">Cortisol is an important hormone</a> that we do want to be released in the morning, but the caffeine hit from coffee on an empty stomach can lead to an over-stimulated release of cortisol and trigger an unhelpful stress response that can impact our gut, hormones, adrenals, and energy [in negative ways],” says Hueber. Fortunately, there are some strategic practices you can do before drinking coffee first thing to better support your body and reduce a potential stress response.</p>  
<h2>Here’s a look at what you should do <em>before </em>you drink coffee</h2>  
<h3>1. Rehydrate</h3>  
<p>Your body dehydrates overnight, so before enjoying your morning coffee, Hueber says that it’s important to drink 16 ounces of a mineral-rich drink to re-up your <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/electrolyte-body-needs/">electrolytes</a>. “When I say minerals, I’m talking most about potassium and sodium, which help to direct the water where to go in the body for optimal hydration, as well as play a major role in supporting everything from our adrenals to blood sugar and even our hormone balance.” She suggests mixing eight ounces of a potassium-rich drink like coconut water, aloe vera juice, grapefruit or orange juice with a pinch of salt and eight ounces of water for morning hydration before coffee.</p>  
<h3>2. Eat fiber and protein</h3>  
<p>As mentioned, coffee on an empty stomach can stimulate cortisol, which can spike blood sugar. “Elevated blood sugar can trigger inflammation and set us up to be on a blood sugar roller coaster for the rest of the day thereby tanking our energy,” says Hueber. “But when we start the day with <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/foods-with-soluble-and-insoluble-fiber/">fiber from a whole food source</a>, we can majorly help to balance blood sugar.” She suggests having half a cup of berries, a banana, an orange, or a date with almond butter before your morning coffee.</p>  
<p>In addition to fiber, protein is the other  major macronutrients that counter-balance a spike in blood sugar, so consuming some either before you drink coffee or with your coffee is ideal, according to Hueber, who recommends <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/jennifer-aniston-coffee/">adding a scoop of collagen protein into your coffee <em>á la</em> Jennifer Aniston</a>. “This can have a major benefit on better blood sugar balance and make a positive impact on your body’s stress and inflammation balance, all without changing the flavor or consistency of your coffee.”</p>  
<h3>3. Work out</h3>  
<p>While <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/caffeine-gum/">caffeine can be helpful for making tough workouts feel less difficult</a>, having your coffee before heading to the gym could make you anxious during your workout, according to <a href="https://www.instagram.com/franceslrothrd/?hl=en">Frances Largeman-Roth</a>, RDN, nutrition expert and author of the upcoming book <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Everyday-Snack-Tray-Recipes-Nourish/dp/0800744993/ref=sr_1_6?"><em>Everyday Snack Tray</em></a>. “Plus, since both coffee, especially black coffee, and exercise are GI stimulants, having your <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/why-does-coffee-make-you-poop/">coffee before your sweat session could leave you running for the bathroom</a>.” If this caffeine delay seems unrealistic, Largeman-Roth suggests starting by trying to cut down to a few sips versus indulging in your usual full cup pre-workout.</p>  
<h3>4. Brush your teeth</h3>  
<p>This one probably surprises most people. “The acids in coffee weaken the enamel on our teeth and brushing right after drinking coffee can be damaging to our pearly whites,” says Largeman-Roth. Alternatively: “If you wait about 30 minutes [after drinking coffee to brush], your teeth can remineralize and brushing is no longer problematic.”</p>  
<h3>5. Go to the bathroom</h3>  
<p>“Definitely take care of your bladder and other bodily functions before pouring that first cup,” says Largeman-Roth. “Coffee will trigger you to pee, so emptying your bladder first is a smart thing to do.”</p>  
<h3>6. Wait 90 minutes after waking up</h3>  
<p>This is the ideal scenario according to Hueber because delaying caffeine for the first 90 minutes of waking allows for the best hormone balance. “Within the first hour of waking, our cortisol levels ideally acutely rise and fall in a response known as our <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/symptoms-of-low-cortisol/">cortisol awakening response</a>, or CAR. This rise and fall of cortisol represents a healthy nervous system and actually has a big influence over our immune health and even risk of autoimmune development. Pausing on caffeine for the first 90 minutes helps to promote the most balanced CAR and can even better support our energy levels throughout the day.”</p>  
<h3>7. Take a walk</h3>  
<p>If you’re reaching for caffeine first thing to help you feel more awake and alert, there is a better way to acheive both: “Getting natural light exposure within the first hour or so of waking is a major way to support optimal hormone balance and a healthy CAR response,” says Hueber. The combo of walking and light, she says, is a win-win for hormones, energy, and overall health. “Morning light exposure is a huge regulator of circadian rhythm and light exposure triggers the healthy release of cortisol in the morning to support the body’s natural rhythm, but just remember, we need at least 10–15 minutes without sunglasses to get that natural light exposure on our eyeballs.” BYOB (bringing your own brew) or picking up a coffee at your local café sounds like a pretty nice way to start the day.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 21:19:48 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Fitness</category>
<dc:creator>Sharon Feiereisen</dc:creator>
<source url="http://wellandgood.com/">Well+Good</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e7517d1e793</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>There’s a Good Chance You’re Friendlier on Vacation—Here’s How To Bring That Energy Into Your Regular Life</title>
<link>https://www.wellandgood.com/friendlier-on-vacation/</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/GettyImages-1391299866-resized.jpg" alt="GettyImages-1391299866-resized.jpg"></p><p>Whether you’re sipping margaritas on a beach somewhere or experiencing one of the world’s wonders, it’s safe to say that the vibe is just different when it comes to vacations. With some distance (literally) from everyday routines and stressors, you likely feel more relaxed, happier, and excited about life than you do day to day. Another potential vacation shift you may experience: feeling friendlier. According to a recent survey, more than seven in 10 Americans say that they’re <a href="https://talker.news/2023/03/08/3-in-4-americans-talk-to-strangers-more-on-vacation-than-at-home/?utm_campaign=Distro%20Contacts%20roundups&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;_hsmi=249209423&amp;_hsenc=p2ANqtz-_ztk1pZ_4-cFV-WtKxAJLNChHM1jpB0lE0mfbAAv0iH9FPr-JSQbFjBDvwTi60sIyIzzFkH6EgovM0pMVYLjBwFNu53XOUUm5WJai9Z04oYjU-IGs&amp;utm_content=249209423&amp;utm_source=hs_email">more likely to chat with strangers</a> when they’re on vacation compared to their normal day-to-day life.</p>  
<p>Ahead, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/drsanamhafeez/?hl=en">Sanam Hafeez</a>, PsyD, a neuropsychologist and director of <a href="http://www.comprehendthemind.com/">Comprehend the Mind</a>, and <a href="https://drkatecummins.com/">Kate Cummins</a>, PsyD, a licensed clinical psychologist, explain why this may be. Plus, they offer tips on bringing this friendly energy into your everyday life for a happiness boost—no traveling required.</p>  
<h2>Why you may be friendlier while on vacation</h2>  
<p>Life is busy and often social connections can be put on the back burner. However, when we’re on vacation, Dr. Cummins says our minds are free of life’s demands, thus making us more open and expansive, leading to increased friendliness. There’s also a shift in our perspective while on holiday that makes us more open to connecting. “People have cognitively conditioned themselves into believing they have more flexibility and freedom on vacation versus being at home because of the idea of being stress-free,” Dr. Cummins says. This isn’t necessarily true she says, but rather a perception of our reality. “But the <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/psychological-flexibility-improves-relationships/">cognitive flexibility</a> allows for people to shift perspective into believing they’re in a more fluid state so [they] are more flexible in the approach to contact with others,” Dr. Cummins adds.</p>  
<p>Furthermore, when traveling somewhere new, Dr. Cummins says you often need to rely on others for guidance on adapting to the local culture and norms, which can make you more open to interacting with strangers. Dr. Hafeez adds that another potential reason you may be more likely to chat with someone you don’t know on vacation is that holidays are often associated with less screen time, which can limit opportunities for interaction with others. “By avoiding constant phone use, individuals can fully engage with their surroundings, learn more about their destination, and have meaningful interactions with locals and other travelers,” she says.</p>  
<h2>So, does friendliness contribute to feeling happier during vacations?</h2>  
<p>All that said, it begs the question: Can increased openness to social interaction contribute to overall vacation happiness, or is the happiness boost from being on vacation what leads to feeling friendlier? The short answer: It’s both.</p>  
<p>Dr. Hafeez says positive social interactions during vacations can create a sense of belonging and connectedness, which contribute to happiness and well-being. “This sense of community is essential for people who are traveling alone or who are in unfamiliar surroundings,” she says. So vacationers who are more open to social interaction, she adds, are more likely to have positive vacation experiences and feel happy during their travels.</p>  
<p>From a different perspective, increased happiness when on vacation inspires us to connect more with others. Dr. Cummins notes that people generally feel happier on vacation because all the excitement of visiting a new location and trying new things provides a <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/dopamine-vs-serotonin/">dopamine high</a>, and that happiness can extend outward toward people who are part of the vacation setting. “An openness to interaction and friendly nature are results of an already positive emotion existing internally and creating an external connection based on the internal feelings and thoughts,” she explains.</p>  
<p>In other words, feeling happier while on vacation leads to an increased openness for connection, which in turn, also contributes to vacation happiness and satisfaction. It goes both ways.</p>  
<h2>How to bring vacation friendliness to your everyday life</h2>  
<p>The good news is that you don’t have to wait until your next getaway to chat with strangers for a boost of happiness. “Research has shown that <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/relationships-help-you-live-longer/">social interaction and positive relationships positively affect well-being and happiness</a> in general,” Dr. Hafeez says. “So being friendlier and more open to talking to strangers may still positively impact happiness outside vacation settings.” Here are some ways to bring that friendly energy to your everyday life.</p>  
<p>For starters, Dr. Hafeez says you must be open and intentional about having more social interactions, meaning take an interest in the people you come across and make an effort to engage in small talk. “Everyone has their own story, and taking the time to listen to people can give you new ways to look at life, new places to visit, or new restaurants in your city to try,” Dr. Hafeez says. “At the very least, it can provide a <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/conversational-intelligence/201905/the-neuroscience-conversations">thought-provoking conversation that develops a stronger brain</a>.”</p>  
<p>Taking this further, Dr. Cummins notes it’s also important to intentionally create positive external energy by making people feel warm and comfortable around you. And Dr. Cummins and Dr. Hafeez both agree that smiling is also part of exuding friendly energy and making yourself more approachable. “A smile is a universal signal of connection and kindness with others,” Dr. Cummins says. “When you are smiling, you create automatic behavioral cues with others that allow for friendly interaction immediately.”</p>  
<p>And lastly, try to limit your screen time. “Just like on vacation, taking breaks from technology can help you be more present and open to social interactions,” Dr. Hafeez says. In other words, put down your phone when opportunities for connection present themselves.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 19:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Fitness</category>
<dc:creator>Jessica Estrada</dc:creator>
<source url="http://wellandgood.com/">Well+Good</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e7517dafadd</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>11 Hypoallergenic Makeup Must-Haves Formulated With Sensitive-Skin Types in Mind</title>
<link>https://www.wellandgood.com/best-hypoallergenic-makeup/</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to a recent surge in sensitive-skin friendly skin-care products, finding gentler alternatives to traditionally harsh products like retinols and chemical peels is easier than ever. But finding hypoallergenic makeup that doesn’t cause a flare up? That’s a different story. Even though they offer fabulous results, many popular products on the market still feature ingredients that can trigger rashes, itchiness, and irritation. There <em>are </em>exciting options for people with skin allergies—you just have to know what to look for.</p> 
 
 
<div></div> 
<h2>What is hypoallergenic makeup?</h2> 
<p>Finding hypoallergenic makeup is complicated because the term “hypoallergenic” isn’t exactly regulated by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA). <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/hypoallergenic-makeup/">As we’ve learned</a>, <em>anything </em>can be a potential allergen or irritant, so it’s hard to say something is 100 percent hypoallergenic when every single person’s skin is different and unique. Generally, though, hypoallergenic makeup, like mascara, foundation, and blush, is made with less ingredients that commonly cause irritations. <a href="https://www.nyderm.org/biography">Macrene Alexiades</a>, MD, PhD, board-certified dermatologist and founder of <a href="https://macreneactives.com/">Macrene Actives</a>, explains that “hypo” means “less than normal,” so in reference to makeup and skincare, hypoallergenic alludes to products that (through less ingredients) are less likely to trigger an allergic reaction. Popular irritants include fragrances, alcohol, dyes, and more.</p> 
<p>When shopping for this type of makeup, looking at the label is your best bet. Doctors like Dr. Alexiades have some general green and red flags to look for when you do.</p> 
<div></div> 
<h2>What to look for in makeup if you have allergies</h2> 
<p>It doesn’t need explaining that if you have a specific allergy, steer clear of those specific allergens in the makeup itself. From there, Dr. Alexiades explains that if you experience any sensitivity to makeup, seek out options have been tested by the pros, like dermatologists and ophthalmologists. “If you have sensitive skin, look for mineral-based makeup as well as formulas that state they’ve gone through rigorous allergy testing,” she adds.</p> 
<p>Some products also have a seal to shoppers know it’s been vetted by professionals and made without common irritants, like the <a href="https://nationaleczema.org/eczema-products/about-nea-seal-of-acceptance/">National Eczema Association’s Seal of Acceptance</a> and the <a href="https://www.skinsafeproducts.com/how-skinsafe-works">SkinSafe Seal</a>, which was developed in partnership with MayoClinic.</p> 
<div></div> 
<h2>What to avoid in makeup if you have allergies</h2> 
<p>If you have a skin condition like eczema or hyper-sensitive skin in general, NYC-based dermatologist, <a href="https://angelalambmd.com/">Angela Lamb,</a> MD, says to avoid all makeup that contains fragrance (both synthetic and natural), parabens, or formaldehydes.</p> 
<p>“<a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/paraben-alternatives/">Parabens</a> are preservatives that manufacturers add to products to extend their shelf life, but they commonly cause skin reactions,” Dr. Lamb explains. To tell if a product contains preservatives, check ingredient lists for benzyl alcohol, propylparaben, diazolidinyl urea, and butylparabyn. And to really double down on irritating allergies, Dr. Alexiades adds that avoiding mica, retinol, alpha hydroxy acids, and essential oils can help, too.</p> 
<div></div> 
<h2>11 best hypoallergenic makeup staples</h2> 
<div> 
  <div> 
          <h2>Face</h2> 
     
     
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Anti-Aging-Almay-Hyaluronic-Niacinamide-Hypoallergenic/dp/B0BHLDYF6Q"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Almay-Ageless-Hydrating-Concealer-.jpeg" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Anti-Aging-Almay-Hyaluronic-Niacinamide-Hypoallergenic/dp/B0BHLDYF6Q"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Anti-Aging-Almay-Hyaluronic-Niacinamide-Hypoallergenic/dp/B0BHLDYF6Q">Almay, Ageless Hydrating Concealer — $13.00</a></div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Anti-Aging-Almay-Hyaluronic-Niacinamide-Hypoallergenic/dp/B0BHLDYF6Q"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>According to Dr. Alexiades, Almay makes some of the best hypoallergenic makeup on the market—and this doesn’t fall short. This creamy concealer-slash-eye cream contains a skin-loving combination of niacinamide, hyaluronic acid, electrolytes, and vitamins C and E, making it a great choice for covering up imperfections and correcting the look of dark under-eye circles. Whether you apply it to a small area or across your entire face, it’ll deliver a smooth, youthful-looking complexion.</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros: </strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Dermatologist-tested 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Designed with sensitive skin in mind 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Infused with nourishing ingredients 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Affordable 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Not vegan 
</li> 
                                                                <li>No SPF 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Anti-Aging-Almay-Hyaluronic-Niacinamide-Hypoallergenic/dp/B0BHLDYF6Q"> 
            Shop Now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://howl.me/cjyZIf4siw0"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Tower-28-Sculptino-Soft-Matte-Cream-Contour-Bronzer.webp" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://howl.me/cjyZIf4siw0"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://howl.me/cjyZIf4siw0">Tower 28 Sculptino Soft Matte Cream Contour + Bronzer — $20.00</a></div><a href="https://howl.me/cjyZIf4siw0"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>Tower 28 was made for people with eczema and sensitive skin and is the only brand that follows 100 percent of the National Eczema Association’s strict ingredient guidelines. And it’s products are <em>good, </em>especially this cream contour-slash-bronzer that features tons of nourishing ingredients (like green tea extract, mango seed butter, and castor seed oil) and doesn’t contain anything pore-clogging or irritation-inducing. It also doesn’t contain silicones (like most similar products do), making it a major win for those with an allergy. Nevertheless, it glides onto skin effortlessly and is available in four sheer shades that help add soft-focus dimension to your face.</p> 
<p><strong>Shades</strong>: 4</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Dermatologist tested 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Designed specifically for sensitive-skin 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Infused with nourishing ingredients 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Affordable 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Vegan and gluten-free 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons: </strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>No SPF 
</li> 
                                                                          </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://howl.me/cjyZIf4siw0"> 
            SHOP NOW      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.colorescience.com/products/natural-finish-pressed-foundation-spf-20"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Colorescience-Pressed-Mineral-Foundation-SPF-20.webp" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.colorescience.com/products/natural-finish-pressed-foundation-spf-20"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.colorescience.com/products/natural-finish-pressed-foundation-spf-20">Colorescience, Pressed Mineral Foundation SPF 20 — $59.00</a></div><a href="https://www.colorescience.com/products/natural-finish-pressed-foundation-spf-20"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>When it comes to face makeup, less is more; and with this foundation from sensitive-skin makeup brand Colorescience, it’s in more ways than one. The 2-in-1 pressed powder foundation offers a veil of coverage and SPF 20 sun protection, making for an easier morning routine without extra steps and fussy (and potentially irritating) products. It’s non-comedogenic (aka it won’t clog your pores) and water-resistant for up to 80 minutes.</p> 
<p><strong>Shades:</strong> 7</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros: </strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Designed with sensitive skin in mind 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Made with broad-spectrum mineral SPF 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Infused with nourishing ingredients 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Water-resistant 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Lightweight 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Vegan and gluten-free 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Expensive 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Unclear if it’s been dermatologist tested 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.colorescience.com/products/natural-finish-pressed-foundation-spf-20"> 
            SHOP NOW      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.mineralfusion.com/collections/virtual-try-on/products/liquid-mineral-foundation"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Mineral-Fusion-Liquid-Mineral-Foundation.jpeg" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.mineralfusion.com/collections/virtual-try-on/products/liquid-mineral-foundation"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.mineralfusion.com/collections/virtual-try-on/products/liquid-mineral-foundation">Mineral Fusion Liquid Mineral Foundation — $33.00</a></div><a href="https://www.mineralfusion.com/collections/virtual-try-on/products/liquid-mineral-foundation"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>Those that prefer a liquid foundation over powder will love this option from Mineral Fusion. Its hypoallergenic formula blends seamlessly over skin, minimizing the look of dark spots and discoloration, creating a more even-looking skin tone. Antioxidant-rich ingredients like green tea and pomegranate work in tandem with skin-smoothing peptides to give skin a IRL filter look while feeling weightless and comfortable.</p> 
<p><strong>Shades:</strong> 24</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros: </strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Designed with sensitive skin in mind 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Infused with nourishing ingredients 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>EWG-verified 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Inclusive shade range 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Vegan and gluten-free 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons: </strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Unclear if it’s been dermatologist-tested 
</li> 
                                                                <li>No SPF 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.mineralfusion.com/collections/virtual-try-on/products/liquid-mineral-foundation"> 
            SHOP NOW      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.amazon.com/jane-iredale-Non-Comedogenic-Antioxidants-Cruelty-Free/dp/B09RVTLSLD"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Jane-Iredale-PurePressed-Blush.webp" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/jane-iredale-Non-Comedogenic-Antioxidants-Cruelty-Free/dp/B09RVTLSLD"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/jane-iredale-Non-Comedogenic-Antioxidants-Cruelty-Free/dp/B09RVTLSLD">Jane Iredale, PurePressed Blush — $32.00</a></div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/jane-iredale-Non-Comedogenic-Antioxidants-Cruelty-Free/dp/B09RVTLSLD"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>With a silky smooth glide and easy blendability, the PurePressed Blush from Jane Iredale builds like a powder and blends like a cream for seamless, long-lasting color. The 14 shades include a variety of colors in warm, cool, and neutral undertones and are designed to suit all skin tones. The formula features a slew of good-for-you ingredients like shea butter and jojoba seed oil, so you can soften and soothe the skin while you wear it.</p> 
<p><strong>Shades:</strong> 14</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros: </strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Designed with sensitive-skin in mind 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Infused with nourishing ingredients 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Inclusive shade range 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Vegan and gluten-free 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Blendable and buildable 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons: </strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Unclear if it’s been dermatologist tested 
</li> 
                                                                <li>No SPF 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/jane-iredale-Non-Comedogenic-Antioxidants-Cruelty-Free/dp/B09RVTLSLD"> 
            Shop Now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://howl.me/cjGcNru5t92"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Peter-Thomas-Roth-Instant-FIRMx-No-Filter-Primer.webp" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://howl.me/cjGcNru5t92"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://howl.me/cjGcNru5t92">Peter Thomas Roth, Instant FIRMx No Filter Primer — $42.00</a></div><a href="https://howl.me/cjGcNru5t92"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>Primers are an integral part of any makeup routine, as they help makeup go on smoother and last far longer. Dr. Madfes is a fan of this formula from Peter Thomas Roth, sharing that it’s especially perfect for sensitive skin. “The tint blends nicely and it has active ingredients that are non-irritating,” she explains. It even boasts a blurring effect that temporarily hides the look of fine lines and pores for a flawless yet natural finish.</p> 
<p> </p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros: </strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Infused with nourishing ingredients 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Blurring effect 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons: </strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Expensive 
</li> 
                                                                <li>No SPF 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Unclear if it’s been dermatologist tested 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Not vegan or gluten-free 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://howl.me/cjGcNru5t92"> 
            SHOP NOW      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://veracityselfcare.com/skincare/bioevolve-moisturizer"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Veracity-BioEvolve-Moisturizer.webp" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://veracityselfcare.com/skincare/bioevolve-moisturizer"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://veracityselfcare.com/skincare/bioevolve-moisturizer">Veracity, BioEvolve Moisturizer — $72.00</a></div><a href="https://veracityselfcare.com/skincare/bioevolve-moisturizer"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>If you’d rather a more natural primer, Dr. Lamb is a huge fan of this hypoallergenic moisturizer and recommends it to all of her patients with sensitive skin. “This non-sensitizing, non-irritating moisturizer is a great product to add to your makeup routine as it will serve as a flawless base,” she says. What’s more, it’s free from fragrance, silicones, sulfates, hormone disruptors, and is even safe to use during pregnancy and breastfeeding.</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros: </strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Designed with sensitive skin in mind 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Infused with nourishing ingredients 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Vegan and cruelty-free 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Pregnancy safe 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons: </strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Not technically makeup 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Expensive 
</li> 
                                                                <li>No SPF 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://veracityselfcare.com/skincare/bioevolve-moisturizer"> 
            Shop Now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
            </div> 
</div> 
<div> 
  <div> 
          <h2>Eyes </h2> 
     
     
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://thrivecausemetics.com/products/liquid-lash-extensions-mascara"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/thrive-mascara.jpeg" alt="thrive mascara"> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://thrivecausemetics.com/products/liquid-lash-extensions-mascara"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://thrivecausemetics.com/products/liquid-lash-extensions-mascara">Thrive Causemetics, Liquid Lash Extensions Mascara  — $25.00</a></div><a href="https://thrivecausemetics.com/products/liquid-lash-extensions-mascara"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>Despite being hypoallergenic, this mascara doesn’t skimp on length and volume. Powered by a trademarked flake-free tubing technology and Orchid Stem Cell Complex, Thrive Causemetics’ mascara lengthens each lash from root to tip and supports healthier-looking lashes while doing so. It’s been dermatologist recommended for sensitive skin (it’s one of Dr. Madfes’s favorites) and is gentle enough for those with sensitive eyes and contact lens wearers.</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Dermatologist + ophthalmologist tested 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Designed with sensitive eyes in mind 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Infused with nourishing ingredients 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Tubing technology adds extra length 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Not waterproof 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://thrivecausemetics.com/products/liquid-lash-extensions-mascara"> 
            Shop Now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://howl.me/cjGcTa3Bb7X"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Natasha-Deonona-Bronze-Eyeshadow-Palette-.webp" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://howl.me/cjGcTa3Bb7X"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://howl.me/cjGcTa3Bb7X">Natasha Deonona, Bronze Eyeshadow Palette  — $69.00</a></div><a href="https://howl.me/cjGcTa3Bb7X"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>Natasha Denona is known for her striking eyeshadows made with high-quality ingredients, and this palette is no different. Free of fragrance, gluten, preservatives, parabens, and other potentially irritating ingredients Dr. Alexiades says to look out for, this 15-shade hypoallergenic eyeshadow palette is safe for use on eyelids, which are a particularly vulnerable area. With a range of textures from sultry, cream-powder mattes to vibrant chromes and shimmers, this palette is ideal for creating a variety of looks, no matter your skin tone or eye color</p> 
<p> </p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros: </strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Designed with sensitive skin in mind 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Vegan and gluten-free 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Includes a wide range of shades 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Not ophthalmologist tested 
</li> 
                                                                <li>No nourishing ingredients 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Expensive 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://howl.me/cjGcTa3Bb7X"> 
            Shop Now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
            </div> 
</div> 
<div> 
  <div> 
          <h2>Lips </h2> 
     
     
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Honest-Beauty-Moisture-Paraben-Silicone/dp/B07NTS4RDR/?th=1"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/honest-beauty-lip-balm-.jpg" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Honest-Beauty-Moisture-Paraben-Silicone/dp/B07NTS4RDR/?th=1"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Honest-Beauty-Moisture-Paraben-Silicone/dp/B07NTS4RDR/?th=1">Honest Beauty, Tinted Lip Balm  — $9.00</a></div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Honest-Beauty-Moisture-Paraben-Silicone/dp/B07NTS4RDR/?th=1"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>Jessica Alba knows a thing or two about natural beauty. Aside from being a stunning actress and model, she’s also the brains behind Honest Beauty, a brand dedicated to creating sensitive skin-friendly makeup made from safe, naturally-derived ingredients. If you have sensitive lips, this creamy lip balm should be part of your makeup kit. It goes on smooth and silky, thanks to conditioning oils that lock in moisture while delivering long-lasting color in just a swipe or two.</p> 
<p><strong>Shades:</strong> 7</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros: </strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Dermatologist tested 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Designed with sensitive skin in mind 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Infused with nourishing ingredients 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Vegan and gluten-free 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Affordable 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>EWG-verified 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons: </strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>No SPF 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Honest-Beauty-Moisture-Paraben-Silicone/dp/B07NTS4RDR/?th=1"> 
            Shop Now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bareminerals-Mineralist-Hydra-Smoothing-Lipstick-Awareness/dp/B084R82Y86"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Bare-Minerals-Mineralist-Hydra-Smoothing-Lipstick.webp" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bareminerals-Mineralist-Hydra-Smoothing-Lipstick-Awareness/dp/B084R82Y86"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bareminerals-Mineralist-Hydra-Smoothing-Lipstick-Awareness/dp/B084R82Y86">Bare Minerals, Mineralist Hydra-Smoothing Lipstick — $22.00</a></div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bareminerals-Mineralist-Hydra-Smoothing-Lipstick-Awareness/dp/B084R82Y86"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>Lip skin is still skin, even if it looks a little different from the rest of your face. This clean lipstick from Bare Minerals is a nice choice for someone with highly-reactive skin. The creamy formula imparts a full-coverage wash of color across the lips and drenches them with smoothing hydration. With 25 gorgeous colors to choose from (ranging from dusty pinks and rosy reds to potent purples and gorgeous mauves), there’s something in the lineup for everyone.</p> 
<p><strong>Shades</strong>: 25</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros: </strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Designed with sensitive skin in mind 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Vegan and gluten-free 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Infused with nourishing ingredients 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Affordable 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Unclear if it’s been dermatologist tested 
</li> 
                                                                <li>No SPF 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bareminerals-Mineralist-Hydra-Smoothing-Lipstick-Awareness/dp/B084R82Y86"> 
            Shop Now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
            </div> 
</div>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 18:16:12 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Fitness</category>
<dc:creator>Caitlyn Martyn</dc:creator>
<source url="http://wellandgood.com/">Well+Good</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e7517c0077d</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>‘I’m a Lawyer-Turned-Hotelier—Here’s How My Passion for Culture, Travel, and Tradition Led Me to My True Calling’</title>
<link>https://www.wellandgood.com/roundtree-amagansett/</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>For Sylvia Wong, the founder of <a href="https://www.theroundtreehotels.com/">The Roundtree, Amagansett</a>, creating a welcoming home away from home for guests is her number one priority. Wong, who opened the idyllic 14-room boutique hotel located in the Hamptons, New York in June 2020, has drawn inspiration from her cultural background and experiences to guide what hospitality means in her business.</p> 
<p>Thanks to a fruitful career in law, Wong had the opportunity to travel throughout the globe over the span of a decade and was exposed to many different cultures and experiences along the way that helped her bring to life what The Roundtree is today. We had the chance to learn more about Wong’s lawyer-turned-hotelier background and how she’s woven her Chinese background into the hotel’s magic, from its culinary offerings to special events.</p> 
<img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/roundtree-amagansett-sylvia-wong.jpg" alt="roundtree amagansett sylvia wong" width="747" height="499">Photo: The Roundtree Amagansett 
<h2>How Wong has woven her background into the foundation of her business</h2> 
<p>Although you might be fooled otherwise—thanks to the impeccable hotel she operates today—Wong didn’t come from a background in hospitality, per se. “Becoming a hotelier is a complete departure from what most of my professional career has looked like. I studied law at New York University,” Wong says.</p> 
<p>To that end, Wong says that she learned a lot about how to run a <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/hotel-guest-etiquette-mistakes/">successful hospitality business</a> while traveling around the world. “After working at a law firm in New York City for several years, I joined a technology firm and was based in Asia for about 10 years. I was responsible for the legal affairs of its emerging markets business, so I spent a lot of time traveling in Asia, Latin America, Eastern Europe, and Africa. That was an incredible experience, professionally,” Wong says. “On a personal level, being able to live and work across the globe fits my interest perfectly. I have always enjoyed traveling.”</p> 
<p>What’s more, her passion and curiosity for cultures around the world is what inspired her core values in her business today. “Because of these travels, it’s helped to frame up the creation and experience that’s delivered at The Roundtree, from the design aesthetic down to the service,” Wong says. Since her passion for hospitality and design inspired the hotel, she notes that every last detail reflects her values and experiences. “The property’s ethos is 100 percent connected to my roots.”</p> 
<p>One such way was the hotel’s Lunar New Year celebrations, which featured culinary programs with Asian American restaurateurs and “carefully chosen design elements,” Wong says. “This past year, we excitedly added Lunar New Year celebrations within our first-ever culinary series that took place in the winter.” The celebrations included the Savor the Hamptons series, which brought a diverse group of chefs from New York City for weekend residencies for guests to experience exclusive food-focused programs.</p> 
<p>“For the Lunar New Year, we hosted a traditional experience at our Beach House. It spotlighted the holiday’s classic traditions, provided a dumpling-making opportunity for guests, let them sample a variety of different traditional foods, and enjoy traditional tea,” Wong says.</p> 
<img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/roundtree-amagansett-hotel.jpg" alt="roundtree amagansett hotel" width="798" height="533">Photo: The Roundtree Amagansett 
<h2>What’s in store at the hotel next?</h2> 
<p>Going into its third year of operation, Wong says the programs and innovative ways she can weave her cultural ties are still evolving. “As of right now, we are much in the planning process of our upcoming programming,” she says. While she’s in the development process, Wong hopes to recreate the success of the winter-timed Savor the Hamptons culinary series they hosted earlier this year. “Specifically, we’re excited to highlight female culinary leaders and hospitality innovators this year, and I’m looking forward to partnering with a diverse range of chefs. Every flavor, cuisine, and form of comfort food has a place at our table,” she says.</p> 
<blockquote><p>“Specifically, we’re excited to highlight female culinary leaders and hospitality innovators this year, and I’m looking forward to partnering with a diverse range of chefs. Every flavor, cuisine, and form of comfort food has a place at our table,”—Sylvia Wong, founder, The Roundtree, Amagansett</p></blockquote> 
<p>The core of her operation, however? Her guests, which is why Wong welcomes any and all feedback from those who stay at the hotel to enhance their experience further. “From the day The Roundtree opened its doors to welcome its first guests three years ago, we have been blessed to have received consistent feedback from our guests about the understated luxury and serenity of the property and the bespoke service they received. We are thrilled as we set out to create a beautiful place where our guests would feel like it is their second home,” Wong says.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 17:14:32 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Fitness</category>
<dc:creator>Maki Yazawa</dc:creator>
<source url="http://wellandgood.com/">Well+Good</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e7517cd64c9</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>13 Must-Have Swim Skirts for When You Want a Little More Coverage</title>
<link>https://www.wellandgood.com/best-swim-skirts/</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>If you’ve been on social media lately, you’ve likely noticed that yet another early aughts fashion trend has made a comeback. Joining the ranks of tube tops, low-rise denim, <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/universal-standard-karlee-cargo-pants/">cargo pants</a>, <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/tankinis/">tankinis</a>, and Y2K sunglasses, swim skirts have officially joined the conversation. (On TikTok alone, the term has amassed over <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/discover/swim-skirt">28.3 <em>million</em> views</a>.) Swim skirts are not only trendy, they’re super practical—especially for those days you forgot (or didn’t feel like) shaving or waxing your bikini area. Or maybe you just want to wear a pool-friendly sports skirt-like covering from pool to dinner. Whatever the reason (and there are so many), a good swim skirt is a summer must-have.</p> 
 
 
<h2>Best swim skirts, at a glance:</h2> 
<ul> 
<li><strong>Best overall:</strong> <a href="https://athleta.gap.com/browse/product.do?pid=468220042#pdp-page-content">Athleta, Tidal Swim Skirt</a>, $59</li> 
<li><strong>Best runner-up:</strong> <a href="https://spanx.com/products/pique-shaping-high-rise-swim-skort">Spanx, Pique Shaping High Rise Swim Skort</a>, $118</li> 
<li><strong>Best budget:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/GRAPENT-Womens-Shirring-Swimsuit-Bikini/dp/B0BNBJPVDX">Grapent, Women’s High Waist Tulip Hem Swim Skirt</a>, $25</li> 
<li><strong>Most stylish:</strong> <a href="https://www.victoriassecret.com/us/pink/swimwear-catalog/5000009191">Victoria’s Secret Pink, Shimmer Swim Mini Skirt</a>, $20</li> 
<li><strong>Best compression:</strong> <a href="https://www.landsend.com/products/womens-chlorine-resistant-tummy-control-adjustable-swim-skirt-swim-bottoms/id_353002">Lands’ End, Chlorine-Resistant Tummy Control Adjustable Swim Skirt</a>, $27-41</li> 
<li><strong>Best maxi skirt:</strong> <a href="https://www.sieswim.com/collections/bikini-bottoms/products/isabel-maxi-skirt-stardust-shimmer">SIE, Isabel Maxi Skirt</a>, $210</li> 
<li><strong>Best sarong:</strong> <a href="https://gap.igs4ds.net/c/2372336/383278/5555?subId1=STRUSY-&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Foldnavy.gap.com%2Fbrowse%2Fproduct.do%3Fpid%3D553787032%23pdp-page-content">Old Navy, High-Waisted Wrap-Front Sarong Swim Skirt</a>, $35</li> 
</ul> 
<div></div> 
<h2>What is a swim skirt?</h2> 
<p>Once upon a time, swim skirts solely referred to swim bottoms that featured a skirt silhouette. Nowadays, however, swim skirts can pertain to that, as well as to swimwear skirt sets (ie: coordinating skirts that pair perfectly over your bikini or one-piece).</p> 
<p>Generally speaking, they add more coverage to overall swim outfits. That said, they also provide the opportunity to thoughtfully style a full swim ensemble that works just as well for the beach as it does for beachside drinks thereafter.</p> 
<p>Of course, not all swim skirts are created equally. Where some are designed to actually swim in, others are purely for coverage’s sake (such as sarongs and pareos, for example).</p> 
<p>No matter your intent—to wear it in the water or as a coverup post-swim—there are plenty of swim skirts to choose from. Ahead, find 13 of our favorites.</p> 
<div></div> 
<h2>The best swim skirts</h2> 
<div> 
  <div> 
     
     
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://athleta.gap.com/browse/product.do?pid=468220042"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Athleta-Tidal-Swim-Skirt.webp" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://athleta.gap.com/browse/product.do?pid=468220042"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://athleta.gap.com/browse/product.do?pid=468220042">Athleta, Tidal Swim Skirt — $59.00</a></div><a href="https://athleta.gap.com/browse/product.do?pid=468220042"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>If you’re shopping for a swim skirt that you can <em>actually</em> swim in (and looks cute), the Athleta Tidal Swim Skirt is a classic option. Designed with an athletic appeal, the high-waisted silhouette features a built-in brief for optimal coverage. Swim, surf, fish, kayak—the nylon-lycra blend will stretch with you, allowing more movement and comfort (plus, the fabric is made with recycled materials, which makes us love it more—brownie points for sustainability).  Constructed from UPF 50+ fabric, it’s also sun-safe, protecting skin from the sun’s UV rays. The fit is more “exercise dress” than “sarong,” so expect a higher waist than other styles. Bonus: It has a zip pocket on the back of the waistband.</p> 
<p>Pair it with the matching <a href="https://athleta.gap.com/browse/product.do?pid=531217102&amp;rrec=true&amp;mlink=5050,12413545,atproduct1_rr_2&amp;clink=12413545#pdp-page-content">Square Neck Bikini Top</a> or <a href="https://athleta.gap.com/browse/product.do?pid=405827162&amp;rrec=true&amp;mlink=5050,12413545,atproduct1_rr_3&amp;clink=12413545#pdp-page-content">Maldives Bra Cup Bikini Top</a>.</p> 
<p><strong>Colors:</strong> 5<br> 
<strong>Sizes: </strong>XXS-XL</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>It has a built-in brief, so you can wear it during more high-impact water activities 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>UPF 50+ material for sun protection 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Classic, sporty fit and style 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Comes in a variety of different colors 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>It looks good on all body types 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>It has pockets 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>High quality 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>It may have too high of a waist for petites 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Some say it runs small—try ordering a size up (returns are free) 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://athleta.gap.com/browse/product.do?pid=468220042"> 
            SHOP NOW      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://skims.com/products/swim-ruched-mini-skirt-neon-green"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/skims-swim-ruched-skirt.webp" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://skims.com/products/swim-ruched-mini-skirt-neon-green"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://skims.com/products/swim-ruched-mini-skirt-neon-green">Skims, Swim Ruched Mini Skirt — $54.00</a></div><a href="https://skims.com/products/swim-ruched-mini-skirt-neon-green"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>Looking for a swim skirt that can be worn a couple ways? The Skims Swim Ruched Mini Skirt, which is designed to be worn over your swim bottoms of choice, has a double drawstring feature that lets you adjust the length to your liking. Since the fabric is made of (recycled) nylon and spandex, you can technically wear this in the water—but since it’s supposed to be worn over your actual bathing suit, it’s not ideal for any active swimming (since it’ll easily ride up). This is best for lounging or wading in the pool.</p> 
<p><strong>Colors:</strong> 7<br> 
<strong>Sizes available: </strong>XXS-4X</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Flattering on all body types 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Easily tailors to the length you want, thanks to the ruching detail 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Comes in a variety of colors 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons</strong>:</p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>If you’re looking for something with an actual bikini attached, this isn’t it 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://skims.com/products/swim-ruched-mini-skirt-neon-green"> 
            SHOP NOW      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.victoriassecret.com/us/pink/swimwear-catalog/5000009191"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Victorias-Secret-Pink-Shimmer-Swim-Mini-Skirt.jpeg" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.victoriassecret.com/us/pink/swimwear-catalog/5000009191"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.victoriassecret.com/us/pink/swimwear-catalog/5000009191">Victoria’s Secret Pink, Shimmer Swim Mini Skirt — $20.00</a></div><a href="https://www.victoriassecret.com/us/pink/swimwear-catalog/5000009191"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p><strong>Originally $30, on sale for $15-$20</strong></p> 
<p>Shimmer swimwear is one of 2023’s biggest swim trends, making this bodycon swim skirt a no-brainer, style-wise. This is another pick that goes over your bikini, so it’s better suited for lounging or wading. With that said, it’s a high-waist fit and is only a little bit shorter than most exercise skirts, so it offers some coverage. Its (recycled) polyamide and elastane material is totally suited for the water, and it’s nice and stretchy, so it’ll give you long-lasting comfort.</p> 
<p>To complete the ensemble, choose one of the Victoria’s Secret Pink Shimmer swimsuits, such as the <a href="https://www.victoriassecret.com/us/pink/swimwear-catalog/1121824800">Shimmer Push-Up Bikini Top</a> and <a href="https://www.victoriassecret.com/us/pink/swimwear-catalog/1121834700">Shimmer High Waist Cheeky Bikini Bottom</a>.</p> 
<p><strong>Colors: </strong>11<br> 
<strong>Sizes: </strong>XS-XXL</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Shoppers say sizing is “perfect” 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Affordable 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Comes in a variety of colors 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li><strong>Cons:</strong> 
</li> 
                                                                <li>It works better as a cover-up, so if you’re looking for something more functional, this may not be the best choice 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.victoriassecret.com/us/pink/swimwear-catalog/5000009191"> 
            SHOP NOW      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.amazon.com/GRAPENT-Womens-Shirring-Swimsuit-Bikini/dp/B0BNBJPVDX"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/GRAPENT-Womens-High-Waist-Tulip-Hem-Swim-Skirt.jpg" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/GRAPENT-Womens-Shirring-Swimsuit-Bikini/dp/B0BNBJPVDX"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/GRAPENT-Womens-Shirring-Swimsuit-Bikini/dp/B0BNBJPVDX">Grapent, Women's High Waist Tulip Hem Swim Skirt — $25.00</a></div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/GRAPENT-Womens-Shirring-Swimsuit-Bikini/dp/B0BNBJPVDX"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>Similar to the Athleta swim skirt, this fan-favorite Amazon find (it has over 6,700 reviews and a 4.4/5 rating from shoppers) has an athletic silhouette complete with a built-in brief. The tulip-hem swim skirt is stretchy and slightly compressive, offering a stylish <em>and</em> functional option. The outer material is a stretchy nylon-spandex blend, while the lining is mainly polyester with 5 percent spandex for a bit of stretch (so it doesn’t shift around, yet doesn’t completely feel like you’re wearing regular underpants). The elastic spring closure makes it easy to put on without help (score), and it’s sold in a bunch of solid colors and prints. Some shoppers say they’ve filled their swim drawers with the style entirely.</p> 
<p><strong>Colors:</strong> 40<br> 
<strong>Sizes:</strong> XS-3XL</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Great for all body types 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>A huge variety of colors and patterns 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Thick, sturdy material 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Built-in briefs 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Some colors and patterns are selling out quickly 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Shoppers say it’s not as compressive as they hoped 
</li> 
                                                                <li>It runs small for some—try ordered a couple sizes and return the one that doesn’t fit as well 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/GRAPENT-Womens-Shirring-Swimsuit-Bikini/dp/B0BNBJPVDX"> 
            SHOP NOW      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.ae.com/us/en/p/aerie/accessories-shoes/capes-sarongs/aerie-sarong-skirt/1729_7880_612"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/American-Eagle-Aerie-Sarong-Skirt.webp" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.ae.com/us/en/p/aerie/accessories-shoes/capes-sarongs/aerie-sarong-skirt/1729_7880_612"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.ae.com/us/en/p/aerie/accessories-shoes/capes-sarongs/aerie-sarong-skirt/1729_7880_612">American Eagle, Aerie Sarong Skirt — $26.00</a></div><a href="https://www.ae.com/us/en/p/aerie/accessories-shoes/capes-sarongs/aerie-sarong-skirt/1729_7880_612"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p><strong>Originally $35, on sale for $26</strong></p> 
<p>Prefer a swim skirt that can be tailored to your body shape? The Aerie Sarong Skirt has two ties on the side so you can choose to tie it tighter for a high-waisted approach or looser to accomplish the low-rise look. It’s meant to be worn over top of your bottoms of choice, so bikini bottoms do come separately, and it’s not attached to bottoms like an exercise skirt may be. Since this one has ties, we recommend low-impact activities or wearing this for lounging or wading. The soft nylon material is agreeably stretchy, and the two vibrant patterns make it fun and summery.</p> 
<p><strong>Colors:</strong> 2<br> 
<strong>Sizes:</strong> XS/S-L/XL</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Material is soft 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Ties are adjustable 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Affordable 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Material is a bit thin 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.ae.com/us/en/p/aerie/accessories-shoes/capes-sarongs/aerie-sarong-skirt/1729_7880_612"> 
            SHOP NOW      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.summersalt.com/products/the-ruched-swim-skirt-sea-urchin"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/summersalt-ruched-swim-skirt.png" alt="summersalt"> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.summersalt.com/products/the-ruched-swim-skirt-sea-urchin"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.summersalt.com/products/the-ruched-swim-skirt-sea-urchin">Summersalt, The Ruched Swim Skirt — $65.00</a></div><a href="https://www.summersalt.com/products/the-ruched-swim-skirt-sea-urchin"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>Designed to be worn over a swimsuit, the Summersalt Ruched Swim Skirt can transform any one piece into a lunch-ready ‘fit. The pull-on skirt features subtle ruching on the front left side for a bit of flare and a bit more coverage than other options on this list. Since it doesn’t have a liner, you do need to wear a bikini bottom underneath, and it’s not meant for any high-impact activities. While this skirt is a bit more expensive, we will say Summersalt swimwear is meant to last a long time—it takes a LOT for the material to pill or wear down, so consider it an investment (there’s a reason why the brand is so popular). Hack: Pair it with the matching <a href="https://www.summersalt.com/products/the-ruched-sidestroke-in-garden-party-in-rust">Summersalt Sidestroke</a> or <a href="https://www.summersalt.com/products/the-ruffle-backflip-in-garden-party-in-rust">Ruffle Backflip Swimsuit</a>, it will look like a chic mini dress.</p> 
<p><strong>Colors: </strong>6<strong><br> 
<strong>Sizes: </strong></strong>XXS-2X</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Great for all body types 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>High-quality, long-lasting 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Ruching detail is stylish (and flattering) 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Doesn’t have a liner, if that’s what you’re looking for 
</li> 
                                                                <li>On the more pricey side 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.summersalt.com/products/the-ruched-swim-skirt-sea-urchin"> 
            SHOP NOW      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://spanx.com/products/pique-shaping-high-rise-swim-skort"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/spanx-swim-skort.png" alt="spanx swim skort"> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://spanx.com/products/pique-shaping-high-rise-swim-skort"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://spanx.com/products/pique-shaping-high-rise-swim-skort">Spanx, Pique Shaping High Rise Swim Skort — $118.00</a></div><a href="https://spanx.com/products/pique-shaping-high-rise-swim-skort"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>This swim skort isn’t entirely a “skort”—it’s really a swim skirt with built-in briefs. But what makes it stand out is a list of features we absolutely love. First, the pique texture of the fabric gives it a high-quality look (it looks like an actual piece of clothing, versus swimwear), so you can do double-duty with it at the pool *and* at brunch. Second, it has hidden tie-down features that keep your skirt down in water (so you won’t have to keep patting down floating fabric all the time—genius). Like everything Spanx does, this gives you a little bit of compression and shaping, making you feel like the best version of yourself. Also? The high waist is super stylish.</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Built-in lining 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Hidden ties to keep skirt down while in water 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Super flattering on all body types 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>High-quality 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Expensive 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Not actually “shorts” 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://spanx.com/products/pique-shaping-high-rise-swim-skort"> 
            Shop Now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.solidandstriped.com/products/the-pareo-optic-swirl-clementine"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Solid-Striped-The-Mini-Wrap-Pareo-.webp" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.solidandstriped.com/products/the-pareo-optic-swirl-clementine"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.solidandstriped.com/products/the-pareo-optic-swirl-clementine"> Solid &amp; Striped, The Mini Wrap Pareo — $98.00</a></div><a href="https://www.solidandstriped.com/products/the-pareo-optic-swirl-clementine"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>If you prefer more of a beachy look, consider layering a pareo (aka, a sarong) over your swimsuit. The Solid &amp; Striped The Mini Wrap Pareo is a shorter sarong sold in a variety of fun prints and unique textiles, including reimagined eyelet options. We love Solid &amp; Striped (<a href="https://fashionista.com/2016/07/taylor-swift-solid-and-striped">and so does Taylor Swift</a>), mainly for their “of the moment” patterns and designs that make us feel like chic Instagram ads—but also because the quality of material is top-notch. However, this is definitely a fashion piece, not a functional swim piece. Wear it to the pool, but it’s not really designed to be submerged in water (it’s 100 percent polyester). Is it gorgeous? Yes. Will it make you look like a fashion influencer in your photos? Absolutely. Is it <em>practical</em>? Eh, not so much—but that’s okay sometimes.</p> 
<p><strong>Colors:</strong> 7<br> 
<strong>Sizes:</strong> OS</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros</strong>:</p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Gorgeous design 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Works for all body types 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>High-quality 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Is absolutely not meant to be worn in the water 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Expensive 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.solidandstriped.com/products/the-pareo-optic-swirl-clementine"> 
            SHOP NOW      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.landsend.com/products/womens-chlorine-resistant-tummy-control-adjustable-swim-skirt-swim-bottoms/id_353002"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Lands-End-Chlorine-Resistant-Tummy-Control-Adjustable-Swim-Skirt.jpeg" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.landsend.com/products/womens-chlorine-resistant-tummy-control-adjustable-swim-skirt-swim-bottoms/id_353002"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.landsend.com/products/womens-chlorine-resistant-tummy-control-adjustable-swim-skirt-swim-bottoms/id_353002">Lands’ End, Chlorine-Resistant Tummy Control Adjustable Swim Skirt, $27-41</a></div><a href="https://www.landsend.com/products/womens-chlorine-resistant-tummy-control-adjustable-swim-skirt-swim-bottoms/id_353002"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>Here we have another adjustable swim skirt, only this one can actually be worn in the water, thanks to the attached liner. Made with lycra Xtra Life spandex, this material is designed to last 10 times longer than your average spandex swimsuit, so the longevity on this piece is impressive (no pilling or wear and tear for a decade—and it resists damage from chlorine, sunscreen, and sweat). The mini skirt has ruching on each side, a contoured waistband, plus side ties to adjust the length and body-hugging nature of the piece, and it features a light tummy compression for a feel-good silhouette. Plus, it features UPF 50 for UV protection.</p> 
<p><strong>Colors:</strong> 8<br> 
<strong>Sizes:</strong> 4-26 (<a href="https://www.landsend.com/products/womens-plus-size-chlorine-resistant-tummy-control-adjustable-swim-skirt-swim-bottoms/id_353003">more size options here</a>)</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Comes with a built-in liner 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Fit is adjustable 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Made of super-sturdy material 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Features UPF protection 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Perfect coverage 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Runs a size small for some shoppers (size up) 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.landsend.com/products/womens-chlorine-resistant-tummy-control-adjustable-swim-skirt-swim-bottoms/id_353002"> 
            SHOP NOW      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.goodamerican.com/products/twist-mini-sarong-electric-lime002"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Good-American-Twist-Mini-Sarong.webp" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.goodamerican.com/products/twist-mini-sarong-electric-lime002"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.goodamerican.com/products/twist-mini-sarong-electric-lime002">Good American, Twist Mini Sarong — $55.00</a></div><a href="https://www.goodamerican.com/products/twist-mini-sarong-electric-lime002"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>Twisted details are on the rise in 2023, making the Good American Twist Mini Sarong especially stylish for spring and summer. The polyester and elastane swim skirt is meant to be layered over a swimsuit, so think of it as more of a water-friendly sarong or cover-up. Good American is known for its comfort as well as its size-inclusive offerings (and fun, bright colors), so you’ll love the buttery-soft fabric that covers you in all the right places.</p> 
<p><strong>Colors:</strong> 3<br> 
<strong>Sizes:</strong> XXS/S-4XL/5XL</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Size-inclusive options 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Bright colors 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Looks good on everyone 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Doesn’t come with a built-in liner 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.goodamerican.com/products/twist-mini-sarong-electric-lime002"> 
            SHOP NOW      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.sieswim.com/collections/bikini-bottoms/products/isabel-maxi-skirt-stardust-shimmer"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/SIE-Isabel-Maxi-Skirt.webp" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.sieswim.com/collections/bikini-bottoms/products/isabel-maxi-skirt-stardust-shimmer"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.sieswim.com/collections/bikini-bottoms/products/isabel-maxi-skirt-stardust-shimmer">SIE, Isabel Maxi Skirt — $210.00</a></div><a href="https://www.sieswim.com/collections/bikini-bottoms/products/isabel-maxi-skirt-stardust-shimmer"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>While most swim skirts are mini in length, here in 2023, maxi swim skirts exist, too (and they’re thriving!). We especially love the SIE Isabel Maxi Skirt, which shimmers and stretches for an eye-catching end look. It pairs beautifully with the coordinating <a href="https://www.sieswim.com/collections/bikini-tops/products/taylor-bikini-top-quartz-shimmer">SIE Taylor Bikini Top</a>, <a href="https://www.sieswim.com/collections/bikini-tops/products/stella-bikini-top-stardust-shimmer">Stella Bikini Top</a>, and <a href="https://www.sieswim.com/collections/bikini-tops/products/dani-bikini-top-stardust-shimmer">Dani Bikini Top</a>. While it’s meant to be worn over a bottom, thanks to its length, you likely wouldn’t flash anyone if you went without. Made with a nylon-spandex material, it’s water-safe, but not meant to be fully submerged (although you technically can). Size up for a more relaxed fit.</p> 
<p><strong>Colors: </strong>2<br> 
<strong>Sizes:</strong> XS-XL</p> 
<p>(Love the idea of a maxi skirt swim set but prefer bolder colors and prints? Be sure to check out <a href="https://farailondon.com/collections/newin/products/izumi-maxi-high-slit-skirt">Farai London’s Izumi Maxi High Slit Skirt</a> and <a href="https://farailondon.com/collections/new/products/aurora-coverup-skirt">Aurora Coverup Skirt</a>.)</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Provides a ton of coverage (great for chilly summer nights) 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Water-friendly 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Stylish 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Not meant for swimming 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Expensive 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.sieswim.com/collections/bikini-bottoms/products/isabel-maxi-skirt-stardust-shimmer"> 
            SHOP NOW      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.amazon.com/ALove-Drawstrings-Bathing-Skirted-Swimsuit/dp/B08MQJLMRN"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/ALove-Womens-High-Waisted-Split-Swim-Skirt.jpg" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/ALove-Drawstrings-Bathing-Skirted-Swimsuit/dp/B08MQJLMRN"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/ALove-Drawstrings-Bathing-Skirted-Swimsuit/dp/B08MQJLMRN">ALove Womens High Waisted Split Swim Skirt — $26.00</a></div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/ALove-Drawstrings-Bathing-Skirted-Swimsuit/dp/B08MQJLMRN"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>If you’re not quite sure how you feel about the swim skirt trend, you can’t go wrong with this popular split hem option sold on Amazon. It has a built-in bikini bottom so you can wear it from a dip in the ocean and out to drinks, all without having to go home and change. Made of a nylon-spandex blend, it’s meant to be worn in the water, and it provides the perfect amount of coverage. It’s also not super expensive, so you really don’t have to commit if you decide it’s not a summertime wardrobe keeper (but we like it because it’s so versatile!).</p> 
<p><strong>Colors:</strong> 14<br> 
<strong>Sizes:</strong> S-XL</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Features a built-in liner 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Easy to style 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Comfortable 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Has tons of color and pattern options 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Affordable 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Could be more size inclusive 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Shoppers say it runs small 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Not something that will last you years and years 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/ALove-Drawstrings-Bathing-Skirted-Swimsuit/dp/B08MQJLMRN"> 
            SHOP NOW      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://gap.igs4ds.net/c/2372336/383278/5555?subId1=STRUSY-&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Foldnavy.gap.com%2Fbrowse%2Fproduct.do%3Fpid%3D553787032%23pdp-page-content"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/old-navy-High-Waisted-Wrap-Front-Sarong-Swim-Skirt.webp" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://gap.igs4ds.net/c/2372336/383278/5555?subId1=STRUSY-&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Foldnavy.gap.com%2Fbrowse%2Fproduct.do%3Fpid%3D553787032%23pdp-page-content"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://gap.igs4ds.net/c/2372336/383278/5555?subId1=STRUSY-&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Foldnavy.gap.com%2Fbrowse%2Fproduct.do%3Fpid%3D553787032%23pdp-page-content">Old Navy, High-Waisted Wrap-Front Sarong Swim Skirt — $35.00</a></div><a href="https://gap.igs4ds.net/c/2372336/383278/5555?subId1=STRUSY-&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Foldnavy.gap.com%2Fbrowse%2Fproduct.do%3Fpid%3D553787032%23pdp-page-content"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>Unlike most tie-front sarongs, this skirt comes with an elastic waistband that stays put. Made of an athletic poly-spandex blend, this skirt is breathable, stretchy, and <em>feels</em> like a swimsuit. Which, because, it kind of is: It comes with a built-in liner, so you can swim in it without worry. Think of it as a 2-in-1 bathing suit bottom <em>and</em> sarong.</p> 
<p>Prefer a more beachy-boho ook? The <a href="https://gap.igs4ds.net/c/2372336/383278/5555?subId1=STRUSY-&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Foldnavy.gap.com%2Fbrowse%2Fproduct.do%3Fpid%3D553878022%26vid%3D1%26%26searchText%3Dcrochet%2520skirt%23pdp-page-content">crochet version of this skirt</a> is just as cute.</p> 
<p><strong>Colors: </strong>3</p> 
<p><strong>Sizes:</strong> XS-4X</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Flattering and fun flare skirt style 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Has built-in liner 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Sarong-style 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Provides great coverage (a little bit longer than most on this list) 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Looks great on all body types 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Sizing is accurate 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Shoppers looking for something tighter or higher-up may not like the style 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://gap.igs4ds.net/c/2372336/383278/5555?subId1=STRUSY-&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Foldnavy.gap.com%2Fbrowse%2Fproduct.do%3Fpid%3D553787032%23pdp-page-content"> 
            SHOP NOW      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
            </div> 
</div> 
<div></div> 
<h2>Do you swim in a swim skirt?</h2> 
<p>It depends. Since the label “swim skirt” is applied to actual swimwear as well as coordinating swim skirt cover ups, you’ll want to check the care instructions before diving into a chlorine-filled pool or the ultra-salty sea. (We’ll note in our roundup when you can treat a swim skirt like actual swim attire.)</p> 
<div></div> 
<h2>Do they have shorts underneath?</h2> 
<p>Some do. Generally, swim skirts that are actually intended for swimming—as opposed to just styling—feature built-in shorts or briefs underneath.</p> 
<div></div> 
<h2>Can you wear a swim skirt as a skirt?</h2> 
<p>Totally! That’s the beauty of a swim skirt—they’re designed to turn your swimwear into an outfit that you can wear from the beach to brunch (or to the bar). That said, some swim skirts are more appropriate than others, so you’ll want to consider where you plan to go after your swim when selecting which swim skirt to wear. After all, a sheer, high-slit sarong-style swim skirt may not be the best choice for a venue with family and/or kids abound.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 16:12:52 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Fitness</category>
<dc:creator>Rebecca Norris</dc:creator>
<source url="http://wellandgood.com/">Well+Good</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e7517cb343f</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>For Me, Gentle Parenting Is a Worthwhile But Challenging Endeavor—Here’s What Parents Should Know Before Trying It</title>
<link>https://www.wellandgood.com/what-is-gentle-parenting/</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/GettyImages-what-is-gentle-parenting.jpeg" alt="GettyImages-what-is-gentle-parenting.jpe"></p><p>Just this morning, as part of my daily routine with my 6-year-old, I said the following phrases, each one slightly more irate than the last: “I understand how you feel—waking up <em>can</em> be hard.” “Don’t you want to eat a breakfast that will give you energy?” “I know you can put your shoes on all by yourself.” “Don’t you want to go to school today?” “You need to be a better listener.” “Hurry up, you’re making us late!”</p>  
<p>To an average observer, this was a typical, nothing-to-see-here encounter <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/parent-adolescent-bonding/">between a mother and her child</a>. To me, however, it was yet another emotionally exhausting, possibly failed attempt at being a “gentle parent.” You know: the one who prioritizes the acknowledgement of a child’s feelings over the correction of their behavior. A parent who doesn’t bark orders, and doesn’t offer rewards or punishments—no bribes of ice cream, no two-minute time-outs. A parent who sets boundaries using primarily natural consequences (i.e. what would happen without parental interference), who doesn’t engage in power struggles, and who most certainly does not yell. This approach is the gold standard of gentle parenting.</p>  
<p>How did I get here? And why had I set such a seemingly unattainable standard for myself?</p>  
<blockquote><p>“Many are realizing that their emotions as children were never validated, and their opinions were rarely considered. So they are swayed back to movements that really prioritize the parent-child relationship.” —Erin Avirett, PhD, child psychologist</p></blockquote>  
<p>For starters, my determination in ascribing to this “gentle” approach is in part thanks to my desire to raise children who will grow up <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5330336/">to be respectful, resilient, capable</a> members of society (as promised by evangelists of this parenting style). But according to <a href="http://avirettpsychological.com/meet-the-team/">Erin Avirett, PhD</a>, and <a href="https://dfwchild.com/directory/jordana-mortimer-phd-lp-lssp/">Jordana Mortimer, PhD</a>, child psychologists and founders of parenting community <a href="https://www.mindandchild.com/">Mind &amp; Child</a>, it’s also because of generational shifts in child-rearing and recent research that shows the importance of parental emotional regulation.</p>  
<p>“Modern parents, raised in the ‘80s and ‘90s, feel the draw towards a more balanced parenting style,” says Dr. Avirett. “Many are realizing that their emotions as children were never validated, and their opinions were rarely considered. So they are swayed back to movements that really prioritize the parent-child relationship.”</p>  
<p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/shannon-kroll-5983181a4">Shannon Kroll, MEd</a>, a child behavior specialist and mom of three, echoes this sentiment: “We are the generation of pattern breakers. Most of my clients are moms who are people-pleasers, they’re perfectionists, and they’ve spent their lives trying to unlearn those tendencies so they don’t pass them down to their children. Our own lived experience causes us to want to do it differently for our kids.”</p>  
<p>The way we seem to be doing it, if the “momfluencers” across social media are any indication, is by proselytizing this gentle parenting movement.</p>  
<p>Unlike well-established parenting styles, like the laissez-faire permissive parenting (where parents don’t <a href="https://parentingscience.com/permissive-parenting/">impose limits or boundaries on their kids</a>) on one end or strict authoritarian parenting (which <a href="https://www.canr.msu.edu/news/authoritarian_parenting_style">emphasizes children’s obedience and rule following</a>) on the other, gentle parenting falls somewhere in the middle.</p>  
<p>“Much of the early research on parenting has called this approach ‘authoritative parenting,’” says Dr. Mortimer. In fact, decades of studies show that <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC8391119/">effective parents are emotionally available</a>, actively teach and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4839741/">reinforce positive behaviors</a>, and hold firm boundaries that employ consistent and <a href="https://melissainstitute.org/positive-parenting-using-natural-and-logical-consequences/">logical consequences</a> as needed.</p>  
<p>This parenting style has also been linked to positive outcomes for kids, including <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC8967044/">improved academic achievement</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK568743/">improved self-regulation</a> (in which they’re able to manage one’s negative emotions in a healthy way), and higher self-esteem and confidence.</p>  
<h2>What sets gentle parenting apart</h2>  
<p>Dr. Mortimer, Dr. Avirett, and Kroll all acknowledge subtle delineations between gentle and authoritative parenting—namely, the former’s overt omission of punishments.</p>  
<p>Kroll notes that those specializing in gentle parenting “do not enforce positive punishments, like taking random things away, time-outs, or shame-based responses.” Instead, gentle parents strive to maintain boundaries and address behavior through connection and conversation, and they tend to teach through the use of natural consequences. For example, if a child refuses to wear a jacket on a rainy day, a gentle parent might let them go outside without it and learn for themselves just how unpleasant it is to get cold and wet. (Exceptions are made for times when a child is about to do something unsafe or life-threatening, like running out into the street or touching a hot stove.)</p>  
<p>Authoritative parents, meanwhile, believe imposing certain consequences work as long as they aren’t arbitrary. Dr. Mortimer believes that if parents can “use time-outs calmly and consistently,” they can be effective, <a href="https://medicine.iu.edu/blogs/pediatrics/child-development-the-time-out-controversy-effective-or-harmful">research-backed</a> tools to address behavior, whereas it doesn’t make sense to limit screen time when your child hits their sibling or withhold dessert because they misbehaved at school.</p>  
<p>Another point of difference? Because gentle parenting methods have not been formally studied, Dr. Mortimer adds that “there is not much research on their individual effectiveness yet.”</p>  
<h2>The harsh realities of gentle parenting</h2>  
<p>Gentle parenting is certainly a worthwhile endeavor when the goal is to raise well-adjusted children. But—when compared to previous generations, in which parents were more often either hands-off or ruled with an iron fist—this method is also just so much work. Spending 15 minutes helping your toddler come down from a tantrum (without losing your own cool), for example, requires far more emotional energy than just sending them for a time-out in their room to cry it out solo. Multiply that by the amount of times in a day that a toddler will inevitably melt down, and you can get a sense of how much effort this approach takes.</p>  
<p>“Parenting this way takes more time because you are having to be responsive to individual situations,” says Kroll, who practices this style herself. “Not only does it require a deep pool of energy and patience, two things most parents don’t have an endless reserve of, but it’s also new territory for most of them. They’re trying to give something to their kids that they’re not necessarily used to giving to themselves.”</p>  
<blockquote><p>“We’re all going to lose our cool when our kid is screaming in our face. But it’s in those moments of perceived failure when [gentle] parenting actually works best.” —Shannon Kroll, MEd, child behavior specialist</p></blockquote>  
<p>And that contributes to why often, parents may feel like they’re failing at it. “It’s important to remember that there is nuance across families, cultures, and income levels,” says Dr. Mortimer, who notes that parents with access to therapy, support systems, and the extra time to devote to reading about parenting are certainly at an advantage when it comes to practicing this method. Even with that privilege, however, gentle parenting can feel impossible.</p>  
<p>“It’s an inevitability that we’re going to fall off the wagon,” says Kroll. “We’re all going to lose our cool when our kid is screaming in our face. But it’s in those moments of perceived failure when empathic parenting actually works best.”</p>  
<p>I wish I’d realized that sooner. Instead of reading up on how to be the <em>perfect</em> gentle parent, I wish I’d asked the harder questions about how to realistically implement this approach into my family’s life. So I tapped the experts to better understand what parents should know before beginning their own gentle parenting journey.</p>  
<h2>What to know before considering gentle parenting</h2>  
<h3>1. Accept your lack of control</h3>  
<p>Fact: Parents can’t control their children. Dr. Avirett has found most parents have the hardest time accepting this. “No matter how hard you try, you cannot force a toddler to swallow a piece of broccoli,” she says. “But we <em>can</em> control ourselves. We can control how we relate to our children, how we model positive behaviors for them, and how we handle really hard moments.”</p>  
<h3>2. Stop thinking you aren’t supposed to mess up</h3>  
<p>Many people worry that gentle parenting puts all the focus on the child to the detriment of the parent’s mental health and well-being, but Kroll maintains it’s a practice meant to serve everyone. “Ask yourself, ‘how can I have compassion for my child <em>and</em> myself? How can I have boundaries that feel good for my child <em>and </em>for me?’”</p>  
<p>Kroll adds: “For parents under a lot of stress, this approach frees everyone up. It’s recognizing that my kids are going to mess up—that’s part of being a kid. But I’m also going to mess up, because that’s part of being a human.”</p>  
<h3>3. Making mistakes is actually a good thing</h3>  
<p>If you lose your temper, it can feel like you’re backsliding in your gentle parenting efforts, but Kroll believes the opposite is true. “If anything, you’re gaining ground because when you come back together, apologize, and “repair,” you’re now teaching them what a compassionate, loving apology looks like and how to respond when they find themselves in a similar situation—rather than brushing it under the rug and pretending like it didn’t happen, which is invalidating for your child and yourself.”</p>  
<h3>4. Front-load your parenting time</h3>  
<p>One of the common concerns parents have with gentle parenting methods is the perception that the children lack discipline. Can you really raise a well-developed child without ever sending them to their room or taking away their iPad? It is possible, Dr. Mortimer says. In fact, methods like gentle parenting are based on the premise that you don’t need disciplinary measures if you <a href="https://ora.ox.ac.uk/objects/uuid:7c3ad0a2-b215-4d45-9509-4ad724cd77c6/download_file?file_format=application%2Fpdf&amp;safe_filename=2019%2BLeijten%2Bet%2Bal_accepted_JAACAP_what%2Bto%2Bteach%2Bparents%2Bto%2Breduce%2Bdisruptive%2Bchild%2Bbehavior.pdf&amp;type_of_work=Journal+article">front-load the bulk of your parenting time</a> in non-difficult moments.</p>  
<p>What does this “front-loading” mean, exactly? Basically, the difficult work you put in is not in doling out consequences for bad behavior. Instead, it’s pre-emptive. You put in the effort during peaceful times by offering choices and affirming boundaries up front. “You let your child choose their clothes the night before,” says Dr. Mortimer. “You offer them a choice of red shirt or green shirt. You let them choose if they want to get dressed before or after they brush their teeth. This initial investment builds your relationship with your child and proactively teaches them skills when there is <em>not</em> a problem, and it leads you to spend less time dealing with meltdowns and misbehaviors over your child not wanting to get dressed.”</p>  
<h3>5. Being gentle doesn’t mean being a pushover</h3>  
<p>“If we mistake gentle parenting for only being that zen side, then we allow our kids to act out—to scream and swear and call us names and hit us—and nothing happens,” says Kroll. “We need to teach them that all feelings are okay, but all behaviors are not.”</p>  
<p>This is where repeated connecting, enforcing boundaries, and natural consequences come in. “Parents need to accept that behavior doesn’t change immediately,” says Kroll, who outlined a three-step process she recommends: “We have to connect first. We have to approach the situation with compassion: ‘Hey, I saw that you got mad that your sister took your toy. It’s okay to feel mad.’ Then we set or reaffirm the boundary. ‘It’s not okay to hit her.’ And then, we must teach. ‘What can we do instead of hitting?’ Remember that it’s going to take time for this behavior to change. We’ll have to keep having that conversation over and over and over. But of course, if they are going to do something that makes anyone unsafe, we stop it. We take away the toy before they throw it or restrain them if they are going to hit.”</p>  
<p>This distinction has long-term effects, she says: “Kids in high school need to know that they don’t have to allow people to treat them any way, and they need to have had models of what it looks like to stand up for yourself and say, ‘It’s not okay to yell at me. It’s not okay to call me names. It’s okay to be angry, but it’s not okay to hurt me.’”</p>  
<h3>6. There is no single way to parent</h3>  
<p>There is no one formula or script to follow, even though it seems that way on social media. “If saying: ‘I see you are very sad. Let’s take a few minutes to collect our thoughts, take some deep breaths, and repeat this positive affirmation’ is not natural for you, don’t say it,” says Dr. Avirett. “Maybe you’re the parent who says: ‘I see you are sad, but we have got to go. Let’s talk about it on the way to the bus stop.’ Or, maybe you are the parent who quietly gives your child a hug, kiss on the forehead, and slips their favorite snack into their lunch box.”</p>  
<p>None of this expert advice changes how hard gentle parenting can be. In truth, it shines a spotlight on its inherent difficulties. What it does offer, at least for me and all the other parents nervously committed to a gentler way of raising children, is the reminder that we are human.</p>  
<p>We are not perfect. We will make mistakes. It’s the same lesson that we are committed to teaching our children. We just need to learn it ourselves, too.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 15:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Fitness</category>
<dc:creator>Kate Schweitzer</dc:creator>
<source url="http://wellandgood.com/">Well+Good</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e7517b15837</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>We Tested the Highest Rated Espresso Machines on the Market—These Are the 7 Best Worth Investing In</title>
<link>https://www.wellandgood.com/best-espresso-machines-reviews/</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Going without your morning shot of espresso is tough, but even harder than that? Forking up the bills every single day to expense your <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/tips-for-better-coffee/">coffee habit</a>—which is probably why you’re here researching for the best espresso machines. If you’re heading to <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/best-hot-drinks-starbucks/">Starbucks</a> for your double shot of espresso one too many times a week and are putting a dent in your checking account, consider making espresso at home; it can save you some cash, while controlling the quality of your espresso from the comfort of your own home (now <em>that’s</em> something we can sip to).</p> 
<p>One of the best ways to mimic cafe-quality espresso is by using a high-quality espresso machine. Sure, it may require some legwork and be costly at first, but if you’re drinking espresso daily, it’s totally worth the time and investment. Not sure where to start? Lucky for you, we tested the most popular espresso machine brands: These are the ones that make the best espresso, are easiest to use, and are completely worth the investment.</p> 
 
 
<h2>Best espresso machines, at a glance</h2> 
<ul> 
<li><strong>Best overall:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Breville-Express%C2%AE-Espresso-Stainless-BES876BSS/dp/B0BBYNPV33">Breville, Express Impress</a>, $720</li> 
<li><strong>Best budget:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nespresso-DeLonghi-ENV120WAE-Espresso-Aeroccino/dp/B084GYKJ58?th=1">Nepresso, Vertuo Next</a>, $216</li> 
<li><strong>Best low-maintenance:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Philips-Automatic-Espresso-EP3246-74/dp/B091MPHQ9M?">Philips, 3200 Automatic Espresso Machine</a>, $799</li> 
<li><strong>Most stylish:</strong> <a href="https://www.williams-sonoma.com/products/smeg-espresso-machine/?catalogId=79&amp;sku=528443&amp;cm_ven=PLA&amp;cm_cat">Smeg, Espresso Machine</a>, $530</li> 
<li><strong>Best for latte art:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/DeLonghi-EC9155MB-Specialista-Espresso-Machine/dp/B099YT9MYG">Delonghi, La Specialista Arte Espresso Machine</a>, $500</li> 
<li><strong>Best combination:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mr-Coffee-2168819-Coffeehouse-Cappuccino/dp/B09R5ZP81W/?th=1">Mr. Coffee, One Touch Espresso, Cappuccino, and Latte Maker</a>, $350</li> 
<li><strong>Best for pro baristas:</strong> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Breville-Barista-Pro-Automatic-Integrated/dp/B08133HX34">Breville, Barista Pro</a>, $650</li> 
</ul> 
<div></div> 
<h2>What to look for in an espresso machine</h2> 
<h3>Type of machine</h3> 
<p>The first thing to note is that there are different types of espresso machines: fully-automatic, semi-automatic, and manual. As the name implies, fully-automatic machines are like planes on auto-pilot; it grinds your coffee, packs the grounds, and brews espresso with just a click of a button. On the other hand, semi-automatic models will require some leg work, such as filling a portafilter, aka a holder for ground espresso, and tamping your grounds down. Both of these options are great if you’re new to at-home brewing.</p> 
<p>If you’re an espresso aficionado, though, you might appreciate a manual espresso machine—which embraces a more hands-on brewing experience. They don’t have all the bells and whistles of fully- and semi-automatic machines. Things like temperature and automated pressure sensors don’t exist on manual mode. For this article, we tested automatic and semi-automatic machines.</p> 
<h3>Material and versatility</h3> 
<p>Once you’ve picked the type of machine you’re going to use, <a href="https://roastingplant.com/pages/about-us">Genevieve Kappler</a>, director of coffee and brewing and roasting technologist at Roasting Plant Coffee, recommends looking at the material. For example, stainless steel is “easy to clean and maintain,” Kappler tells us. You also might just like the way it looks.</p> 
<p>While some machines stick strictly to espresso, there are others that brew up lattes, cappuccinos, as well as Americanos. Versatility matters, so if you envision yourself whipping up something more than just shots, Kapper recommends going with a versatile machine that can do it all.</p> 
<h3>Space and water storage</h3> 
<p>“The amount of counter space you have and how often you plan to make espresso will help determine the size of the tank and boiler,” says Kappler. “I suggest at least 1.5 liters or more, or you’ll end up having to refill all the time!”</p> 
<div></div> 
<h2>What makes a good or tasty espresso</h2> 
<p>It’s all in the beans! The fresher, the better. To tell if your beans are good, “look for the crema when brewing espresso or bloom of foam as a visual indicator; crema is an indicator of freshness,” she says. “Not having the crema can be a sign the espresso beans are now stale.” Womp, I know. Once you have ’em, Kappler suggests brewing your beans within seven to ten days.”People don’t typically typically think of coffee beans as a food that can go bad, but coffee drinkers should treat their coffee beans like fresh fruit and vegetables or baked goods,” Kappler explains.</p> 
<p>The final verdict will come down to you. Delicious espresso depends on how you like the bean’s bitterness, acidity, and aromatics, says <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/maciej-kasperowicz/">Maciej Kasperowicz</a>, director of Coffee at Trade based in Brooklyn.</p> 
<p>One things for certain: the Well+Good team loves their coffee, so we put seven espresso machines to the test. Ahead, you’ll find machines made espresso-ly for you.</p> 
<div></div> 
<div> 
  <div> 
          <h2>Best overall</h2> 
     
     
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Breville-Express%C2%AE-Espresso-Stainless-BES876BSS/dp/B0BBYNPV33"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/WG_Commerce_Best-Espresso-Machines-InsetsBreville-Impress-.jpg" alt="best espresso machines"> 
                </a> 
                Photo: W+G Creative 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Breville-Express%C2%AE-Espresso-Stainless-BES876BSS/dp/B0BBYNPV33"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Breville-Express%C2%AE-Espresso-Stainless-BES876BSS/dp/B0BBYNPV33">Breville, Express Impress — $720.00</a></div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Breville-Express%C2%AE-Espresso-Stainless-BES876BSS/dp/B0BBYNPV33"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>“<span style="font-weight:400;">The Breville Barista Express Impress is probably as close to a professional espresso machine as you can get—without having to deal with a professional espresso machine. It’s nice and compact (not as small as</span><a href="https://www.breville.com/us/en/products/espresso/bes500.html"><span style="font-weight:400;"> the Bambino Plus</span></a><span style="font-weight:400;">, though, which I used to own and loved), and super easy to use. I’m an incredibly tired, lazy person (who is really not technical at all) in the morning, but making myself a latte using the Express Impress only takes a few minutes. </span></p> 
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">To use, you simply slide in the portafilter, press on the “Dose” button (you can hold it so that it automatically fills it with ground espresso, or manually choose the amount you want). Then, you press down on the handle on the side and its assistant tamping feature will press down on the espresso, packing it in. Next, attach it to the part of the machine that creates the espresso (choose between single or double shot). And then steam your milk if you want with the steam wand! I had to brush up on my foaming skills (I was a barista in college for a bit, so it wasn’t too bad—but it’s not hard to learn using YouTube!), but the wand was incredibly simple to use. You can also just leave it in and make steamed milk.</span></p> 
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">The results are a perfectly hot espresso drink. I haven’t bought a latte from a coffee shop since I’ve owned the Impress! </span></p> 
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">Cleaning the machine is easy—a little sign will automatically pop up telling you it’s time to dump the extra liquid (leftover espresso water and milk), which I’ll do and quickly rinse. And every six months or so (it depends how often you use it—I use mine multiple times a day) you’ll have to descale the whole machine, which is a bit of a process, but it’s simple enough—you just use the descaling powder the Impress comes with, and run it through the whole thing using the water tank so it gets rid of build up. You’ll also want to soak your portafilter in a descaling solution once or twice a year, since if you’re an avid espresso drinker, they can potentially get clogged after a while.” – Gina Vaynshteyn, editorial commerce director</span></p> 
<p><strong>Type:</strong> Semi-automatic</p> 
<p><b>Features:</b></p> 
<ul> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Built-in coffee bean grinder</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">“Intelligent” dosing</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">25 grind settings</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Thermocoil heating system</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Manual steam wand</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Preset single or double shot</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Ability to make hot water</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Adjustable brew temps</span><span style="font-weight:400;"><br> 
</span></li> 
</ul> 
<p><b>Accessories included:</b></p> 
<ul> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Portafilter</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Milk jug for steaming milk</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">A precision razor </span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Cleaning tablets</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">A steam wand cleaning tool and a cleaning brush</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Descale powder</span></li> 
</ul> 
<p><b>Warranty: </b><span style="font-weight:400;">2 years</span></p> 
<p><b>Dimensions</b><span style="font-weight:400;">: </span><span style="font-weight:400;">12.9″ x 14.9″ x 16.1″</span></p> 
<p><span style="font-weight:400;"> </span></p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Easy to use 
  
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Creates professional-quality espresso 
  
</li> 
                                                                        <li>So! Many! Features! 
  
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Durable 
  
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Simple to clean 
  
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Makes a latte in minutes 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Not automatic like a Nespresso 
  
</li> 
                                                                <li>Requires whole beans (which can be pricey) 
  
</li> 
                                                                <li>Expensive 
  
</li> 
                                                                <li>Requires some maintenance 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Breville-Express%C2%AE-Espresso-Stainless-BES876BSS/dp/B0BBYNPV33"> 
            Shop Now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
            </div> 
</div> 
<div></div> 
<div> 
  <div> 
          <h2>Best budget</h2> 
     
     
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nespresso-DeLonghi-ENV120WAE-Espresso-Aeroccino/dp/B084GYKJ58?th=1"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/WG_Commerce_Best-Espresso-Machines-InsetsNepresso-Virtuo-Next-.jpg" alt="best espresso machines"> 
                </a> 
                Photo: W+G Creative 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nespresso-DeLonghi-ENV120WAE-Espresso-Aeroccino/dp/B084GYKJ58?th=1"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nespresso-DeLonghi-ENV120WAE-Espresso-Aeroccino/dp/B084GYKJ58?th=1">Nepresso, Vertuo Next — $216.00</a></div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nespresso-DeLonghi-ENV120WAE-Espresso-Aeroccino/dp/B084GYKJ58?th=1"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>“As you know, espresso machines aren’t cheap, but this no-frills device brews espresso, double espresso, and coffee with just a click of a button and for under $250, it’s a price you can’t beat. For a jolt of caffeine, I load a Nepresso pod into the machine, put my cup on the adjustable cup holder, and watch it brew me a delicious cup of Joe or a powerful kick of espresso within 30 seconds. The end result? Jittery and chatty Kayla…that’s how you know the caffeine works.</p> 
<p>Unlike other espresso machines on this list, this one has no extra bells and whistles. However, for the price, it makes sense that it doesn’t have all of the extra features like a milk frother, tamper, or portafilter. I do appreciate the pod self-emptying feature because once the pod door is opened, it self-empties and ejects the capsule into a removable container—which holds up to 10 capsules. So, clean up is easy as pie!</p> 
<p>What’s great about the machine is that it’s compatible with the Nepresso app, where you can order more pods or brew with just a touch of your phone. Unfortunately, my machine wasn’t connecting to the app, so I could not use this feature.</p> 
<p>All in all, if a simple espresso machine is what you seek, I’d recommend Nepresso’s Vertuo Next. It’s easy to use, clean, and delivers shots wickedly fast.” – Kayla Hui, commerce writer</p> 
<p><strong>Type:</strong> Automatic</p> 
<p><b>Features:</b></p> 
<ul> 
<li>25-second brew time</li> 
<li>Removable water tank</li> 
<li>Used capsule container</li> 
<li>Self-emptying feature</li> 
<li>Adjustable cup holder</li> 
</ul> 
<p><b>Accessories included: </b>none</p> 
<p><b>Warranty: </b>1<span style="font-weight:400;"> year</span></p> 
<p><b>Dimensions</b><span style="font-weight:400;">: </span><span style="font-weight:400;">5.5″ x 16.8″ x 12.4″</span></p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>No-frills design 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>More affordable compared to other machines on the list 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Makes quality espresso 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Features a pod waste bin 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Sturdy design 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Easy to use and clean 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Must purchase special Nepresso pods 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Water tank is relatively small (1.09L) 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Closing lid may be difficult for some 
</li> 
                                                                <li>App connectivity issues 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nespresso-DeLonghi-ENV120WAE-Espresso-Aeroccino/dp/B084GYKJ58?th=1"> 
            Shop Now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
            </div> 
</div> 
<div></div> 
<div> 
  <div> 
          <h2>Best low-maintenance </h2> 
     
     
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Philips-Automatic-Espresso-EP3246-74/dp/B091MPHQ9M?"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/WG_Commerce_Best-Espresso-Machines-InsetsPhilips-3200.jpg" alt="best espresso machines"> 
                </a> 
                Photo: W+G Creative 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Philips-Automatic-Espresso-EP3246-74/dp/B091MPHQ9M?"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Philips-Automatic-Espresso-EP3246-74/dp/B091MPHQ9M?">Philips, 3200 Automatic Espresso Machine  — $799.00</a></div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Philips-Automatic-Espresso-EP3246-74/dp/B091MPHQ9M?"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p><span style="font-weight:400;">“I have been hesitant to bring a high-tech espresso machine into my home because I have a love/hate relationship with anything that claims to be ‘smart’ or ‘automatic.’ That’s usually code for ‘needing fixing all the time,’ and who has the time for that? I’m eating my words, though, because the Philips 3200 Automatic Espresso Machine LatteGo is *actually* low maintenance and reliable. And for especially being a box that spits out ready-made, coffee shop-level espresso drinks after pressing a couple buttons, that’s really dang impressive.</span></p> 
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">Set up is simple—the hardest part is installing the included water filter (included) into the tank. Once installed though, making a cafe-worthy cup of coffee is easy peasy. You can use either whole beans or ground coffee; for whole beans, you just pour your beans into the hopper on top, select which beverage you want to make (either single or double servings, depending on the serving), along with the aroma setting and cup size, and press “start.” </span></p> 
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">More convenient is the LatteGo system, which is a total game-changer for making lattes, macchiatos, and other milky drinks. There are no tubes or steam nozzles to hassle with; all you do is fill up the LatteGo cup with milk—which sits on the outside of the machine—select your frothy drink, and press “start.” B</span><span style="font-weight:400;">y using a “cyclonic frothing technology,” the LatteGo releases a stream of microbubbles to create a creamy, decadent foam directly in your cup or mug. When you’re done, just unclip the LatteGo cup and throw it in the dishwasher—there’s no extra cleaning required. It’s truly seamless and takes about two minutes total to make professional quality drinks in the comfort of your own home. </span></p> 
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">Since using my Philips 3200 series, I have noted it’s easier to use it with whole beans than pre-ground coffee. If you’re using grounds, you can only make one cup at a time, and the process requires a few extra steps than if you just stick with whole beans. Additionally, the water tank is smaller than I’d like it to be, and by the time my boyfriend and I are done making our 2-3 cups in the morning, we often have to refill it for the other to use. </span></p> 
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">These minor downsides aside, it’s convinced me that an automatic coffee machine is the investment every caffeine lover should make. If said caffeine lovers want quality coffee or lattes in the press of a button, the Philips 3200 LatteGo has got you covered.” – Francesca Krempa, associate commerce editor</span></p> 
<p><strong>Type:</strong> Automatic</p> 
<p><b>Features:</b></p> 
<ul> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Built-in coffee bean grinder </span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">5 beverage settings (espresso, coffee, cold brew, latte, americano) </span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">12 grind settings</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">3 aroma settings </span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Automatic LatteGo milk froth system </span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Preset single or double shot</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Ability to make hot water</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Adjustable brew temps</span></li> 
</ul> 
<p><b>Accessories included:</b></p> 
<ul> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Measuring scoop</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Water hardness test strip</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">AquaClean filter</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">LatteGo storage lid</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Grease tube</span></li> 
</ul> 
<p><b>Warranty: </b><span style="font-weight:400;">2 years</span></p> 
<p><b>Dimensions: </b><span style="font-weight:400;">9.7”x14.6”x17”</span></p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Easy to set up and use 
  
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Completely automatic  
  
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Compatible with whole and ground beans 
  
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Makes professional-quality espresso 
  
</li> 
                                                                        <li>LatteGo is simple and fast 
  
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Easy to clean 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Water tank is relatively small (1.8L)  
</li> 
                                                                <li>Expensive 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Switching from whole bean to ground coffee can be inconsistent  
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Philips-Automatic-Espresso-EP3246-74/dp/B091MPHQ9M?"> 
            Shop Now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
            </div> 
</div> 
<div></div> 
<div> 
  <div> 
          <h2>Most stylist</h2> 
     
     
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.williams-sonoma.com/products/smeg-espresso-machine/?catalogId=79&amp;sku=528443&amp;cm_ven=PLA&amp;cm_cat"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/WG_Commerce_Best-Espresso-Machines-InsetsSmeg-Espresso-Machine-.jpg" alt="best espresso machines"> 
                </a> 
                Photo: W+G Creative 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.williams-sonoma.com/products/smeg-espresso-machine/?catalogId=79&amp;sku=528443&amp;cm_ven=PLA&amp;cm_cat"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.williams-sonoma.com/products/smeg-espresso-machine/?catalogId=79&amp;sku=528443&amp;cm_ven=PLA&amp;cm_cat">Smeg, Espresso Machine — $530.00</a></div><a href="https://www.williams-sonoma.com/products/smeg-espresso-machine/?catalogId=79&amp;sku=528443&amp;cm_ven=PLA&amp;cm_cat"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>“<span style="font-weight:400;">As a habitual moka pot user, I appreciate that Smeg’s Manual Espresso Machine doesn’t overwhelm you with bells and whistles. It gives me the core coffeeshop fixtures that make me feel like a professional at home—the portafilter and steam wand—and there are only four buttons on the entire machine: a power button, single and double cup brew buttons, and a steam button to ready the steam valve. Beyond learning how to use the steam valve (which you’ll get the hang of after one or two tries), the machine itself is super straightforward. </span></p> 
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">It doesn’t have a grinder, so you’ll need to start with ground coffee, and it comes with one and two-cup filter baskets that can be swapped out with ease when you’re in need of an extra dose of caffeine. To use, just power on the machine, load up the portafilter, twist it in place, tap your brew button (once the lights have stopped blinking to indicate it’s reached brewing temp), and you’ll get a smooth cup of espresso in a pinch. For foamy milk, just tap the steam valve button to heat it up, and pull the lever—while submerging the valve in milk—for a quick and satisfying steam. Warning: you’ll feel like a professional barista while you do this. The result is a consistently delicious and easy to make espresso, which my slow morning brain truly appreciates. </span></p> 
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">Thanks to its simple mechanics and user-friendly design, the Smeg is easy to clean. Just dump out the coffee grounds and rinse out the filter, and wipe the steam valve clean with a damp cloth. </span></p> 
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">And obviously when it comes to style, few do it better than Smeg. The Italian home appliance brand is known for its gorgeous, retro look that brings a modern flair to any kitchen. And I can tell you that its Espresso Coffee Machine looks just as stunning in person as it did on my Pinterest board. The glossy exterior and polished chrome accents do the impossible task of dressing up my old granite countertops, and the cream colorway (there are several color options to choose from) totally brightens up the space. </span></p> 
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">One important thing to note, however, is that save for the stainless steel accents, the body of the machine is plastic, which is admittedly a bummer given the high price and luxe aesthetic. It also makes the machine very lightweight, which means you’ll have to awkwardly hold it down as you twist the filter back into place to avoid it moving around your counter (even with the anti-slip feet)—it gets easier the more I use it, but it’s worth noting given the machine’s hefty price tag.” – Alexa Casanova, freelance writer</span></p> 
<p><strong>Type:</strong> Semi-automatic</p> 
<p><b>Features:</b></p> 
<ul> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Manual steam wand</span></li> 
<li>Thermoblock heating system</li> 
<li>Ability to make hot water</li> 
<li>Adjustable coffee size</li> 
<li>Decalcification alarm</li> 
<li>Adjustable coffee temps</li> 
<li>Holds up to 1 liter of water</li> 
</ul> 
<p><b>Accessories included:</b></p> 
<ul> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Portafilter</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">1 and 2 cup filters</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Paper pod filter</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Measuring scoop </span></li> 
</ul> 
<p><b>Dimensions: </b><span style="font-weight:400;">13″ x 5 7/8″ x 13″</span></p> 
<p><strong>Warranty: </strong><span style="font-weight:400;">1 year </span><span style="font-weight:400;"><br> 
</span></p> 
<p> </p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Easy to use  
 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Makes quality espresso  
 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Easy to clean 
 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Makes hot water 
  
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Makes steamed/frothed milk  
  
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Stylish retro design 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Slips around on your counter due to the lightweight design 
 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Plastic body doesn’t feel luxe  
 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Expensive 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.williams-sonoma.com/products/smeg-espresso-machine/?catalogId=79&amp;sku=528443&amp;cm_ven=PLA&amp;cm_cat"> 
            Shop Now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
            </div> 
</div> 
<div></div> 
<div> 
  <div> 
          <h2>Best for latte art</h2> 
     
     
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.amazon.com/DeLonghi-EC9155MB-Specialista-Espresso-Machine/dp/B099YT9MYG"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/WG_Commerce_Best-Espresso-Machines-InsetsDelonghi-La-Specialista-Arte.jpg" alt="best espresso machines"> 
                </a> 
                Photo: W+G Creative 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/DeLonghi-EC9155MB-Specialista-Espresso-Machine/dp/B099YT9MYG"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/DeLonghi-EC9155MB-Specialista-Espresso-Machine/dp/B099YT9MYG">Delonghi, La Specialista Arte Espresso Machine — $500.00</a></div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/DeLonghi-EC9155MB-Specialista-Espresso-Machine/dp/B099YT9MYG"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p><strong>Originally $700, now $500</strong></p> 
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">“Little daily rituals ground my day—and making myself a latte (or three!) using the </span><a href="https://www.amazon.com/DeLonghi-EC9155MB-Specialista-Espresso-Machine/dp/B099YT9MYG"><span style="font-weight:400;">DeLonghi La Specialista Arte</span></a><span style="font-weight:400;"> ($500) is one of my favorites. I love waking up in the morning and hobbling over to my personal cafe, filling my space with the smell of coffee, and making a professional-level drink while I’m still in my PJs.</span></p> 
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">It starts by hitting the “OK” button and seeing the machine light up. (I interpret the flashing to mean “Good morning! I’m ready!!!!!”). I place the dosing funnel onto the portafilter and press it toward the back of the machine for it to dose out freshly ground beans. The Arte has precise settings, so I’m able to set the perfect dose amount and water temperature for the bean type whenever I refill. However, the settings in the booklet don’t always work out perfectly so it can take some trial and error.  </span></p> 
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">Once the grinding stops, I tamp the grinds down. Unlike some of Delonghi’s pricier models, the Arte requires manual tamping. I’ve used both and I prefer the manual tamp because it 1. makes me feel more like a barista and 2. it doesn’t include a big tamping lever on the side, taking up less counter space. To tamp, I take the portafilter off, tap the side to even out the beans, and use the included tamper and tamping mat to press down the beans. </span></p> 
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">Next, the tamping funnel comes off and the portafilter twists into the brewing water. Then, I choose if I want a single or a double shot of espresso, and twist a dial to choose whether I want just espresso or an Americano (espresso + hot water). I can also just pull hot water and not coffee. If I want a frothed drink, I pour my milk of choice—pistachio milk—into the milk pitcher (shout out to my monthly subscription to </span><a href="https://pistachiomilk.com/collections/all"><span style="font-weight:400;">Táche</span></a><span style="font-weight:400;">, the best alt milk). Then, I use the steam wand to get the milk all hot and bubbly and top off my drink.</span></p> 
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">To keep the machine sparkly and clean, I wipe it down after use (making sure to get any residual milk off the wand) and make sure to dump out any excess water that collects in the drip tray (a little red bobbly thing pops up to let you know when it’s filling up). Because my roommate and I basically have coffee instead of blood in our veins, a red light pops up every three-ish months telling us to descale the machine. It takes about an hour and involves water and </span><a href="https://www.delonghi.com/en-us/descaler-universal-eco-friendly-descaling-solution-for-coffee-and-espresso-machines-16-90-oz-5-uses-ecodecalk/p/DLSC500"><span style="font-weight:400;">DeLonghi’s Eco-Decaulk Descaler</span></a><span style="font-weight:400;"> ($25). It’s not hard, but it is involved, so if you’re curious </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k82Oa6Sd7E8"><span style="font-weight:400;">watch this vid</span></a><span style="font-weight:400;"> instead of having to read me try to explain it.</span></p> 
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">I’ve had my machine since August and love it like a child. Sadly, it did spring a violent leak about five months in, making it impossible to use. But, DeLonghi has a great warranty—two years standard and an additional year if you register your machine online. So after a quick video call with a DeLonghi Specialist (Thanks, Guy!!!), I was able to mail out my unit for repairs and got it back a few weeks later good as new. </span></p> 
<p><span style="font-weight:400;">If you’re a coffee lover who wants an intelligent machine that still leaves room for a little fun and artistry, the DeLonghi La Specialista Arte is perfect.” – Kara Brown, beauty writer</span></p> 
<p><strong>Type:</strong> Semi-automatic</p> 
<p><strong>Features:</strong></p> 
<ul> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Built-in coffee bean grinder</span></li> 
<li>8 grind setting</li> 
<li>Thermoblock heating system</li> 
<li>Manual steam wand</li> 
<li>Preset single or double shot</li> 
<li>Ability to make hot water</li> 
<li>Adjustable brew temps</li> 
<li>Auto shut-off</li> 
<li>Removable water tank</li> 
<li>Removable drip tray</li> 
<li>Water level indicator</li> 
</ul> 
<p><strong>Accessories included:</strong></p> 
<ul> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Portafilter</span></li> 
<li>Dosing funnel</li> 
<li>Stainless Steel Milk Frothing Jug</li> 
<li>Tamper</li> 
<li>Tamping mat</li> 
<li>Total Hardness Test</li> 
<li>Cleaning Brush</li> 
<li>Descaler 100ml</li> 
<li>Single coffee filter</li> 
<li>Double coffee filter</li> 
<li>Cleaning needle for steam nozzle</li> 
<li>Instruction Manual &amp; Quick Start Guide</li> 
</ul> 
<p><strong>Dimensions: </strong><span style="font-weight:400;">11.22″ x 14.37″ x 15.87″</span></p> 
<p><strong>Warranty: </strong><span style="font-weight:400;">2 years + 1 if you register</span></p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Easy to use 
  
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Compact for what it offers 
  
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Looks stunning on my counter 
  
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Brews delicious espresso 
  
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Froths milk like a pro 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Manual tamping 
  
</li> 
                                                                <li>Requires whole beans (which can be pricey) 
  
</li> 
                                                                <li>Expensive 
  
</li> 
                                                                <li>Descaling is a bit annoying 
 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Requires some maintenance 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/DeLonghi-EC9155MB-Specialista-Espresso-Machine/dp/B099YT9MYG"> 
            Shop Now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
            </div> 
</div> 
<div></div> 
<div> 
  <div> 
          <h2>Best combination</h2> 
     
     
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mr-Coffee-2168819-Coffeehouse-Cappuccino/dp/B09R5ZP81W/?th=1"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/WG_Commerce_Best-Espresso-Machines-InsetsMr.-Coffee-One-Touch-Machine.jpg" alt="best espresso machines"> 
                </a> 
                Photo: W+G Creative 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mr-Coffee-2168819-Coffeehouse-Cappuccino/dp/B09R5ZP81W/?th=1"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mr-Coffee-2168819-Coffeehouse-Cappuccino/dp/B09R5ZP81W/?th=1">Mr. Coffee, One Touch Espresso, Cappuccino, and Latte Maker — $308.00</a></div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mr-Coffee-2168819-Coffeehouse-Cappuccino/dp/B09R5ZP81W/?th=1"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p><strong>Originally $350, now $308</strong></p> 
<p>“Froth? I want ALL of it, and Mr. Coffee’s One Touch Espresso Machine makes it easy to whip up all kinds of drinks. As the name implies, with just a push of a button, you can have a latte, espresso, or cappuccino within minutes. For pro baristas or coffee fanatics, there’s also a manual button for each of the coffee settings, so you can configure the right dosage.</p> 
<p>What I love about this machine is the portafilter and automatic milk frother. As someone who likes to take it easy in the morning, it’s a breath of fresh air not to worry about grinding or manual frothing with this machine. The One Touch comes with a portafilter, which takes coffee grinds, giving you the feeling of a being behind the barista counter minus the actual stress of having to determine the grind size. To use the frother, I just add milk in the container and click it back into the machine. If I want more froth, I just turn the dial. The result is a fluffy, cloud-like latte that’s too yummy to put down.</p> 
<p>I do wish the water container was a bit larger than the frothing reservoir (it holds 18 ounces of liquid)—they are about the same size—so I didn’t have to worry about refilling it so quickly. One thing to consider is that this machine has a “warm-up” time. The progress bar at the top will illuminate in increments. Once it’s ready to brew, the whole bar will glow, but this process can take up to two minutes (a little bit long, if you ask me). Another caveat is the plastic and lightweight build. It can be hard to lock in the portafilter without the machine moving around, but I just hold down the machine to ensure the filter locks in place. Things to love, though: The tamper is built into a measuring spoon, so you can scoop the grinds and tamp with the same tool.</p> 
<p>For the money, this machine creates a good selection of drinks, and is a great combo machine to have on the counter. What also helps? It looks chic and stylish. If you love a variety of drinks, but want the ease of use in making them, consider Mr. Coffee.” – Kayla Hui, commerce writer</p> 
<p><strong>Type:</strong> Semi-automatic</p> 
<p><b>Features:</b></p> 
<ul> 
<li>Progress bar for when machine is ready to brew</li> 
<li>One-touch control panel</li> 
<li>Automatic frother</li> 
<li>Milk reservoir</li> 
<li>Water reservoir</li> 
<li>Adjustable cup tray</li> 
</ul> 
<p><b>Accessories included:</b></p> 
<ul> 
<li>Single and double shot filters</li> 
<li>Measuring scoop and tamper</li> 
</ul> 
<p><b>Warranty: </b>1<span style="font-weight:400;"> year</span></p> 
<p><b>Dimensions</b><span style="font-weight:400;">: 14.7″ x 8.5″ x 12.6″ </span></p> 
<p> </p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Has a milk and water reservoir 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Manual and automatic modes 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Makes espresso, cappuccino, and latte 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Automatic milk frother 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Plastic body doesn’t feel luxe 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Latte dosage is smaller 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Takes roughly two-minutes to “warm up” 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mr-Coffee-2168819-Coffeehouse-Cappuccino/dp/B09R5ZP81W/?th=1"> 
            Shop Now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
            </div> 
</div> 
<div></div> 
<div> 
  <div> 
          <h2>Best for pro baristas</h2> 
     
     
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Breville-Barista-Pro-Automatic-Integrated/dp/B08133HX34"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/WG_Commerce_Best-Espresso-Machines-InsetsBreville-Barista-Pro-.jpg" alt="best espresso machines"> 
                </a> 
                Photo: W+G Creative 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Breville-Barista-Pro-Automatic-Integrated/dp/B08133HX34"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Breville-Barista-Pro-Automatic-Integrated/dp/B08133HX34">Breville, Barista Pro — $680.00</a></div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Breville-Barista-Pro-Automatic-Integrated/dp/B08133HX34"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>“I’m nowhere near retirement age, but my dreams of owning a coffee shop in my elderly years and channeling my inner barista came early. As a full disclaimer, I’m not a pro barista—I just aspire to be one, but this machine has already set me up for success.</p> 
<p>The machine comes with a built-in grinder and a heavy duty, stainless steel portafilter that makes getting the first part of espresso-making easy. All I have to do is load the portafilter in the grinder port, push the filter in once, and watch as all the espresso-y goodness fall down. Here’s where pro barista experience is needed: You have to determine the grind size, which can be adjusted with a built-in dial.</p> 
<p>Once the grinding is done, I use my tamper and tamp, tamp, tamp (because I like mine extra flat), and lock the portafilter back into the brewing port. Within seconds after pushing the espresso making button, I have a shot (or two) of espresso. The part where I feel like a true barista is when I have to froth the milk. Included in the kit is a stainless steel milk frothing cup, where I pour my milk of choice: Minor Figures Oat Milk. It takes under a minute to get hot, and once it’s ready, I pour all of the frothy goodness into my cup. I love this feature a <em>latte</em>. Can you tell?</p> 
<p>It is worth noting that the machine retails for a hefty $680, which is a ton of coins if you don’t plan on drinking coffee on the daily. However, if you’re going to be espresso-ing it up frequently, it’s a sound investment. The nice perk is the stainless steel build; it’s a durable machine with tough accessories, so this machine is going to last me a LONG time. Since using it, I barely go out for coffee, which means more moolah for me.” – Kayla Hui, commerce writer</p> 
<p><strong>Type:</strong> Semi-automatic</p> 
<p><b>Features:</b></p> 
<ul> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Built-in coffee bean grinder</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Adjustable grind control with 30 grind settings</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Thermojet heating system</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Manual steam wand</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Preset single or double shot</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Ability to make hot water</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">LCD screen </span><span style="font-weight:400;"><br> 
</span></li> 
</ul> 
<p><b>Accessories included:</b></p> 
<ul> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Portafilter</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Milk jug for steaming milk</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">A precision razor </span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">Cleaning kit</span></li> 
<li><span style="font-weight:400;">A steam wand cleaning tool and a cleaning brush</span></li> 
<li>Filter baskets</li> 
</ul> 
<p><b>Warranty: </b><span style="font-weight:400;">2 years</span></p> 
<p><b>Dimensions</b><span style="font-weight:400;">: 13.9″ x 13.5″ x 16″</span></p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Built-in grinder 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Simple to clean 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Stainless steel build 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Can make lattes in minutes 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Expensive 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Not easy to use for beginners 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Requires whole beans (which can be pricey) 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Breville-Barista-Pro-Automatic-Integrated/dp/B08133HX34"> 
            Shop Now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
            </div> 
</div>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 13:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Fitness</category>
<dc:creator>Kayla Hui</dc:creator>
<source url="http://wellandgood.com/">Well+Good</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e7517ba8852</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Pull-String Bathing Suit That’s All Over the Internet Does Not Disappoint—It Makes Me Feel *So* Confident</title>
<link>https://www.wellandgood.com/ta3-swimsuit-review/</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I can’t wait to start hanging out in a bathing suit for the entirety of summer. I’m just a warm-weather kind of lady. But, as a 38-year-old mom of two, with the battle scars to prove it, sometimes I wonder if my days of strutting around poolside, totally unencumbered by <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/body-positive-beach-body-tips/">body-shame</a>, are behind me. Of course, that’s a ridiculous thought. I know my body is bangin’, but thanks to years and years of narrow (and frankly, unrealistic) societal body standards and things like filters and Photoshop, it’s hard <i>not</i> to think it.</p> 
<p>There are a few things I strive to do to change that. For starters, I try to talk nicely to myself about my body, even the parts I don’t love, like my droopy post-nursing boobs and my belly with just a bit of jiggle. I also exercise daily, and prioritize <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/joyful-exercise/">joyful movement</a>. But by far, the best thing I do for myself when summer rolls around is buy a <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/best-swimsuit-brands/">bathing suit</a> I feel absolutely great in. This year, I have to say, I outdid myself by taking a chance and ordering a suit from <a href="https://ta3swim.com/">TA3, </a>a product so genius and first-of-its-kind, it was featured on Shark Tank.</p> 
<div> 
  <div> 
     
     
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://ta3swim.com/collections/all-products/products/lacey-black"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/ta3-swimsuit.png" alt="ta3 swimsuit"> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://ta3swim.com/collections/all-products/products/lacey-black"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://ta3swim.com/collections/all-products/products/lacey-black">Ta3 Swim, Lacey  — $158.00</a></div><a href="https://ta3swim.com/collections/all-products/products/lacey-black"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p><strong>Sizes available:</strong> XS-3X, regular/long or short</p> 
<p><strong>Colors:</strong> 7</p> 
</div> 
           
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Pros:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                      <li>Compressive, but still comfortable 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Smoothing fabric 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>High-quality and long-lasting 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Made for all body types 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Size-inclusive 
</li> 
                                                                        <li>Adjustable straps and removable bust pads (basically feels like it’s tailored to your body) 
</li> 
                                                </ul> 
            </div> 
                                <div> 
                              <div> 
                  <p><strong>Cons:</strong></p> 
                </div> 
                            <ul> 
                                                <li>Expensive 
</li> 
                                                                <li>Only comes in solid colors 
</li> 
                                            </ul> 
            </div> 
           
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://ta3swim.com/collections/all-products/products/lacey-black"> 
            Shop Now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
            </div> 
</div> 
<h2>My honest review of the TA3 Lacy swimsuit</h2> 
<p>I’d been seeing these suits with the pull-string waists in my Instagram ads (you probably have, too), and I knew I had to snag one. I excitedly ordered <a href="https://ta3swim.com/collections/all-products/products/lacey-sapphire">The Lacey,</a> a stunning one-piece with a criss-cross back, but I couldn’t have anticipated just how great this suit would fit. As a person with a much bigger top than bottom, suits are always tough for me. Especially one-pieces. But this one manages to hug my body perfectly, which is perhaps because, with a pull-string waist, you’re basically your own tailor. Synching it up feels like the best magic trick you’ve ever seen. No filters required!</p> 
<p>While I’ve struggled to find a killer one-piece since I was a teenager, I’m thrilled to say that I finally have one. It doesn’t just fit my body. It shapes and lifts it, too. While there are a lot of one-pieces out there with cool designs, and maybe a few that will fit me well, I’ve never found one that sculpts my body, too. It’s like I’ve gone back about 10 years (or two kids) in time and I look pretty snatched if I do say so myself. The suit is also incredibly well-made, super supportive, and has a killer cut.</p> 
<img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/ta3-swimsuit-sarah.jpg" alt="ta3 swimsuit" width="1800" height="1200">Photo: Sarah Bregel 
<p>And I’m not the only one who’s a major fan of this swimsuit—other reviewers have left glowing reviews about the fit, look, and functionality of the suit. “This suit is beyond expectations. I got the red in small and I’m just saying….be ready to look like a <em>Baywatch</em> babe when you get it! The leg cut is so flattering and the fit is unlike any suit I’ve tried. I am a mom of twins and it gives me the waist of my dreams,” one shopper says.</p> 
<p>Another writes, “This is the best swimsuit I have ever purchased. It is a little pricey HOWEVER i have not felt this confident in a swimsuit in a while. It accents all the right parts of my body and the quality is just THERE. You can really feel that it’s made well and built to last.”</p> 
<p>While I couldn’t wait for the weather to turn, (because, hello, summer) now I’ve got even more reason to be blissful come those glorious pool days. I’ll be strutting, swimming, and lazying without an ounce of sweat-soaked body-shame in sight. With my Lacey by TA3, I’ve got all the body confidence I’ll need until Labor Day, and more than I ever imagined I’d get from a bathing suit.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 00:28:11 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Fitness</category>
<dc:creator>Sarah Bregel</dc:creator>
<source url="http://wellandgood.com/">Well+Good</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e7517679e1c</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Improving Your Circadian Clock</title>
<link>https://www.bodybuilding.com/content/improving-your-circadian-clock.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.bodybuilding.com/images/2023/april/improving-your-circadian-clock-header-960x540.jpg" alt="improving-your-circadian-clock-header-96"></p>It’s all in the timing.]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 23:33:10 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Fitness</category>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<source url="http://www.bodybuilding.com/fun/bbinfoupdate.php?day=7">Bodybuilding.com Articles</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e751763f471</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Impact of Healthy Fats on Women</title>
<link>https://www.bodybuilding.com/content/impact-of-healthy-fats-on-women.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.bodybuilding.com/images/2023/april/impact-of-healthy-fats-on-women-header-960x540.jpg" alt="impact-of-healthy-fats-on-women-header-9"></p>Why fats are important in a woman’s diet.]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 23:33:10 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Fitness</category>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<source url="http://www.bodybuilding.com/fun/bbinfoupdate.php?day=7">Bodybuilding.com Articles</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e751763f46e</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>‘Lash Baths’ Are the Only Way a Dermatologist and an Ophthalmologist Want You To Take Off Your Mascara—Here’s How To Do Them Right</title>
<link>https://www.wellandgood.com/lash-bath/</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/GettyImages-1206222024.jpg" alt="GettyImages-1206222024.jpg"></p><p>There was a stretch of time when I loved getting regular lash extensions. While I’m on the natural train now, it looks like I wasn’t the only lover, with the industry continuing to soar year after year. A report by <a href="https://www.fortunebusinessinsights.com/false-eyelashes-market-106573">Fortune Business Insights</a> valued the global false lash industry at $1.33 billion in 2022, with projections to grow to $2.12 billion by 2030. While extensions are in my past, one thing I learned during that time was the importance of cleaning in and around the lashes and eyes. So it’s good that recent times have seen new popularity in the term ‘lash bath’. And the best part is that the additional skin care step benefits everyone—not just those with lash extensions.</p>  
<h2>What is a lash bath?</h2>  
<p>“A lash bath is a term used to describe cleansing your eyelashes of impurities and makeup residue,” explains Dr. Harold Lancer, founder of <a href="https://www.lancerskincare.com/">Lancer Skincare</a>. And while most of us will cleanse our faces, including over the eye and lash region, it’s not the same as a daily lash bath.</p>  
<p>“Traditional face washes contain ingredients that are too harsh for the delicate eye area,” says Dr. Lancer. The skin around our eyes is more delicate and incredibly thin, so it’s important to be gentle and focus on this area separately. On top of that, our lashes are a first line of defense against damage to the eyes, so they need some extra TLC. “The skin, as well as your lashes, are your first lines of defense against bacteria, debris, and other harmful contaminants that could damage your eyes,” says Dr. Diane Hilal-Campo, board-certified ophthalmologist and founder of <a href="https://trytwentytwenty.com/">twenty/twenty beauty</a>. “We only get one set of eyes, and proper care is critical to ensure ocular health. If you harm the skin or lashes, you put your eyes in harm’s way, too.”</p>  
<h2>Why are lash baths important?</h2>  
<p>In the past, it has been assumed that lash baths are for just those with extensions. However, Dr. Hilal-Campo says it’s not exclusive and should be done by all each night. “Lash baths not only remove the makeup, dirt, debris, and dust in and on your lids and lashes but also help prevent Demodex, a type of mite that is naturally found in the lashes.”</p>  
<h2>How to give yourself a lash bath</h2>  
<p>First and foremost, it’s crucial to remember how delicate the area is, so slow and steady wins the race. After that, it’s as simple as using your lash cleanser with a gentle tool brush to cleanse and purify them. “Don’t use anything with sharp bristles, as they can damage your eyes,” warns Dr. Hilal-Campo. “Also do not rub at your eyes and lashes when trying to cleanse them – this is very irritating and can even pull lashes out or harm your eyes.” And if you don’t feel like you got it all cleaned the first time, don’t be afraid to go over it again. “Keep it simple and rinse thoroughly with warm water when you’re done,” says Dr. Lancer.</p>  
<h2>The best products for lash baths</h2>  
<p>First and foremost, Dr. Hilal-Campo notes that lash baths are not antibacterial, something to keep in mind, particularly for those with lash extensions. “To sanitize lash extensions safely, I recommend using a hypochlorous acid spray like <a href="https://www.amazon.com/twenty-beauty-Alleviates-Inflammation-Cruelty-Free/dp/B0BCQYQJ49/r">twenty/twenty beauty’s Easy on the Eyes Daily Hygiene Spray</a>. Using a delicate spray like that, made for the eye area, is non-irritating, will not only kill bacteria but also does not contain any oil – so, therefore, will not loosen the glue of the extensions. “Hypochlorous acid is naturally found in the body and helps rid of bacteria,” explains the ophthalmologist. “The acid is produced by your white blood cells to help destroy invaders, and is not only great at cleansing the skin and lashes but also wonderful for starving off breakouts and styes.”</p>  
<p>If you do have lash extensions, then you’re advised to stay away from oil-based products. However, if you don’t and you’re looking for a natural alternative for a lash cleaner, Dr. Hilal-Campo suggests poppy seed oil as it’s gentle and nourishing. Additionally, she warns to stay away from products that contain aqueous solution. “Many aqueous-based eye makeup removal products are harsh on the skin and lashes because they contain harsh preservatives,” she says.</p>  
<p>And following the bath, optimal eyecare is encouraged. “To further promote lash health, incorporate a lash serum into your nighttime skincare routine,” says Dr. Lancer. The celebrity-loved dermatologist recommends a product like his Lancer Skincare Lash Serum Intense, which contains high-performance conditioning agents, pumpkin seed extract, and essential fatty acids, which can help improve the look of thin or sparse lashes.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 23:25:24 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Fitness</category>
<dc:creator>Annita Katee</dc:creator>
<source url="http://wellandgood.com/">Well+Good</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75176c9076</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Looking To Strengthen Your Pelvic Floor? Here’s a Secret Weapon</title>
<link>https://www.wellandgood.com/balance-board-for-pelvic-floor-strength/</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Although working on your pelvic floor is <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/pelvic-floor-tips/">all the rage</a>, sometimes actually figuring out <em>how</em> to do that can prove challenging. Should you be <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/pelvic-floor-stretches/">relaxing</a> it or <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/pelvic-floor-stabliity/">strengthening</a> it? How do you <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/pelvic-floor-activation/">find</a> and <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/how-to-activate-pelvic-floor/">activate</a> your pelvic floor muscles? How do you even know if your pandemic floor needs a little TLC?</p> 
<p>For those uninitiated, the pelvic floor is the sling of muscles at the base of your pelvis that keep your organs in place. Being able to relax your pelvic floor is key to being able to go to the bathroom, while having a resilient pelvic floor is important to prevent incontinence. But beyond those essential functions, your pelvic floor also plays a big role in your posture and stability.</p> 
<p>“The pelvic floor is literally the base of our core,” physical therapist Kelly Sadauckas, DPT, OCS, founder of <a href="https://www.instagram.com/therealpelvicfloored/">Pelvic Floored</a>, <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/pelvic-floor-stabliity/">previously told Well+Good</a>. The pelvic floor stabilizes the pelvis, which in turn stabilizes and aligns the hips and spine. If something is off with the pelvic floor, something could be off throughout your whole body. “From walking up the stairs, to weightlifting, to attempting to jump or move heavy boxes, if the pelvic floor isn’t functioning well, you will see compensatory patterns of leaning to one side, or having an uneven stride length when running, or observing uneven wear patterns on your shoes or socks.”</p> 
<p>Unfortunately, stress and being stationary for long periods of time can impact pelvic floor health, and experts have seen <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/pandemic-pelvis/">an uptick in pelvic floor–related issues in recent years</a>. Relieving stress, deep breathing, optimizing your work set-up are all key to pelvic floor health. But beyond doing kegels, you can actually work on your pelvic floor—and all the muscles that provide it with support—with an unexpected tool: <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/best-balance-boards/">balance boards</a>.</p> 
<p>Whether on a Bosu ball or a platform on a cylinder or springs, balance boards, well, challenge your balance. They recruit the small stabilizing muscles, such as the erector spinae (which surround your spine) and other deep core muscles—like those in the pelvic floor—to keep you upright even when the ground beneath you is unsteady. So using a balance board works both your pelvic floor, and the entire core system of which it is a part.</p> 
<p>“When you’re on the board, because you are centered on this fulcrum of springs, your body is forced to stay centered,” says personal trainer <a href="https://www.instagram.com/strongboardmike/?hl=en">Mike Curry</a>, the creator of the <a href="https://strongboardbalance.com/">StrongBoard</a>, a balance board made up of two boards with four springs sandwiched in between. “So we’re working those deeper, intricate stabilizing muscles that often get ignored with your traditional exercises where we isolate certain muscle groups.”</p> 
<blockquote style="background:#FFF;border:0;margin:1px;padding:0;"> 
<div style="padding:16px;"> 
<p> </p> 
<div> 
<div style="background-color:#f4f4f4;height:40px;margin-right:14px;width:40px;"></div> 
<div> 
<div style="background-color:#f4f4f4;height:14px;margin-bottom:6px;width:100px;"></div> 
<div style="background-color:#f4f4f4;height:14px;width:60px;"></div> 
</div> 
</div> 
<div style="padding:19% 0;"></div> 
<div style="height:50px;margin:0 auto 12px;width:50px;"></div> 
<div style="padding-top:8px;"> 
<div style="color:#3897f0;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;font-style:normal;line-height:18px;">View this post on Instagram</div> 
</div> 
<div style="padding:12.5% 0;"></div> 
<div style="margin-bottom:14px;"> 
<div> 
<div style="background-color:#f4f4f4;height:12.5px;width:12.5px;"></div> 
<div style="background-color:#f4f4f4;height:12.5px;width:12.5px;margin-right:14px;margin-left:2px;"></div> 
<div style="background-color:#f4f4f4;height:12.5px;width:12.5px;"></div> 
</div> 
<div style="margin-left:8px;"> 
<div style="background-color:#f4f4f4;height:20px;width:20px;"></div> 
<div style="width:0;height:0;border-top:2px solid transparent;border-left:6px solid #f4f4f4;border-bottom:2px solid transparent;"></div> 
</div> 
<div style="margin-left:auto;"> 
<div style="width:0px;border-top:8px solid #F4F4F4;border-right:8px solid transparent;"></div> 
<div style="background-color:#f4f4f4;height:12px;width:16px;"></div> 
<div style="width:0;height:0;border-top:8px solid #F4F4F4;border-left:8px solid transparent;"></div> 
</div> 
</div> 
<div style="margin-bottom:24px;"> 
<div style="background-color:#f4f4f4;height:14px;margin-bottom:6px;width:224px;"></div> 
<div style="background-color:#f4f4f4;height:14px;width:144px;"></div> 
</div> 
<p> </p> 
<p style="color:#c9c8cd;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;line-height:17px;margin-bottom:0;margin-top:8px;padding:8px 0 7px;text-align:center;white-space:nowrap;"><a style="color:#c9c8cd;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;font-style:normal;font-weight:normal;line-height:17px;text-decoration:none;" href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Cq8-16btIzC/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading">A post shared by StrongBoard Balance® (@strongboardbalance)</a></p> 
</div> 
</blockquote> 
<p></p> 
<p>Working on your stabilizer muscles sounds like an abstract concept, but the moment you step on the board, you get what Curry is talking about. You feel your whole body snap to attention in a way that it doesn’t when you’re not trying to prevent yourself from wobbling, which results in a constant challenge.</p> 
<p>“The brain and the muscles are trying to figure out why they can’t stabilize,” Curry says. “Your brain is constantly sending messages to your muscles to engage when you’re walking or when you’re doing anything. When it gets on here, it starts sending those messages, but they’re not working, so it’s rapidly trying to figure out why. But the more it does that, the more it starts recruiting more muscles.”</p> 
<p>All balance boards will have this effect, but Curry says the springs on the StrongBoard make it a bigger challenge, since springs are always trying to get back to their upright position, and the weight you’re baring on top of the board is fighting with that.</p> 
<div> 
  <div> 
     
     
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.amazon.com/StrongBoard-Balance-Board-Black-Blue/dp/B00P8PPOQM"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Screen-Shot-2023-05-05-at-10.50.29-AM.png" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/StrongBoard-Balance-Board-Black-Blue/dp/B00P8PPOQM"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/StrongBoard-Balance-Board-Black-Blue/dp/B00P8PPOQM">StrongBoard Balance Board — $269.00</a></div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/StrongBoard-Balance-Board-Black-Blue/dp/B00P8PPOQM"> 
                          </a> 
                       
                      <div><p>The StrongBoard allows you to test your balance and build your strength. Just standing on the board, you feel your muscles engage as they try to stabilize you. But you can also perform exercises like squats, lunges, planks, tricep dips, and more on the board to give specific muscle groups an intense workout.</p> 
</div> 
           
                               
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/StrongBoard-Balance-Board-Black-Blue/dp/B00P8PPOQM"> 
            Shop Now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
            </div> 
</div> 
<p>Curry recommends very basic exercises that challenge your balance to strengthen your pelvic floor while using the StrongBoard, since the device will “challenge you to brace your core to get more out of your movements, forcing those deep, intricate stabilizing muscles to stay contracted.” Specifically, the exercises he suggests include:</p> 
<ol> 
<li>Squats with both feet on the board. You can slowly move up and down in the squat, or test your strength and balance in an extended squat hold.</li> 
<li>Hip thrusts with your feet on the board and your shoulders on the ground.</li> 
<li>A plank with your arms on the board and your feet on the ground. Try mixing it up with some slow mountain climbers.</li> 
<li>Lunges with your front foot on the board and your back foot on the ground.</li> 
</ol> 
<p>Even though these exercises are known to work your hamstrings, quads, glutes, and core, with the added challenge of stabilizing, “your pelvic floor muscles will have no say in relaxing,” says Curry.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 22:24:43 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Fitness</category>
<dc:creator>Rachel Kraus</dc:creator>
<source url="http://wellandgood.com/">Well+Good</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e751769b2b2</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>David Henry Looks to Achieve Another Olympia Milestone at the 2023 Masters Olympia Contest</title>
<link>https://breakingmuscle.com/david-henry-2023-masters-olympia-contest/</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://breakingmuscle.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/David-Henry-2023-Master-Olympia-Training.jpg" alt="David-Henry-2023-Master-Olympia-Training"></p><p>The <a href="https://breakingmuscle.com/2023-masters-olympia-roster/">2023 Masters Olympia</a> is scheduled to be held on the weekend of Aug. 26-27, 2023 in Cluj-Napoca, Romania. There will be plenty of history made at this competition. It’s the first time that the Men’s Open Masters Olympia will be held since <a href="https://breakingmuscle.com/dexter-jackson-training-back-arms-workout/">Dexter Jackson</a> won the title in 2012. For the other nine divisions, it will be their first Masters Olympia competition, including the 212 division.</p>  
  
  
  
<p>One of the men in that 212 lineup is David Henry, who knows a lot about making Olympia history. He’s the first Olympia champion in the history of the 212, which dates back to even before the weight cap <em>was</em> 212 pounds.</p>  
  
  
  
<div>  
<div><blockquote style="background:#FFF;border:0;margin:1px;padding:0;width:99.375%;"><div style="padding:16px;"> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="background-color:#F4F4F4;height:40px;margin-right:14px;width:40px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="background-color:#F4F4F4;height:14px;margin-bottom:6px;width:100px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="background-color:#F4F4F4;height:14px;width:60px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a><div style="padding:19% 0;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="height:50px;margin:0 auto 12px;width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a><div style="padding-top:8px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="color:#3897f0;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;font-style:normal;line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;">View this post on Instagram</a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a><div style="padding:12.5% 0;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="margin-bottom:14px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a><div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="background-color:#F4F4F4;height:12.5px;width:12.5px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="background-color:#F4F4F4;height:12.5px;width:12.5px;margin-right:14px;margin-left:2px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="background-color:#F4F4F4;height:12.5px;width:12.5px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a><div style="margin-left:8px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="background-color:#F4F4F4;height:20px;width:20px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="width:0;height:0;border-top:2px solid transparent;border-left:6px solid #f4f4f4;border-bottom:2px solid transparent;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a><div style="margin-left:auto;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="width:0px;border-top:8px solid #F4F4F4;border-right:8px solid transparent;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="background-color:#F4F4F4;height:12px;width:16px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="width:0;height:0;border-top:8px solid #F4F4F4;border-left:8px solid transparent;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="margin-bottom:24px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="background-color:#F4F4F4;height:14px;margin-bottom:6px;width:224px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="background-color:#F4F4F4;height:14px;width:144px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a><p style="color:#c9c8cd;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;line-height:17px;margin-bottom:0;margin-top:8px;padding:8px 0 7px;text-align:center;white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/Crl-Z60ADRn/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="color:#c9c8cd;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;font-style:normal;font-weight:normal;line-height:17px;text-decoration:none;">A post shared by David Henry aka The OGK (@davidhenry_ifbbpro)</a></p></div></blockquote></div>  
</div>  
  
  
  
<div>  
<p><em><strong>More from Breaking Muscle:</strong></em></p>  
  
  
  
<ul>  
<li><em><strong><a href="https://breakingmuscle.com/start-training-over-40/">How to Start Training if You’re Over 40</a></strong></em></li>  
  
  
  
<li><strong><em><a href="https://breakingmuscle.com/workout-splits/">Workout Splits Explained: How They Work and Why You Need Them</a></em></strong></li>  
</ul>  
</div>  
  
  
  
<p>Henry was a part of the lineup for the inaugural Olympia 202 Showdown in 2008, when the weight cap for the division was 202 pounds. That contest in Las Vegas, NV was the first time since 1979 that the Olympia had two different <a href="https://breakingmuscle.com/how-to-eat-more/">weight classes</a>. Frank Zane won the lightweight and overall <a href="https://breakingmuscle.com/2022-mr-olympia-results/">Mr. Olympia</a> titles that year, before the classes were reunited in 1980 — the year <a href="https://breakingmuscle.com/arnold-schwarzenegger-classic-physique-replace-mr-olympia/">Arnold Schwarzenegger</a> came out of retirement to win his seventh Mr. Olympia title.</p>  
  
  
  
<p>When Henry won that inaugural Olympia 202 title, he faced a lineup of contenders that included two eventual <a href="https://breakingmuscle.com/bodybuilding-workout/">bodybuilding</a> greats. Kevin English finished in second place — he would go on to win the next three 202 Olympia titles from 2009-2011. <a href="https://breakingmuscle.com/flex-lewis-retirement-comeback-seven-figures/">Flex Lewis</a> placed third in 2008 and he would eventually overtake English to begin his own string of seven titles once the weight cap was raised to 212 in 2012.</p>  
  
  
  
<p>Henry never reclaimed his title after losing it in 2009, but he’s been a mainstay in the division in the years since. As an active competitor, Henry most recently placed third at the 2022 Japan Pro and earned his most recent contest victory at the 2021 Legion Sports Fest Pro. At 48 years old, he’s qualified to be in the 2023 Masters Olympia 212 lineup with its 40-year-old minimum.</p>  
  
  
  
<div>  
<div><blockquote style="background:#FFF;border:0;margin:1px;padding:0;width:99.375%;"><div style="padding:16px;"> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="background-color:#F4F4F4;height:40px;margin-right:14px;width:40px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="background-color:#F4F4F4;height:14px;margin-bottom:6px;width:100px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="background-color:#F4F4F4;height:14px;width:60px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a><div style="padding:19% 0;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="height:50px;margin:0 auto 12px;width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a><div style="padding-top:8px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="color:#3897f0;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;font-style:normal;line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;">View this post on Instagram</a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a><div style="padding:12.5% 0;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="margin-bottom:14px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a><div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="background-color:#F4F4F4;height:12.5px;width:12.5px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="background-color:#F4F4F4;height:12.5px;width:12.5px;margin-right:14px;margin-left:2px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="background-color:#F4F4F4;height:12.5px;width:12.5px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a><div style="margin-left:8px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="background-color:#F4F4F4;height:20px;width:20px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="width:0;height:0;border-top:2px solid transparent;border-left:6px solid #f4f4f4;border-bottom:2px solid transparent;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a><div style="margin-left:auto;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="width:0px;border-top:8px solid #F4F4F4;border-right:8px solid transparent;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="background-color:#F4F4F4;height:12px;width:16px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="width:0;height:0;border-top:8px solid #F4F4F4;border-left:8px solid transparent;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="margin-bottom:24px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="background-color:#F4F4F4;height:14px;margin-bottom:6px;width:224px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"> </a><div style="background-color:#F4F4F4;height:14px;width:144px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a></div><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="background:#FFFFFF;line-height:0;padding:0 0;text-align:center;text-decoration:none;width:100%;"></a><p style="color:#c9c8cd;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;line-height:17px;margin-bottom:0;margin-top:8px;padding:8px 0 7px;text-align:center;white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CVZNiMNgTxx/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style="color:#c9c8cd;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;font-style:normal;font-weight:normal;line-height:17px;text-decoration:none;">A post shared by David Henry aka The OGK (@davidhenry_ifbbpro)</a></p></div></blockquote></div>  
</div>  
  
  
  
<div>  
<p><em><strong>More from Breaking Muscle:</strong></em></p>  
  
  
  
<ul>  
<li><em><strong><a href="https://breakingmuscle.com/how-to-burn-fat/">Everything You Need to Know About How to Burn Fat</a></strong></em></li>  
  
  
  
<li><strong><em><a href="https://breakingmuscle.com/how-to-build-muscle-over-40-training-tips/">10 Essential Muscle-Building Tips for Lifters Over 40</a></em></strong></li>  
</ul>  
</div>  
  
  
  
<p>The full 18-man lineup for the 2023 Masters Olympia 212 is below.</p>  
  
  
  
<ul>  
<li><strong>Anwar Darwish Ali</strong></li>  
  
  
  
<li><strong>Masoom Butt</strong></li>  
  
  
  
<li><strong>Fernando Noronha de Almeida</strong></li>  
  
  
  
<li><strong>Ricardo Plata Duran</strong></li>  
  
  
  
<li><strong>Jim Everton</strong></li>  
  
  
  
<li><strong>Derik Farnsworth</strong></li>  
  
  
  
<li><strong>Ahmed Fawzi</strong></li>  
  
  
  
<li><strong>David Henry</strong></li>  
  
  
  
<li><strong>Milton A. Martinez</strong></li>  
  
  
  
<li><strong>Zohir Mihoubi</strong></li>  
  
  
  
<li><strong>Bola Ojex</strong></li>  
  
  
  
<li><strong>Jicheng Qian</strong></li>  
  
  
  
<li><strong>Jonni Shreve</strong></li>  
  
  
  
<li><strong>Steve Thayer</strong></li>  
  
  
  
<li><strong>Ryan Walters</strong></li>  
  
  
  
<li><strong>Wayne Williams</strong></li>  
  
  
  
<li><strong>Jeff Williamson</strong></li>  
  
  
  
<li><strong>Hidetada Yamagishi</strong></li>  
</ul>  
  
  
  
<p>Whoever wins this contest will make history as the first Masters Olympia 212 champion, but Henry has even more history riding on this coveted championship. The only competitor to have won both the Masters Olympia and Mr. Olympia titles is Dexter Jackson, who also won the Sandow trophy in 2008 — the same year Henry won his Olympia title.</p>  
  
  
  
<p>If the United States Air Force veteran manages to take the win in Romania, his legacy in the sport may be even more secure than it already is.</p>  
  
  
  
<p><em>Featured Image: @davidhenry_ifbbpro on Instagram</em></p><p>The post <a href="https://breakingmuscle.com/david-henry-2023-masters-olympia-contest/">David Henry Looks to Achieve Another Olympia Milestone at the 2023 Masters Olympia Contest</a> appeared first on <a href="https://breakingmuscle.com">Breaking Muscle</a>.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 21:28:28 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Fitness</category>
<dc:creator>Roger Lockridge</dc:creator>
<source url="http://breakingmuscle.com/feed/rss">Breaking Muscle</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e751756f57c</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>This One Mistake In Your Beauty Routine Can Cause a Major Rosacea Flare</title>
<link>https://www.wellandgood.com/hairspray-flares-rosacea/</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>When you have rosacea, you have to watch out for certain triggers. Spending too much time in the sun, applying harsh skin-care ingredients, and even eating certain foods can cause flare ups. And according to <a href="https://www.centerforadvanceddermatology.com/">Shirley Chi, MD</a>, a board-certified dermatologist in Southern California, you also have to be super careful when using hairspray.</p> 
<p>“Hairspray contains many chemical ingredients, and because it is aerosolized, as opposed to a cream or serum, it can land on your face easily where it can cause your skin to react,” says Dr. Chi. People with rosacea are so sensitive to hairspray and other ingredients because their skin is so reactive. “When rosacea is triggered, a flare can look like redness and pimples on the cheeks, forehead, and chin, and can come with burning, swelling, and itching.”</p> 
<p>According to the American Academy of Dermatology, <a href="https://www.aad.org/public/diseases/rosacea/triggers/find">not all people with rosacea are sensitive to hairspray</a>, so it’s important to figure out your triggers so you know what to avoid. But if you notice that hairspray flares your rosacea, the good news is you don’t have to ditch it completely and accept a life of limp curls and flyaways. Dr. Chi says you have options.</p> 
<h2>3 ways to prevent hairspray from flaring rosacea</h2> 
<h3>1. Cleanse after styling your hair</h3> 
<p>“I always recommend cleansing your face after you’re done with your hair styling if you have used aerosol hair products,” she says. “That way if any chemicals have landed on your skin, you can remove them before applying sunscreen, makeup, and other skin products.”</p> 
<p>To prevent getting your hair wet during this process, you can hold it back with <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Alligator-Barrettes-Hairstyle-Hairdressing-Application/dp/B07G97CRLY/ref=sr_1_7">gentle, no-crease clips</a> ($7) or a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Spa-Headbands-Washing-Skincare-Headband/dp/B0BVM3687R/ref=sr_1_3">headband</a> ($9), or use a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/JEFFSUN-Cleansing-Delicate-Sensitive-Washcloths/dp/B087D4N2C4/ref=sr_1_8">washcloth</a> ($12) to remove hairspray residue so you can remain upright and avoid water dripping onto your hair.</p> 
<div> 
  <div> 
     
     
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Alligator-Barrettes-Hairstyle-Hairdressing-Application/dp/B07G97CRLY/ref=sr_1_7"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Madholly-No-Crease-Duck-Bill-Hair-Clips-8-Pieces.jpg" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Alligator-Barrettes-Hairstyle-Hairdressing-Application/dp/B07G97CRLY/ref=sr_1_7"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Alligator-Barrettes-Hairstyle-Hairdressing-Application/dp/B07G97CRLY/ref=sr_1_7">Madholly, No Crease Duck Bill Hair Clips 8 Pieces — $7.00</a></div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Alligator-Barrettes-Hairstyle-Hairdressing-Application/dp/B07G97CRLY/ref=sr_1_7"> 
                          </a> 
                       
           
                               
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Alligator-Barrettes-Hairstyle-Hairdressing-Application/dp/B07G97CRLY/ref=sr_1_7"> 
            Shop Now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Spa-Headbands-Washing-Skincare-Headband/dp/B0BVM3687R/ref=sr_1_3"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Ztommie-Spa-Headbands-for-Washing-Face-or-Facial-Set-of-2.jpg" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Spa-Headbands-Washing-Skincare-Headband/dp/B0BVM3687R/ref=sr_1_3"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Spa-Headbands-Washing-Skincare-Headband/dp/B0BVM3687R/ref=sr_1_3">Ztomine, Spa Headbands for Washing Face or Facial, Set of 2.jpg — $9.00</a></div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Spa-Headbands-Washing-Skincare-Headband/dp/B0BVM3687R/ref=sr_1_3"> 
                          </a> 
                       
           
                               
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Spa-Headbands-Washing-Skincare-Headband/dp/B0BVM3687R/ref=sr_1_3"> 
            Shop Now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
           
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.amazon.com/JEFFSUN-Cleansing-Delicate-Sensitive-Washcloths/dp/B087D4N2C4/ref=sr_1_8"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Jeffsun-Bamboo-Wash-Cloths.jpg" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/JEFFSUN-Cleansing-Delicate-Sensitive-Washcloths/dp/B087D4N2C4/ref=sr_1_8"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/JEFFSUN-Cleansing-Delicate-Sensitive-Washcloths/dp/B087D4N2C4/ref=sr_1_8">Jeffsun, Bamboo Wash Cloths — $12.00</a></div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/JEFFSUN-Cleansing-Delicate-Sensitive-Washcloths/dp/B087D4N2C4/ref=sr_1_8"> 
                          </a> 
                       
           
                               
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/JEFFSUN-Cleansing-Delicate-Sensitive-Washcloths/dp/B087D4N2C4/ref=sr_1_8"> 
            Shop Now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
            </div> 
</div> 
<h3>2. Cover your face when applying hairspray</h3> 
<p>“If you can’t cleanse after using hair spray, then cover your face with a dry washcloth or paper towel before using hair spray,” says Dr. Chi.</p> 
<h3>3. Use a sensitive-skin-friendly hairspray</h3> 
<p>Options one and two are likely enough, but if you’re super sensitive, you can skip hairspray altogether and substitute <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/barb-soft-clay-pomade/">pomade or gel</a> or use a sensitive-skin-friendly hairspray. Dr. Chi is a big fan of the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Free-Clear-Firm-Hairspray-sensitive/dp/B0000Y3GF2/ref=asc_df_B0000Y3GF2">Vanicream Firm Hold Hairspray</a> ($12). It’s a fragrance-free hairspray designed for sensitive skin and scalp that’s free of potential irritants.</p> 
<p>“When you look at their product line, <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/vanicream/">Vanicream</a> has no parabens, no formaldehyde, no fragrance, and no masking fragrance,” says <a href="https://www.visagederm.com/about-us/dr-st-surin-lord/">Sharleen St. Surin-Lord, MD</a>, a board-certified dermatologist in Washington DC. “And they’re lanolin-free. We like lanolin because it’s very moisturizing, but we have to keep in mind that <a href="https://www.wellandgood.com/humectants-emollients-occlusives/">lanolin</a> comes from sheep’s hair, and some people are sensitive and irritated by it.”</p> 
<div> 
  <div> 
     
     
       
      <div> 
        <div> 
                                     
                <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Free-Clear-Firm-Hairspray-sensitive/dp/B0000Y3GF2/ref=asc_df_B0000Y3GF2"> 
                  <img src="https://www.wellandgood.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Vanicream-Firm-Hold-Hairspray.jpg" alt=""> 
                </a> 
                 
               
                       
                                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Free-Clear-Firm-Hairspray-sensitive/dp/B0000Y3GF2/ref=asc_df_B0000Y3GF2"> 
                        </a><div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Free-Clear-Firm-Hairspray-sensitive/dp/B0000Y3GF2/ref=asc_df_B0000Y3GF2">Vanicream Firm Hold Hairspray — $12.00</a></div><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Free-Clear-Firm-Hairspray-sensitive/dp/B0000Y3GF2/ref=asc_df_B0000Y3GF2"> 
                          </a> 
                       
           
                               
           
                      <div> 
               
  <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Free-Clear-Firm-Hairspray-sensitive/dp/B0000Y3GF2/ref=asc_df_B0000Y3GF2"> 
            Shop Now      </a> 
            </div> 
           
                  </div> 
 
         
              </div> 
 
              <div></div> 
            </div> 
</div>]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 20:20:54 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Fitness</category>
<dc:creator>Kara Jillian Brown</dc:creator>
<source url="http://wellandgood.com/">Well+Good</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75175ddb18</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Resistant Starches for Gains</title>
<link>https://www.bodybuilding.com/content/resistant-starches-for-gains.html</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.bodybuilding.com/images/2023/april/resistant-starches-for-gains-header-960x540.jpg" alt="resistant-starches-for-gains-header-960x"></p>How can the type of carb impact your body?]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 19:33:20 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Fitness</category>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<source url="http://www.bodybuilding.com/fun/bbinfoupdate.php?day=7">Bodybuilding.com Articles</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75175abebf</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>