<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>Gaming &amp; eSports via 710988203 on Inoreader</title>
<link>https://www.inoreader.com/stream/user/1005148177/tag/Gaming%20%26%20eSports/view/html</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<atom:link href="https://www.inoreader.com/stream/user/1005148177/tag/Gaming%20%26%20eSports" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
<generator>Inoreader (https://www.inoreader.com)</generator>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 17:08:18 +0000</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 17:08:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<language>en-US</language>
<item>
<title>Activision and Riot class-action settlement payments have been detailed</title>
<link>https://www.eurogamer.net/activision-and-riot-class-action-settlement-payments-have-been-detailed</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="https://assetsio.reedpopcdn.com/activision-blizzard-logo.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" alt="activision-blizzard-logo.jpg?width=1920&amp;"> <p>Details surrounding the settlements for Activision and Riot Games employees have revealed that more than 1500 current or former workers at Riot Games workers have received payments as part of previously announced settlements following a discrimination lawsuit.
 
</p><p>According to <a href="https://www.axios.com/newsletters/axios-gaming-f6336189-e9c4-4ae3-85c7-87a2a58bc598.html">Axios</a> and a recent court filing, 1548 women have received a payment of between $2500 and $5000 (£1977 - £3950) at Riot, whilst hundreds of Activision employees are also receiving payouts for a separate, but similar, settlement.
 
</p><p>It's thought that in some instances, the terms of Riot's agreement also sees "additional payments of up to $40,000 depending on employment status and tenure". 
 
</p> <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/activision-and-riot-class-action-settlement-payments-have-been-detailed">Read more</a></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 17:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
<enclosure length="1337" type="image/jpeg" url="https://assetsio.reedpopcdn.com/activision-blizzard-logo.jpg?width=1920&amp;amp;height=1920&amp;amp;fit=bounds&amp;amp;quality=80&amp;amp;format=jpg&amp;amp;auto=webp"></enclosure>
<category>Gaming &amp; eSports</category>
<dc:creator>Vikki Blake</dc:creator>
<source url="http://www.eurogamer.net/">Eurogamer.net</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e751631fa96</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Legend of Zelda Face-Off: Which Game Is the Best?</title>
<link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-legend-of-zelda-face-off-which-game-is-the-best</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>It may be hard to believe, but The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom is only a few days away and will finally bring the long-awaited sequel to 2017’s The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild to Switch owners worldwide. However, we know the wait for May 12 is still a tough one, so we thought one of the best ways to make that a bit easier was to have <em>you </em>help us decide what the best Zelda game of all time is <em>before</em> we jump into Link’s latest adventure.</p><p>Do you think The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time deserves the top spot? How about its sequel Majora’s Mask? Maybe Breath of the Wild rose above all others to claim that special place in your heart? We’ve selected 18 of the best The Legend of Zelda games to “Face-Off” against each other two at a time, and you’ll have to make the tough choice between them to help us crown a winner worthy of the Triforce. Will you choose Skyward Sword over A Link to the Past? Twilight Princess over the original? The choice is yours…</p><p>Oh, and there is a very good chance we will bring this Face-Off back after we’ve all had some time to dive deep into The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom to see how it stacks up against the rest, as it will be fun to compare how the results differ!</p><p>(And don't forget, you can pass on a Face-Off round if you don't know a character by just hitting "skip" at the bottom of the page.)</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/faceoffs/the-legend-of-zelda-face-off-which-game-is-the-best">Click here to start voting in The Legend of Zelda Face-Off!</a></p><a href="https://www.ign.com/faceoffs/the-legend-of-zelda-face-off-which-game-is-the-best"><img src="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2023/05/07/capturea-1683465238697.PNG" alt="capturea-1683465238697.PNG"></a><h2><strong>What Is a Face-Off?</strong></h2><p>Like the name suggests, a Face-Off pits two things against one another and you decide which one is the superior of the two. In this case, you are voting to determine what the best game in The Legend of Zelda series is. It's possible to see certain games multiple times, so you can keep voting for your favorites to ensure they get ranked higher than the rest. IGN's resident team of Zelda experts pre-selected 18 games for you to choose from. These get randomly paired up and each time you pick a winner, it's tracked.</p><h2><strong>How Is the Winner Determined?</strong></h2><p>When voting ends on May 11, the day before The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom arrives, we’ll tally up the total number of "wins" and "losses" each Zelda video game has and create a ranked list based on your choices that will go live on May 12. The game that won the most match-ups will be crowned the "winner," and in the event of a tied number of "wins," the game with the least "losses" will take the top spot. If you continue to keep voting for your favorite game, they'll have a better chance of ranking high on the list. You can vote as many times as you want until the Face-Off closes.</p><h2><strong>How Do I Know When I’ve Clicked Through Everything?</strong></h2><p>It's difficult to know when you've seen every Zelda video game included because they are matched randomly, and there are many possible match-ups. Playing until you vote for all your favorites or ensuring that certain games don't get in the winner's circle are different options you can take with a Face-Off. By deciding the winner throughout all these match-ups, you're ensuring that your picks for the best Zelda video game will have a fighting chance to reach the top of the list.</p><h2><strong>Which The Legend of Zelda Video Games Have You Included?</strong></h2><p>The list of games from The Legend of Zelda series we’ve chosen all come from the mainline Zelda games we all know and love. This includes everything from the original back in 1986 to 2017’s The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild on all platforms, but it does not include separate entries for remakes/remasters. This means Ocarina of Time for N64 and Ocarina of Time 3D for 3DS are all the same entry, so you can consider all of that when you make your vote! We’ve also not added spin-offs like Age of Calamity: Hyrule Warriors, games where Zelda characters show up like Super Smash Bros., or the hilarious Philips CD-i titles like Zelda: The Wand of Gamelon. We wanted to focus this Face-Off on the main series so we can truly see what IGN’s audience believes is the best Zelda of them all.</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/faceoffs/the-legend-of-zelda-face-off-which-game-is-the-best">Click here to start voting in The Legend of Zelda Face-Off!</a></p><p>For more, be sure to check out IGN’s list of the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-10-best-legend-of-zelda-games">best The Legend of Zelda games</a> of all time, our hands-on <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-hands-on-preview-it-lets-you-test-out-your-craziest-ideas">preview of The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom,</a> and five reasons why we believe <a href="https://www.ign.com/videos/five-reasons-why-the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-looks-like-more-than-just-a-breath-of-the-wild-sequel">Tears of the Kingdom is more than just a sequel to Breath of the Wild.</a><a href="https://www.ign.com/videos/five-reasons-why-the-legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-looks-like-more-than-just-a-breath-of-the-wild-sequel"></a></p><p><em>Adam Bankhurst is a news writer for IGN. You can follow him on Twitter </em><a href="https://twitter.com/AdamBankhurst"><em>@AdamBankhurst</em></a><em> and on </em><a href="https://www.twitch.tv/AdamBankhurst"><em>Twitch.</em></a></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:50:32 +0000</pubDate>
<enclosure length="1337" type="image/jpeg" url="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2023/05/07/faceoff-zelda-blogroll-03-1683465450477.jpg"></enclosure>
<category>Gaming &amp; eSports</category>
<dc:creator>Adam Bankhurst</dc:creator>
<source url="https://www.ign.com">IGN</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e751632f11d</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Shroud gifted back-to-back aces in late night VALORANT Premier stream</title>
<link>https://dotesports.com/valorant/news/shroud-gifted-back-to-back-aces-in-late-night-valorant-premier-stream</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div><img style="margin-bottom:15px;" src="https://dotesports.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/23115314/FayvLnVVsAA028M-scaled.jpg" alt="FayvLnVVsAA028M-scaled.jpg"></div> 
<p>As a long-time competitor <a href="https://dotesports.com/news/every-team-shroud-has-played-for-professionally">across various FPS titles</a>, and a streamer regarded as a <a href="https://dotesports.com/general/news/breaking-shroud-is-making-an-open-world-survival-game">savant in all things shooter-related</a>, Twitch star shroud doesn’t need much help when it comes to making plays. But that didn’t stop his Premier opponents in <em>VALORANT</em> from giving him back-to-back aces during their <a href="https://dotesports.com/valorant/news/what-is-valorant-premier-how-to-play-team-creation-more-details-on-the-upcoming-competitive-mode">beta phase</a> match.</p> 
 
 
 
<p>During the global open beta phase, shroud joined forces with other popular pro players turned star streamers, teaming up with Tarik, Stewie2k, Steel, and iiTzTimmy to form a stacked Premier roster. All five players hopped on for a Saturday night match during the Pearl week of the Premier beta, and shroud did not disappoint.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:39:15 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Gaming &amp; eSports</category>
<dc:creator>Scott Robertson</dc:creator>
<source url="https://dotesports.com/">Dot Esports</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e751633ff23</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>hallzerk: &quot;After that kick in the ass in Australia our practice has gone really well&quot;</title>
<link>https://www.hltv.org/news/36200/hallzerk-after-that-kick-in-the-ass-in-australia-our-practice-has-gone-really-well</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://img-cdn.hltv.org/gallerypicture/VgR58UKuzQ3rtatpOY38h8.jpg?auto=compress&amp;ixlib=java-2.1.0&amp;m=%2Fm.png&amp;mw=107&amp;mx=20&amp;my=473&amp;q=75&amp;w=800&amp;s=481f0befc5011a3844a0272cb571e7d8" alt="VgR58UKuzQ3rtatpOY38h8.jpg?auto=compress"></p>An unfortunate showing at ESL Challenger Melbourne has not dented Complexity's confidence heading into the BLAST Paris Major.]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:25:28 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Gaming &amp; eSports</category>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<source url="https://www.hltv.org/">HLTV.org - The home of competitive Counter-Strike</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75163d5162</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Star Wars Jedi: Survivor goes all in on Star Wars’ newest era</title>
<link>https://www.polygon.com/star-wars/23712668/star-wars-jedi-survivor-high-republic-era-dagan-gera</link>
<description><![CDATA[ 
      <img alt="Dagan Gera studies an object while a Gen’Dai stands near him, observing, in a screenshot from Star Wars Jedi: Survivor" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ezM9fjD1Y0RQYKVNrs89Huu7C0w=/27x0:1478x816/640x360/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/72257193/star_wars_jedi_survivor_dagan_gera.0.jpg"> 
        Image: Respawn Entertainment/Electronic Arts 
     
 
  <p>The High Republic, it’s a thing</p> 
  <p> 
    <a href="https://www.polygon.com/star-wars/23712668/star-wars-jedi-survivor-high-republic-era-dagan-gera">Continue reading…</a> 
  </p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 16:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Gaming &amp; eSports</category>
<dc:creator>Joshua Rivera</dc:creator>
<source url="http://www.polygon.com/">Polygon -  All</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75163f6af0</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Pokémon TCG Live gets a firm release date next month</title>
<link>https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-tcg-live-gets-a-firm-release-date-next-month</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="https://assetsio.reedpopcdn.com/pokemon-trading-card-game-live_FgQDzZG.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" alt="pokemon-trading-card-game-live_FgQDzZG.j"> <p>Good news, Pokémon fans – we finally have a release date for Pokémon TCG Live: 8th June 2023.
 
</p><p>That means that we also have a closure date for the app Pokémon TCG Live will supercede, Pokémon TCG Online, which is set to be "sunsetted" on 5th June.
 
</p><p>"The Pokémon Trading Card Game (TCG) Online app will be removed from the App Store, Google Play, and Pokemon.com on June 5, 2023, at 9 a.m. PDT prior to the official global launch of Pokémon Trading Card Game (TCG) Live on June 8, 2023," The Pokémon Company <a href="https://support.pokemon.com/hc/en-us/articles/4406895467668">announced earlier this week</a>. "Pokémon TCG Live is currently available in beta to players around the world on iOS and Android devices, as well as PCs and Macs."
 
</p> <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-tcg-live-gets-a-firm-release-date-next-month">Read more</a></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 15:59:31 +0000</pubDate>
<enclosure length="1337" type="image/jpeg" url="https://assetsio.reedpopcdn.com/pokemon-trading-card-game-live_FgQDzZG.jpg?width=1920&amp;amp;height=1920&amp;amp;fit=bounds&amp;amp;quality=80&amp;amp;format=jpg&amp;amp;auto=webp"></enclosure>
<category>Gaming &amp; eSports</category>
<dc:creator>Vikki Blake</dc:creator>
<source url="http://www.eurogamer.net/">Eurogamer.net</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75163fd96c</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Visa issuers, have mercy: Dota 2’s The International returns to Seattle after four years</title>
<link>https://dotesports.com/dota-2/news/visa-issuers-have-mercy-dota-2s-the-international-returns-to-seattle-after-four-years</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div><img style="margin-bottom:15px;" src="https://dotesports.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/ti-2023.jpeg" alt="ti-2023.jpeg"></div> 
<p>Valve just unveiled the host city for <em>Dota 2</em>’s The International 2023. After traversing four different countries since 2017, TI is set to embark on a nostalgic homecoming in Seattle, USA.</p> 
 
 
 
<p>Despite organizing the first-ever TI in Cologne, Germany, Valve turned Seattle into the home of the International for the following six years. The KeyArena in Seattle resonated as the battleground of the top teams in the world, but Valve made the decision to take the Aegis of Champions on a world tour when the event center closed its door for <a href="https://arenadigest.com/2018/07/30/keyarena-renovation-project-cost-now-around-700/">renovations</a>.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 15:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Gaming &amp; eSports</category>
<dc:creator>Gökhan Çakır</dc:creator>
<source url="https://dotesports.com/">Dot Esports</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e751639ab4a</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Greener grass: two LEC teams spice up the mid-season break with sudden support swap</title>
<link>https://dotesports.com/league-of-legends/news/greener-grass-two-lec-teams-spice-up-the-mid-season-break-with-sudden-support-swap</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div><img style="margin-bottom:15px;" src="https://dotesports.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/13133209/52669045556_d38d70b416_k.jpg" alt="52669045556_d38d70b416_k.jpg"></div> 
<p>Even though the LEC is on a break due to the Mid-Season Invitational, teams keep surprising fans with unexpected moves.</p> 
 
 
 
<p>According to sources close to <a href="https://blix.gg/news/trimby-fnatic">Blix.gg</a>, Adrian “Trymbi” Trybus has reached a verbal agreement to join Fnatic before the start of the 2023 LEC Summer Split. The Polish player has reportedly come to a one-split deal with the organization.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 15:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Gaming &amp; eSports</category>
<dc:creator>Davide Xu</dc:creator>
<source url="https://dotesports.com/">Dot Esports</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e751639ab3d</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Guardians of the Galaxy Became the Best Version of Itself By Letting James Gunn Do His Thing</title>
<link>https://www.ign.com/articles/guardians-of-the-galaxy-became-best-version-of-itself-letting-james-gunn-do-his-thing</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2023/05/05/guardians-3-thumb-1683312322052.jpg?width=1280" alt="guardians-3-thumb-1683312322052.jpg?widt"></p><p><strong>Warning: Spoilers follow for Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 3</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol-3-post-credits-scene-ending-explained">Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 3</a> is a tailor-fitted exit for James Gunn from Marvel’s Cinematic Universe (should DC be his new forever home). It’s the “Gunniest” <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol-3-review">Guardians of the Galaxy film (review)</a> as the interstellar outfit sees Gunn’s trilogy come to a close, arguably the most individually-voiced Marvel film down to the universe’s first uncensored F-Bomb. Gunn injected every ounce of himself into the Guardians trilogy, from soundtrack to screenplay to Baby Groot’s motion capture, and found the best version of characters he emphatically adores, since each film allows a bit more of his background telling comically bleak stories into the DNA of the Guardians films. Pound for pound, the Guardians trilogy is one of the best character-focused substories in the MCU — and that’s wholly thanks to freedoms that allowed Gunn to be himself with minimal interference.</p><p>From Peter Quill’s thievery set to Redbone’s “Come and Get Your Love” at the beginning of the first Guardians of the Galaxy to Vol. 3’s bittersweet finale set to Florence + The Machine’s “Dog Days Are Over,” Gunn puts a premium on cinematic personality through songs. What other Marvel film generates excitement around filmmaker-selected mixtapes before a movie releases? Gunn’s ability to accentuate his story’s impact by picking the perfect backing track adds another layer of depth to his cosmic rock operas, because Gunn’s thinking about how every piece fits his Guardians puzzle. Tracks on Gunn’s at-home playlists become the rhythm behind Quill’s antics, Drax’s beatdowns, and deeply emotional confessions like he’s writing scenes to fit pre-selected needle drops, not vice versa. </p><h2><strong>James Gunn Cares a Lot</strong></h2><p>Music is just one ingredient that makes up Gunn’s special sauce. There’s a consistency to the Guardians’ evolution, from unlikely prison-break unions, to battles against Celestials that bring them together, to rescue missions that cause teary goodbyes. The complaint that Marvel movies feel churned out of a machine is nullified by the Guardians trilogy, written (with co-writers) and directed by Gunn. No one’s better at making us fall in love with misfits than Gunn, never losing Drax, Gamora, Rocket, or Groot in the shuffle of Quill’s continued battle to save the galaxy instead of confronting his mamma and papa issues. Unlike lesser superteam movies that fail to elevate all their members, Gunn wants you to love each Guardian as much as he loves them, especially his personal favorite, Rocket Raccoon.</p>Unlike lesser superteam movies that fail to elevate all their members, Gunn wants you to love each Guardian as much as he loves them.<p>His wacky-yet-weighty signatures are subtler in the first Guardians of the Galaxy movie. Gunn’s tasked with creating an origin story worthy of the MCU limelight for superheroes without the mainstream recognition of Captain America or The Hulk. It’s the most neatly tucked and uniform of his Guardians films, minus a dance-off distraction or Groot’s violent skewering-and-slamming of Ronan’s Kree guards as they charge down a hallway. Guardians of the Galaxy is Gunn playing nicely in Marvel’s sandbox, because it’s enough that Vol. 1 is the MCU’s first foray into “Cosmic Marvel.” Gunn knows the spectacle is inherent as Ronan brattily threatens Thanos or we speed around in Quill’s Milano spacecraft. The sights, the sounds, they were MCU unseen back in 2014.</p><p>Gunn’s attention to the little details sets his films apart, starting with Vol. 1. Quill’s dedication to his battered walkman and sentimental mixtapes opens the character like a pop-up picture book. The messiness of Rocket and Drax’s alcohol-soaked fight outside The Collector’s den reveals background trauma. The quieter conversations and bonding moments outside Nova Corps fleets zipping around Kree fighter crafts above Xandar echo loudly throughout all three films. The foundation that Gunn lays for his Guardians in Vol. 1 is impeccable, allowing for durable storytelling arcs to ruin and revitalize heroes who have no idea what to do with conditional love. Gunn never gets distracted by the grand spectacle in Guardians of the Galaxy, always ensuring the Guardians themselves are the main focus.</p><p>There’s no more prominent beneficiary of Gunn’s character building than blue-meanie slash secret softy Yondu — not Quill’s father, but damn sure his daddy. Quill and Yondu banter about how the Ravager captain kidnapped an Earth boy and threatened cannibalism daily, which plays for jokes on the surface, but that’s a cover as Gunn sneaks father-son compassion under Yondu’s supposedly callous motivations. Again, little touches like Yondu’s dashboard tchotchkes or the approving smiles Quill doesn’t see lead to the waterworks flood at the end of Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2 that’s one of the most beautiful celebrations in the entire MCU. Gunn’s stealthy development of Quill and Yondu’s parent/child fondness hits like Ronan’s hammer as Cat Stevens’ “Father and Son” plays over Yondu’s fireworks-filled Ravager funeral, rendering even the stoniest watcher an emotional wreck.</p><h2><strong>He Takes (and Lands) Huge Tonal Swings</strong></h2><p>What’s impressive is how Gunn does this in an immensely sillier Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2. Baby Groot’s opening credits boogie to ELO’s “Mr. Blue Sky” not only doubles down on Quill’s groovy introduction from Vol. 1 but tonally prepares audiences for even more Gunn. The twisted prankster who thinks it’s funny to have Baby Groot sever and steal a Ravager’s toe. The childlike jester who includes scenes out of rejected Looney Tunes cartoons, like when Rocket sends Ravager hordes bouncing into the air like they’re made of Flubber. The hallucinogenic 700 hyper-jump gag that leads to Baby Groot puke, a Hallmarky father and son catch scene between Quill and Ego, Rocket’s continued obsession with stealing bionic body parts — Vol. 2 is Gunn embracing his Scooby-Doo past, approaching the Guardians as Saturday Morning staples.</p><p>Through it all, Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2 is richly rewarding as a character study amidst all the gags and goofs. Quill and Gamora’s will they, won’t they is brimming with warm romantic gazes; meanwhile Mantis bursts out sobbing in a tragic display after reading Drax’s blood-dashed memories. Rocket’s admission as King Asshole after Yondu’s pep talk is simple yet impactful as the mutated mammal learns to be vulnerable. Yondu’s pure face-turn earns cheers, and his proud declaration that he’s Mary Poppins is more than just a throwaway laugh. Kraglin — even Yondu’s second hand — tugs our heartstrings as Quill gifts the now deceased Yondu’s Yaka Arrow weapon, and Kraglin’s voice touchingly squeaks a sobering “thank you.” Gunn makes a single line, the littlest of little things, feel so gigantic.</p><p>Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 3 is the full circle of Gunn’s career that started with a mentorship under cult horror figurehead Lloyd Kaufman of Troma Studios. All the darkest humor within Gunn — prevalent in scripts from Tromeo &amp; Juliet to The Belko Experiment — pushes as far as it can under Marvel’s oversight. Adam Warlock’s inability to understand the difference between some light hostage punishment and laser-beam evisceration is hilariously inappropriate for the MCU, and yet wholly par for the filmmaker’s catalog. The High Evolutionary is one of Marvel’s most detestable bastards, and his animal war machine armies are nightmare fuel (even when voiced by Judy Greer). Gunn explodes innocent Counter-Earth inhabitants, finds humor in material that will stir questions inside younger MCU fans that their parents might fret about answering, and confidently embraces his fullest form in a way that suits the O.G. Guardians’ swan song. Gunn’s all-in, and Marvel’s ability to let Gunn be himself is what drives this trilogy capper home.</p><h2><strong>Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 3 Is Full-Force Gunn</strong></h2><p>Where Vol. 1 and Vol. 2 align more with Gunn’s safer comedy leanings, Vol. 3 isn’t afraid to let his nastier tendencies in scripts like Super or Slither find a home. Dare I say there’s comparable heartbreak to Elliot Page’s fate in Super as Young Rocket tries to spring Lylla and the others from their cages? The High Evolutionary’s gorily disfigured face is something I’d expect to see in a Rated-R zombie flick (it makes Red Skull look like an America’s Next Top Model winner). Yet Gunn still acknowledges what his Guardians deserve at the end of the day and doesn’t pull a no-hope ending like his Dawn of the Dead remake script. Even Drax gets his due, as his companions finally recognize his true calling as a corny-as-heck father, not a vengeful berserker bred to vanquish enemies with an insatiable bloodlust. Gunn channels his compassionate caretaker mojo and reaches deep into his bag of tricks, but stops before entering the abyss of cynicism and societal failures found in some of his harsher horror features — his Guardians fight for the future we all deserve.</p><p>As Gunn-ho Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 3 becomes, it never loses that thread of humanity that endears the Guardians and helps us feel their connection. Flashback sequences where Rocket is subjected to The High Evolutionary’s soul-crushing animal abuse are the tear-jerker moments you’d expect. Quill’s rage-fueled devotion to an injured Rocket, Gamora’s not-so-soft deflections of Quill’s lovesick pleas, the whole “last hurrah” sting of watching characters split for their betterment yet not wanting the Guardians to change — Gunn doesn’t get lost in selfish indulgences. Gunn never stops caring about the Guardians through every tonal embellishment and diversion. Each movie in the trilogy remains a character piece at its core, no matter how easy it is to boil Gunn’s signatures down to borderline juvenile humor and chart-topper music video sequences where baddies get embarrassed.</p>Gunn made these Guardians films for the outcasts, the misunderstood, and the broken among us, never conceding his vision.<p>Gunn fires on all cylinders for the most complete trilogy imaginable. Guardians of the Galaxy is his Star Wars. He lets us ride shotgun with wild-card protectors who mostly need protection from themselves, and lets their flaws lay naked. There’s no current sub-franchise run in the MCU that’s had me openly cry in every entry outside the Guardians — an ode to Gunn’s innate ability to tell affecting stories with characters others might turn into freakshows. Payoff is everything in these Guardians movies, and Vol. 3 nods endlessly to its previous entries. <a href="https://www.ign.com/videos/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol-3-heres-what-happens-to-the-guardians-now-marvel-canon-fodder">To finish it all with us being able to understand Groot</a> because we’re all one big family with the Guardians now? If that doesn’t sock you, stick your heart in an incinerator because it’s frozen solid.</p><p>Ant-Man might make me laugh. Captain America: The Winter Soldier may thrill me. They’re proficient at playing to singular strengths. James Gunn’s Guardians movies are just a different breed that lets you belly laugh, shed tears, howl with excitement, and feel a rainbow of experiences all in one sitting. “We are Groot,” the Ravager funeral, the Guardians’ salute to Rocket — Gunn knows precisely how to meet swelling story highs with a tidal wave of meaning. Over three films, the Guardians have become the unsung heroes of the MCU thanks to the man supporting their imperfect perfection. Gunn made these Guardians films for the outcasts, the misunderstood, and the broken among us, never conceding his vision. As it turns out, Gunn’s emphatic individuality is the secret weapon these underdog Guardians needed to show the MCU how it’s done.</p><p>That, and maybe Zardu Hasselfrau.</p><p><em>For more on the film, check out </em><a href="https://www.ign.com/videos/guardians-of-the-galaxy-cast-respond-to-ign-comments"><em>James Gunn and Chris Pratt responding to IGN comments</em></a><em>, find out </em><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-to-watch-guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol-3"><em>how to watch Guardians 3,</em></a><em> or study up on </em><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/every-guardian-of-the-galaxy-ever-marvel-comics"><em>Every Guardian of the Galaxy Ever</em></a><em>!</em></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 15:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
<enclosure length="1337" type="image/jpeg" url="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2023/05/05/guardians-3-thumb-1683312322052.jpg"></enclosure>
<category>Gaming &amp; eSports</category>
<dc:creator>Matt Donato</dc:creator>
<source url="https://www.ign.com">IGN</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75163b4c2a</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Resident Evil 4 SAVED Resident Evil</title>
<link>https://www.gamespot.com/videos/how-resident-evil-4-saved-resident-evil/2300-6461327/</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_medium/1574/15746725/4134464-how-it-saved-re4-v2_site.jpg" width="480" height="480" alt="4134464-how-it-saved-re4-v2_site.jpg"> Resident Evil and survival horror, as a genre, were on the decline. Sequels to games like Silent Hill, and newer titles like Fatal Frame were failing to make a splash, and even the mighty Resident Evil was slowly tumbling down on sales. This is the story of how Resident Evil 4 SAVED Resident Evil.]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 15:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
<enclosure length="1337" type="image/jpeg" url="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/screen_medium/1574/15746725/4134464-how-it-saved-re4-v2_site.jpg"></enclosure>
<category>Gaming &amp; eSports</category>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<source url="http://www.gamespot.com/feeds/mashup/">GameSpot</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e7516255a06</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Resident Evil 4 Saved The Resident Evil Franchise</title>
<link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-resident-evil-4-saved-the-resident-evil-franchise/1100-6513878/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gamespot-has-an-exciting-new-video-lineup-and-it-starts-this-week/1100-6513702/">big new video week</a> continues with the first installment of "How It Saved." This is a recurring series in which senior producer Dave Klein documents how specific games have pulled franchises back from the brink, or in some cases, how they helped save game studios stay up and running.</p><p>The Resident Evil series debuted in 1996, and it helped define the survival horror genre, and its sequels expanded on the formula and helped grow the franchise to new heights. In the debut episode, "How Resident Evil 4 Saved Resident Evil," Dave discusses in detail how the 2005 game helped turn things around after the series began to slow down in terms of sales.</p><p>"Resident Evil 4 carried the torch for Resident Evil through a slowing of interest in survival horror. It completely revitalized the series, introduced it to new fans, and was able to pave a path for Resident Evil until its next big comeback," Dave argues in the video. "Resident Evil 4 may be divisive for some, but I think there’s no doubt that it saved the Resident Evil franchise."</p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-resident-evil-4-saved-the-resident-evil-franchise/1100-6513878/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f/">Continue Reading at GameSpot</a>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 15:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
<enclosure length="1337" type="image/png" url="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/screen_medium/1179/11799911/4134395-screenshot2023-05-05at12.28.19pm.png"></enclosure>
<category>Gaming &amp; eSports</category>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<source url="http://www.gamespot.com/feeds/mashup/">GameSpot</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75162559fc</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Five Nights at Freddy's movie trailer leaks online</title>
<link>https://www.eurogamer.net/five-nights-at-freddys-movie-trailer-leaks-online</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="https://assetsio.reedpopcdn.com/video-five-nights-at-freddys-live-stream-1408632271214.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" alt="video-five-nights-at-freddys-live-stream"> <p>A trailer for the upcoming Five Nights at Freddy's movie has leaked online.
 
</p><p>Whilst there have been efforts to contain the leak – including a fairly successful community boycott and takedown notices from NBC Universal – the teaser is still available if you're prepared to look.
 
</p><p>"I got emails about this early in the day but was at an amusement park with my kids and was unable to see what had happened," series creator Scott Cawthon said in response to a thread added to the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/fivenightsatfreddys/comments/139zk6k/comment/jj5denn/?context=3">Five Nights at Freddy's subreddit</a>.
 
</p> <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/five-nights-at-freddys-movie-trailer-leaks-online">Read more</a></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 15:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
<enclosure length="1337" type="image/jpeg" url="https://assetsio.reedpopcdn.com/video-five-nights-at-freddys-live-stream-1408632271214.jpg?width=1920&amp;amp;height=1920&amp;amp;fit=bounds&amp;amp;quality=80&amp;amp;format=jpg&amp;amp;auto=webp"></enclosure>
<category>Gaming &amp; eSports</category>
<dc:creator>Vikki Blake</dc:creator>
<source url="http://www.eurogamer.net/">Eurogamer.net</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e7516258da7</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Here are the matchups for the MSI 2023 Bracket Stage</title>
<link>https://dotesports.com/league-of-legends/news/here-are-the-matchups-for-the-msi-2023-bracket-stage</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div><img style="margin-bottom:15px;" src="https://dotesports.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/52877534761_9280c9c794_k.jpg" alt="52877534761_9280c9c794_k.jpg"></div> 
<p>Following the conclusion of the Mid-Season Invitational play-in stage, the remaining <em>League of Legends</em> teams in the tournament were drawn into an eight-team double-elimination bracket. Five teams had already advanced to the bracket stage thanks to their placements during the domestic portion of the season, while three others advanced to the bracket from the play-ins. </p> 
 
 
 
<p>Unlike previous editions of the tournament, MSI 2023 featured <a href="https://dotesports.com/league-of-legends/news/msi-2023-breaking-down-the-new-two-stage-format">an expanded field</a> of 13 participants. That number has been narrowed to eight, moving into the bracket stage. Perhaps the most intriguing development to come out of the play-in stage was the fact that no minor region teams advanced to the tournament’s next round. With that in mind, all four major regions in professional <em>League </em>will have two representatives present in the bracket stage. </p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 14:41:23 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Gaming &amp; eSports</category>
<dc:creator>Michael Kelly</dc:creator>
<source url="https://dotesports.com/">Dot Esports</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e7516276120</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>YEKINDAR: &quot;People are going to notice a different style that we're going to play&quot;</title>
<link>https://www.hltv.org/news/36199/yekindar-people-are-going-to-notice-a-different-style-that-were-going-to-play</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://img-cdn.hltv.org/gallerypicture/qNBH-gHyk0VwUTJ1Juntq7.jpg?auto=compress&amp;ixlib=java-2.1.0&amp;m=%2Fm.png&amp;mw=107&amp;mx=20&amp;my=474&amp;q=75&amp;w=800&amp;s=04485f0f14159cf6880bf94236cddc7e" alt="qNBH-gHyk0VwUTJ1Juntq7.jpg?auto=compress"></p>HLTV was able to catch up with the Latvian entry fragger the day before the BLAST.tv Paris Major begins.]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 13:25:12 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Gaming &amp; eSports</category>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<source url="https://www.hltv.org/">HLTV.org - The home of competitive Counter-Strike</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75162ebd4b</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Propagation: Paradise Hotel is a surprisingly good VR horror game with an old-school Resi vibe</title>
<link>https://www.eurogamer.net/propagation-paradise-hotel-is-a-surprisingly-good-vr-horror-game-with-an-old-school-resi-vibe</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="https://assetsio.reedpopcdn.com/b1_YuRSXZ1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" alt="b1_YuRSXZ1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fi"> <p>A VR horror game that's <em>not</em> set in a mental asylum? What a refreshing change! And it's not just a shonkily put together, cheaply made, unscary and unintelligible jank-fest? Unbelievable!</p><p>That's right, on this week's episode of VR Corner I take a look at Propagation: Paradise Hotel, a new VR horror game that released this week on Quest and PC VR that is actually fairly decent! </p><p>Now look, I'm sorry if I sounded a bit jaded in those opening sentences there but in all honesty, I am. I've played so many VR horror games in the past and a large portion of them have been utterly underwhelming and just terribly, terribly made. Case in point is the recently released Afterlife VR which I streamed on my personal YouTube channel a few weeks ago. It was probably one of the worst PSVR2 games I've played so far and it featured every negative point that I described at the start of this post.</p> <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/propagation-paradise-hotel-is-a-surprisingly-good-vr-horror-game-with-an-old-school-resi-vibe">Read more</a></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 13:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
<enclosure length="1337" type="image/jpeg" url="https://assetsio.reedpopcdn.com/b1_YuRSXZ1.jpg?width=1920&amp;amp;height=1920&amp;amp;fit=bounds&amp;amp;quality=80&amp;amp;format=jpg&amp;amp;auto=webp"></enclosure>
<category>Gaming &amp; eSports</category>
<dc:creator>Ian Higton</dc:creator>
<source url="http://www.eurogamer.net/">Eurogamer.net</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75162904c5</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>karrigan: &quot;We have to break all of the records and make sure CS:GO goes out with a bang&quot;</title>
<link>https://www.hltv.org/news/36198/karrigan-we-have-to-break-all-of-the-records-and-make-sure-csgo-goes-out-with-a-bang</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://img-cdn.hltv.org/gallerypicture/LSGHnOMO111PQqrgi3p6LH.jpg?auto=compress&amp;ixlib=java-2.1.0&amp;m=%2Fm.png&amp;mw=107&amp;mx=20&amp;my=474&amp;q=75&amp;w=800&amp;s=357e4c4cbd4813658b701dfe1cb64e95" alt="LSGHnOMO111PQqrgi3p6LH.jpg?auto=compress"></p>The Danish IGL wants the community to rally for the BLAST.tv Paris Major.]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 12:24:56 +0000</pubDate>
<category>Gaming &amp; eSports</category>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<source url="https://www.hltv.org/">HLTV.org - The home of competitive Counter-Strike</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e7516148e7d</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bohemia Interactive's FPS/RTS hybrid, Silica, is now available in early access</title>
<link>https://www.eurogamer.net/bohemia-interactives-fpsrts-hybrid-silica-is-now-available-in-early-access</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="https://assetsio.reedpopcdn.com/silica_screenshot_6.ca0f1211.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" alt="silica_screenshot_6.ca0f1211.jpg?width=1"> <p>Bohemia Interactive has revealed that its upcoming sci-fi FPS/RTS hybrid, Silica, is now available as an early access title.
 
</p><p>Developed through Bohemia's Incubator initiative, Silica is "a crossover of FPS and RTS" where up to three factions battle for control over the planet Baltarus. 
 
</p><p>"Lead from above as commander, or experience the action first-hand, either alone, or with friends. Join one of two human armies, or hunt them down as the territorial aliens," the blurb teases. You can see it in action in the trailer below:
 
</p> <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bohemia-interactives-fpsrts-hybrid-silica-is-now-available-in-early-access">Read more</a></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 11:56:09 +0000</pubDate>
<enclosure length="1337" type="image/jpeg" url="https://assetsio.reedpopcdn.com/silica_screenshot_6.ca0f1211.jpg?width=1920&amp;amp;height=1920&amp;amp;fit=bounds&amp;amp;quality=80&amp;amp;format=jpg&amp;amp;auto=webp"></enclosure>
<category>Gaming &amp; eSports</category>
<dc:creator>Vikki Blake</dc:creator>
<source url="http://www.eurogamer.net/">Eurogamer.net</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e7516174af1</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>CS:GO has smashed its own all-time concurrent user peak yet again</title>
<link>https://www.eurogamer.net/csgo-has-smashed-its-own-all-time-concurrent-user-peak-yet-again</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="https://assetsio.reedpopcdn.com/csgo_sugarcane_01.jpg.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" alt="csgo_sugarcane_01.jpg.jpg?width=1920&amp;hei"> <p>Counter-Strike: Global Offensive (CS:GO) has once again smashed its all-time concurrent PC user peak.
 
</p><p>According to <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/730/charts/">SteamDB</a>, CS:GO topped 1.8m concurrent users over the weekend, smashing not only its own simultaneous user record, but cementing itself as one of Steam's biggest-ever games.
 
</p><p>With 1,818,773 CS:GO players online at once yesterday, that means only PUBG: Battlegrounds now sports a higher concurrent count – no other game ever released on Steam comes close.
 
</p> <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/csgo-has-smashed-its-own-all-time-concurrent-user-peak-yet-again">Read more</a></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 11:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
<enclosure length="1337" type="image/jpeg" url="https://assetsio.reedpopcdn.com/csgo_sugarcane_01.jpg.jpg?width=1920&amp;amp;height=1920&amp;amp;fit=bounds&amp;amp;quality=80&amp;amp;format=jpg&amp;amp;auto=webp"></enclosure>
<category>Gaming &amp; eSports</category>
<dc:creator>Vikki Blake</dc:creator>
<source url="http://www.eurogamer.net/">Eurogamer.net</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e7516120938</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Sunday Papers</title>
<link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-678</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="https://assetsio.reedpopcdn.com/the-sunday-papers-big.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" alt="the-sunday-papers-big.jpg?width=1920&amp;hei">  
<p>Sundays are for being unreasonably excited by the prospect of a Gousto box. Before you unpack, let's read this week's best writing about games (and game related things).</p> 
 <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-sunday-papers-678">Read more</a></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 10:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
<enclosure length="1337" type="image/jpeg" url="https://assetsio.reedpopcdn.com/the-sunday-papers-big.jpg?width=1920&amp;amp;height=1920&amp;amp;fit=bounds&amp;amp;quality=80&amp;amp;format=jpg&amp;amp;auto=webp"></enclosure>
<category>Gaming &amp; eSports</category>
<dc:creator>Ed Thorn</dc:creator>
<source url="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/">Rock, Paper, Shotgun</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e751619baf5</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Respawn wants you to decide which mode gets its &quot;own dedicated playlist&quot; during Apex Legends Season 17</title>
<link>https://www.eurogamer.net/respawn-wants-you-to-decide-which-mode-gets-its-own-dedicated-playlist-during-apex-legends-season-17</link>
<description><![CDATA[<img src="https://assetsio.reedpopcdn.com/Apex-Legends-Arsenal-Ballistic-Execution-Key-Art-Respawn-Entertainment-EMBARGO-MAY-1.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" alt="Apex-Legends-Arsenal-Ballistic-Execution"> <p>Respawn wants you to decide which Limited Time Mode (LTM) should get its "own dedicated playlist" when season 17, Arsenal, drops next week.
 
</p><p>Players have until tomorrow, 8th May, to <a href="https://t.co/jmb0CM6Xqk">register their vote</a> for either Control, Team Deathmatch (TDM), or Gun Run.
 
</p><p>"We’re letting the community decide which Limited Time Mode should get its own dedicated playlist during the first in-game event coming in Arsenal!" Respawn explains in a tweet. 
 
</p> <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/respawn-wants-you-to-decide-which-mode-gets-its-own-dedicated-playlist-during-apex-legends-season-17">Read more</a></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 09:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
<enclosure length="1337" type="image/jpeg" url="https://assetsio.reedpopcdn.com/Apex-Legends-Arsenal-Ballistic-Execution-Key-Art-Respawn-Entertainment-EMBARGO-MAY-1.png?width=1920&amp;amp;height=1920&amp;amp;fit=bounds&amp;amp;quality=80&amp;amp;format=jpg&amp;amp;auto=webp"></enclosure>
<category>Gaming &amp; eSports</category>
<dc:creator>Vikki Blake</dc:creator>
<source url="http://www.eurogamer.net/">Eurogamer.net</source>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.inoreader.com/article/3a9c6e75161ba463</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>